<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tor on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/tor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tor on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/tor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindness Mode: Help People Connect to Tor on World Kindness Day</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2025/11/13/kindness-mode-help-people-connect-to-tor-on-world-kindness-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2025/11/13/kindness-mode-help-people-connect-to-tor-on-world-kindness-day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Kindness_Day&#34;&gt;World Kindness Day&lt;/a&gt;. As stated on Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;World Kindness Day is to highlight good deeds in the community focusing on the positive power and the common thread of kindness for good which binds us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Kindness_Day&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;worldkindnessday.png&#34; width=200/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that word &lt;strong&gt;bind&lt;/strong&gt; is particularly meaningful to use in a technical way - when a remote computer connects to another computer over a network, whether peer-to-peer or a server, one way to state what happens is &amp;ldquo;binding to their socket port&amp;rdquo;. The decentralized, privacy-focused &lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;tor network&lt;/a&gt; is powered by volunteer organizations and inviduals around the world sharing their network resources. On Tor, there is a great deal of positive, community &amp;ldquo;good which binds us&amp;rdquo; going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind on this auspicious day, we have released new guidance about &lt;strong&gt;KINDNESS MODE&lt;/strong&gt;, a feature for helping others in need, available in our app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orbot.app&#34;&gt;Orbot for Android and iOS&lt;/a&gt;. Kindness Mode is our name for the underlying technology also known as &amp;ldquo;Snowflake&amp;rdquo;, which helps people get around extreme forms of network censorship and filtering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-a-snowflake-proxy&#34;&gt;Running a Snowflake Proxy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a &lt;a href=&#34;https://snowflake.torproject.org&#34;&gt;Snowflake Proxy&lt;/a&gt; is one of the easiest, safest, and most impactful ways to help people circumvent censorship, especially if you’re in a place with an open and free internet. Your device, through your public IP address, becomes an essential bridge for people where Tor is blocked (in, say, Iran or China) and the entrance to the Tor network. There are many ways you can run a Snowflake Proxy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orbot’s “Kindness Mode” on iOS and Android: &lt;a href=&#34;https://orbot.app/kindness&#34;&gt;https://orbot.app/kindness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snowflake add-on for Firefox, Chrome or Edge: &lt;a href=&#34;https://snowflake.torproject.org&#34;&gt;https://snowflake.torproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WEPN home device: &lt;a href=&#34;https://we-pn.com/kindness-faq.html&#34;&gt;https://we-pn.com/kindness-faq.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-facts-to-know&#34;&gt;Key Facts to Know&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not using Tor yourself, you are simply a bridge for someone else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of the data passing through your device is encrypted; nothing is visible to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There will be an impact on your bandwidth, but it is minimal, and you can set limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;kindessmodehandout.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kindessmode1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kindness Mode diagram&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-and-considerations&#34;&gt;Risks and Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In most countries, running a Snowflake Proxy is legal. It’s equivalent to making an online “VOIP” call between two points on the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In high-censorship networks, this traffic could draw attention, and since your internet is not free and open, it doesn’t make sense to run a Snowflake Proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy and IP Visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fact that your device was connected to by a remote device on the internet can be seen and logged by your internet service provider.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your IP address will appear in the central Snowflake “Broker” logs since it is necessary to share your proxy’s existence so others can find it.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the app or browser activity of the person you are helping, YOUR IP address is NOT visible and there is no link to your or your device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network and Bandwidth load&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any data used by the device proxying through your connection will count as data on your service or plan. It is best on wifi or with unlimited plans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proxying can slow your connection slightly. However by default only a very limited number of devices can use your proxy at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-minimize-risks&#34;&gt;How to Minimize Risks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Snowflake from a trusted, unrestricted, unlimited network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t use it on shared, public, or corporate networks where administrators might block or misinterpret traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you can, set limits to when and how the Snowflake Proxy should be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;orbot-is-kind&#34;&gt;Orbot is Kind!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have all this important knowledge, you can understand better if you are in a position to be kind, and share your network. &lt;a href=&#34;https://orbot.app/downlaod&#34;&gt;Get Orbot Today&lt;/a&gt; and see how good it feels each time someone connects through your Kindness Mode Snowflake Proxy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;kindessmodehandout.pdf&#34;&gt;View our Orbot Kindness Mode How-To Guide PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arti, next-gen Tor on mobile</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/04/arti-next-gen-tor-on-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/04/arti-next-gen-tor-on-mobile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For software projects with recurring bugs, efficiency or security issues
there&amp;rsquo;s a joke making the rounds in the software industry: &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s re-write it
in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rust_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;!&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s a
fairly new low-level programming language with the declared goal to help
developers avoid entire classes of bugs, security issues and other pitfalls.
Re-writing software is very time consuming, so it rarely happens, especially
when just one more fix will keep a project up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;Tor-Project&lt;/a&gt; was started in 2001 using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;C
programming lanugage&lt;/a&gt;.
However a few years ago they set out to actually re-write their project in
Rust.  That projects codename is &lt;a href=&#34;https://arti.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Arti&lt;/a&gt; and it
was &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.torproject.org/arti_100_released/&#34;&gt;first released&lt;/a&gt; in 2022.
While Arti is working great, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all features of the original Tor
implementation yet.  However, they are steadily working on getting there.  For
example, rough &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pluggabletransports.info/&#34;&gt;Pluggable Transports&lt;/a&gt;
support was added to Arti in the recent 1.1.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have early &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/guardianproject/arti-mobile-ex/&#34;&gt;test builds of
Arti&lt;/a&gt; running on both
Android and iOS.  The integration we came up with is pretty basic, but so far
it seems to work reliable for accessing the Tor network.  Maintaining code for
both iOS and Android in the same project will hopefully simplify shipping new
Arti releases for us, make integrating Tor capabilities into any app simpler.
To make it useful for the broader mobile developer community, we&amp;rsquo;re also
investigating whether we can provide easy to use API bindings.  We&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/guardianproject/arti-mobile-ex/-/tree/main/android/sample&#34;&gt;sample
app&lt;/a&gt;
on Android to test and illustrate what a minimalistic integration of Arti looks
like.  It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as adding a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support for features like advanced censorship circumvention or onion services is not
exactly straight forward on mobile operating systems, because they tend to be
way more locked down than traditional computers.  Currently, we can successfully test
pluggable transports in &amp;ldquo;managed&amp;rdquo; mode on old versions of Android.  However
this technique will likely not work on the latest version of Android and never
worked iOS to begin with.  We have shared our findings with the Arti developer
team and hope they&amp;rsquo;ll work on getting us to full Pluggable Transports support, integraing
with our existing &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/guardianproject/IPtProxy&#34;&gt;IPtProxy Library&lt;/a&gt; soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps towards trusted VPNs</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/02/28/steps-towards-trusted-vpns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/02/28/steps-towards-trusted-vpns/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;VPNs have become quite popular in recent years for a number of reasons, and more and more they are being touted as a privacy tool.  The question is whether using a VPN does improve privacy.  It is clear that VPNs are quite useful for getting access to things on the internet when direct connections are blocked.  VPN providers include a number of tactics in both their client apps and server infrastructure to ensure that their users are able to make a connection.  Then once users are connected, all of their traffic that goes over the VPN will see the internet from the point of view of the VPN&amp;rsquo;s server.  That is how VPNs &amp;ldquo;unblock&amp;rdquo; the internet.  In contrast, some are using VPNs to selectively block things, like making a system-wide &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-block-advertisements-at-the-dns-level-using-pi-hole-and-openvpn-on-ubuntu-16-04&#34;&gt;adblocker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the question about whether they are a useful privacy tool, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the history of where VPNs came from.  VPN stands for Virtual Private Network.  They were developed by large companies with multiple offices and travelling employees.  The goal was to link together all of these offices so that internal data could be freely shared between them without that data going over the internet as easily readable unencrypted plain text.  Then travelling employees could also safely access the internal data via any internet connection.  The key piece of this picture is that the users, employees in this case, already had to trust their VPN provider.  The VPN provider was the company they worked for, and the data they were handling belonged to the company.  So there was no attempt to hide user information from the VPN provider.  Indeed quite the opposite: companies linked the VPN access to each employee&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;single sign-on&amp;rdquo; account.  Built into the design of VPNs is full trust of the VPN provider, with the aim of keeping the data private from the internet. This setup was also by design, since many large companies wanted to ensure their employees work laptops were still going through the corporate firewall, where the company could block certain sites (e.g. malware, porn), then also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fortinet.com/resources/cyberglossary/data-exfiltration&#34;&gt;monitor employees&lt;/a&gt; internet activity to ensure they are not exposing files that the company does not want to be public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Virtual_Private_Network_overview.svg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Virtual Private Network overview&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not paint a good picture for a tool to protect privacy.  But there is hope!  It is possible to use a VPN to improve your privacy if you pay attention to some key details.  For VPN services to provide privacy, you have to put a lot of trust in the people who are operating the service.  The VPN provider can see &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; of your traffic that goes over the VPN, and they have a strong link to your user account with them.  The privacy advantage of a VPN is that the destination sites cannot see which IP address your device is coming from, they will see the VPN provider&amp;rsquo;s IP address.  And your ISP will see you are using a VPN, but not which sites you visit.  With HTTPS, TLS, and end-to-end encryption being widespread, any encrypted content will be protected from the VPN provider also.  But the VPN provider can still see where you are connecting from, which sites and services you are using, what time of day, and even potentially correlate traffic to link activities of their users.  In other words, the VPN operator sees lots of metadata about you, so much so that they could paint a quite detailed portrait of your personal life if they ever did let their data be analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-build-a-privacy-respecting-vpn-service&#34;&gt;How to build a privacy-respecting VPN service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are good signals that VPN services can send to show that they are tackling the real issues.  For example, shipping free software clients, maintaining a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/05/canary-watch-one-year-later&#34;&gt;warrant canary&lt;/a&gt;, posting a clear privacy policy describing the logging policy, and publishing the unredacted results of third party audits.  If the VPN operator is doing the right thing, then VPNs can provide a relatively private way to access the internet.  With a consistent track record of transparency, they can build up a trusted reputation for protecting privacy.  Unfortunately, we cannot rest there since a VPN provider can change their setup quite easily, whether willingly or under duress.  Maintaining consistent, regular, and transparent communications is therefore essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calyx Institute&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://calyxinstitute.org/legal/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://calyxinstitute.org/about/financials-and-annual-reports&#34;&gt;Financials and Annual Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/privacy/principles/&#34;&gt;Data Privacy Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mullvad&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mullvad.net/help/swedish-legislation/&#34;&gt;Swedish legislation relevant to us as a VPN provider&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mullvad.net/help/no-logging-data-policy/&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vpnalyzer.org/&#34;&gt;VPNalyzer&lt;/a&gt; project is working to make monitoring VPN services a lot easier and possible to crowdsource.  This gives a third party perspective from some respected organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;know-as-little-as-possible-about-your-users&#34;&gt;Know as little as possible about your users&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many VPN providers require an account and payment information.  This is usually personally identifiable information, like name, credit card information, email address, phone number, billing address, etc.  The most private services have &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2022/02/28/no-user-accounts-by-design.html&#34;&gt;no user accounts by design&lt;/a&gt;.  Calyx, Lavabit, and Riseup VPNs do not require any account or payment at all, so they do not have that information to give out or leak.  Providers that accept payment need a way to tie payment to service, that is usually done using accounts tied to email addresses or phone numbers.  Personal details are not required to make accounts and payments work.  Mullvad uses a randomly generated account number only, there is no link to other identifiers unless you provide them.  Additionally, Mullvad is one of the few VPN vendors that accepts cash payments.  Many technically minded implementers laugh at the idea of processing envelopes of cash, but it is an effective, real world solution to minimizing personal data that software methods struggle to match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-as-little-information-as-possible&#34;&gt;Keep as little information as possible&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VPN servers unavoidably see lots of information about what users are doing.  The default with most servers is to keep logs of that data. The longer this data is kept, the greater the risk it will be used to identify users and their activities. It does not help that standard practice for running servers is to keep logs for a long time.  Many service providers keep those logs for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VPN providers must be clear about what logs they are keeping, and how long they are stored.  Even better, they will provide information about how they do store the data that they do keep.  For example, if the servers do not use full disk encryption, then it would be straightforward to recover the deleted logs.  That is much harder on systems using full disk encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://cure53.de/audit-report_ivpn.pdf&#34;&gt;2019 audit&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivpn.net/blog/independent-security-audit-concluded&#34;&gt;IVPN&lt;/a&gt; showed that, at that time, the auditors confirmed that IVPN performed no &amp;ldquo;statistical logging of customer-traffic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;logging of traffic, IP addresses or DNS requests&amp;rdquo; on the servers that the auditors were given access to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mullvad says, &amp;ldquo;we never store any activity logs of any kind.&amp;rdquo; in their &lt;a href=&#34;https://mullvad.net/en/help/no-logging-data-policy/&#34;&gt;no logging data policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;proven-track-record-of-resisting-unjust-legal-intrusion&#34;&gt;Proven track record of resisting unjust legal intrusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many legal ways for authorities to get private data, this is an essential part of a functioning justice system.  But these powers are sadly abused in basically every country in the world, it is only a question of degrees.  A VPN provider needs to represent its users legal interests, and push back on legal orders when there is the possibility they are unjust.  Calyx Institute&amp;rsquo;s Nick Merrill provides the shining example in this regard.  With the ACLU, he fought a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doe_v._Ashcroft&#34;&gt;legal case&lt;/a&gt; for over a decade to prevent unjust intrusion for his users.  Ladar Levison shut down his email company &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lavabit&#34;&gt;Lavabit&lt;/a&gt; rather than allow the US Government to monitor Edward Snowden&amp;rsquo;s email account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other ways to ensure that the legal processes are not abused.  These include warrant canaries and disclosure when data had to be turned over via legal procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/policy/transparency/&#34;&gt;Transparency&lt;/a&gt; policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ProtonVPN&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonvpn.com/blog/transparency-report/&#34;&gt;Transparency Report &amp;amp; Warrant Canary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riseup&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://riseup.net/canary&#34;&gt;Canary Statement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publish-as-much-as-possible-as-free-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Publish as much as possible as free open source software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid works to build &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2022/05/24/buildserver-overhaul-sponsored-by-calyx-institute.html&#34;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt; where free software, &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2022/07/22/maven-central.html&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2022/09/30/free-software-and-inspection-are-key-to-software-we-can-trust.html&#34;&gt;inspection&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2023/01/15/towards-a-reproducible-fdroid.html&#34;&gt;reproducible builds&lt;/a&gt; provide a method to ensure that the software we deliver is trustworthy.  VPN vendors recognize how important trust is, so the good ones work to get their apps into f-droid.org.  The F-Droid community provides the best screening for ensuring Android apps are truly free software.  On top of that, F-Droid flags apps for &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/docs/Anti-Features/&#34;&gt;Anti-Features&lt;/a&gt;, which are things that users may not like, but might accept.  Here are VPN clients that do maintain their free software clients in f-droid.org:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/se.leap.bitmaskclient/&#34;&gt;Bitmask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/org.calyxinstitute.vpn/&#34;&gt;Calyx VPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/nl.eduvpn.app/&#34;&gt;eduVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/net.ivpn.client/&#34;&gt;IVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/com.lavabit.pahoehoe/&#34;&gt;Lavabit Encrypted Proxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/net.mullvad.mullvadvpn/&#34;&gt;Mullvad VPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/org.outline.android.client/&#34;&gt;Outline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/ch.protonvpn.android/&#34;&gt;ProtonVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/one.librem.tunnel/&#34;&gt;Purism Librem Tunnel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/se.leap.riseupvpn/&#34;&gt;Riseup VPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/com.tailscale.ipn/&#34;&gt;Tailscale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/com.wireguard.android/&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-external-auditors-to-confirm-source-code-and-operations&#34;&gt;Use external auditors to confirm source code and operations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External auditors are important because they can bring fresh eyes on the source code, and good auditors are experts at finding issues in source code and server setups.  And responsible organizations will publish the full, unredacted audit report once they have fixed the issues.  Even if a VPN app is included in F-Droid, there are key aspects of the service that cannot be independently verified.  For this, we must rely on the people who run the service to do the right thing.  Audits can demonstrate that they were doing the right thing at the point of time of the audit.  Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IVPN&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://cure53.de/audit-report_ivpn.pdf&#34;&gt;2019 audit of IVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla VPN had their app source code &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/security/files/2021/08/FVP-02-report.final_.pdf&#34;&gt;audited&lt;/a&gt; in 2021 and fixed the issues that were found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mullvad&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://cure53.de/pentest-report_mullvad_2020_v2.pdf&#34;&gt;Pentest-Report Mullvad Apps, Clients &amp;amp; API 05.2020&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cure53.de/pentest-report_mullvad_v2.pdf&#34;&gt;Pentest-Report Mullvad VPN Clients 09.2018&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mullvad.net/en/blog/2021/1/20/no-pii-or-privacy-leaks-found-cure53s-infrastructure-audit/&#34;&gt;2020 Infrastructure Audit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outline&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/outline-vpn/static_downloads/ros-report.pdf&#34;&gt;2017 Pentratration Test Report&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/outline-vpn/static_downloads/cure53-report.pdf&#34;&gt;Pentest &amp;amp; Audit Report Jigsaw Outline 09.-12.2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proton VPN open sourced their client apps and had them &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zdnet.com/article/protonvpn-apps-handed-to-open-source-community-in-transparency-security-push/&#34;&gt;audited&lt;/a&gt; in 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publicly-verifiable-binaries-via-reproducible-builds&#34;&gt;Publicly verifiable binaries via reproducible builds&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source code is the easiest place to conduct an audit of software, but it is the binary files that actually run on your device.  Auditing binaries rarely happens since it is so much more time intensive.  And yet, there are ways to change how software works without changing the source code. This can be done by injecting changes into the process that converts the source code into the executable binary.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://reproducible-builds.org/&#34;&gt;Reproducible Builds&lt;/a&gt; is the indisputable method for proving that a given binary was generated by given source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some generic VPN clients in Debian that are built reproducibly, but there are no Android or iOS VPN apps or  branded desktop client apps that meet this standard yet.  We recommend that VPN providers work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/ReproducibleBuilds&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;f-droid.org/docs/Reproducible_Builds&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reproducible-builds.org/&#34;&gt;Reproducible Builds&lt;/a&gt; group, or any other relevant &lt;a href=&#34;https://reproducible-builds.org/who/projects/&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; to achieve this key step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;apple-ios&#34;&gt;Apple iOS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on Android because iOS has a number of issues that make using VPNs for privacy less effective.  For example, VPNs on iOS will &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/unpatched-ios-bug-blocks-vpns-from-encrypting-all-traffic/&#34;&gt;leak IP addresses&lt;/a&gt;.  Apple knows about this issue, yet still has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.com/2022/08/19/apple_ios_vpn/&#34;&gt;not fixed&lt;/a&gt; it after a couple years.  On top of that, it is not possible to have reproducible builds on iOS because the actual executable binaries are encrypted by Apple&amp;rsquo;s proprietary Digital Restrictions Management (DRM), so only Apple could ever reproducibly build something.  If you are running Apple iOS, you are stuck trusting Apple to do the right thing, since they operate a relatively opaque, proprietary, strictly walled garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;run-your-own-vpn&#34;&gt;Run your own VPN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VPN security model means you have to put a ton of trust in the operator.  Questions of trust get much easier when you are talking about yourself or own organization.  There are many projects that aim to make it as easy as possible to run your own VPN service.  The good ones are all free software and have been audited, both the client source code and the server side setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amnezia.org&#34;&gt;Amnezia&lt;/a&gt; is a free service to create a personal VPN on your server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://leap.se/&#34;&gt;LEAP VPN&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;white label&amp;rdquo; VPN setup used to build Bitmask, CalyxVPN, RiseupVPN and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getoutline.org/&#34;&gt;Outline&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;makes it easy to create a VPN server, giving anyone access to the free and open internet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://we-pn.com/&#34;&gt;WEPN&lt;/a&gt; is a free software kit to become your own VPN provider, designed around a small hardware device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also generic VPN client apps based on standard protocols:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/nl.eduvpn.app/&#34;&gt;eduVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/de.blinkt.openvpn/&#34;&gt;OpenVPN for Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.github.shadowsocks/&#34;&gt;Shadowsocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/org.strongswan.android/&#34;&gt;strongSwan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/com.WireGuard.android/&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparing-vpns-to-tor-and-masque&#34;&gt;Comparing VPNs to Tor and MASQUE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is privacy that you seek, then there are other tools to review.  Tor is a longstanding community project that aims to make privacy proxies without compromise. Tor works similarly to VPN in that it is tunneling traffic to shared servers, the big difference is that your traffic is tunneled through three relays (in comparison to single hop VPNs). Each individual Tor relay cannot see the enough to put together a picture of who is doing what. At most, a relay can see what is done, but not who.  Or that someone is accessing Tor, but not their destination.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/org.torproject.android/&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; provides a VPN mode, but this is still full Tor protection, since it is just using the device&amp;rsquo;s VPN user experience to provide access to the Tor network.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt; then adds whole other layers of privacy protection that can only be implemented in the internet-enabled app.  This includes things like reducing metadata leaks in the HTTPS connection or web APIs, or isolating websites from each other within the browser, so they cannot read data about other sites the user has visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new approach that is somewhere in between a VPN and Tor are multi-hop &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2020/02/25/masque-review/&#34;&gt;MASQUE&lt;/a&gt; relays.  MASQUE is a new protocol that is similar to VPN and proxy protocols.  MASQUE is built on HTTP/3 aka QUIC, so it does not stick out as much as VPN or WireGuard traffic.  It also allows for multi-hop configurations.  MASQUE is only newly deployed, so there is not the two decades of experience working to minimize metadata leaks in the processes for relaying traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple iCloud Private Relay is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/icloud-private-relay/&#34;&gt;two hop deployment&lt;/a&gt; on MASQUE, which means that the Apple side can see that the user is sending traffic, and the Cloudflare side can see the destination, but not the user.  That does provide a real privacy improvement over a single hop system.  Unfortunately, Apple iCloud Private Relay fails most of the other tests laid out in this post.  Plus given the history of NSA programs like PRISM, and the willingness for US companies like Apple and Google to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/us-tech-giants-nsa-data&#34;&gt;take part&lt;/a&gt;, this setup is not clear protection from NSA and Five Eyes surveillance and targeting.  It would be relatively straightforward for those kinds of agencies to correlate the data from the Apple and Cloudflare side if they have access to the metadata from both sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If privacy is your primary concern, then it is worth investing time into tools like Tor.  If you have limited time and are mostly concerned about mass surveillance, then a good VPN is worth considering for some added privacy protection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving Websites Privately Over Tor Onion Services (From Your Laptop!)</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/08/29/serving-websites-privately-over-tor-onion-services-from-your-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/08/29/serving-websites-privately-over-tor-onion-services-from-your-laptop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this day and age when our data is consistently being tracked and profited off of, sharing information safely and securely is difficult. However, that does not necessarily mean that all network services are subject to such scrutiny. Users now have the ability to combine the security of HTTPS with the privacy benefits of Tor Browser and share information through Tor’s anonymous network services – &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.torproject.org/onion-services/&#34;&gt;Onion Services&lt;/a&gt;. By using an onion service, users can hide their location while active, connect to other Tor users, and retain their privacy throughout. But to do so, one needs to know how to set up an Onion Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the following instructions are specific to a Mac, with minor differences this can be applied to other devices and systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-download-and-set-up-the-tor-service&#34;&gt;Step 1 → Download and Set Up the Tor Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are multiple ways to download and set up tor, the simplest is to follow the instructions at &lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org/download/&#34;&gt;https://torproject.org/download/&lt;/a&gt; that goes along with the operating system you are using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information, you can follow the Tor installation guide: &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.torproject.org/onion-services/setup/install/&#34;&gt;https://community.torproject.org/onion-services/setup/install/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have successfully downloaded tor, to check if tor is running you can either open the browser and establish connection or use commands to check its success:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/opt/homebrew/bin/brew services start tor
/opt/homebrew/bin/brew services stop tor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note, in this step you are running the tor service on your machine to host the onion server. In later steps, we will be using the Tor Browser app to view the site remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-download-and-set-up-a-web-server-optional-during-development-but-required-for-production&#34;&gt;Step 2 → Download and Set Up a Web Server (Optional during Development, but required for Production)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to set up a website or some content for a client to access, we need to set up a local web server. A web server is the computer software and underlying hardware that communicates with a web browser using HTTP to distribute web pages to the client who requested it, with local web server examples including Apache and Nginx. The reason for this is that when it comes to the finished product, you can copy the fields into the apache web directory and that would be your web server&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for websites that we are building on npm, as npm has its own built in web server for development, it has its own local host web server ready. Hence, we can just point our hidden service web server at that, for testing and development. Once we arrive at production, we will use the apache or another web server to host our local service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install these web servers on MacOS can be difficult, so specifically for this operating system, it is best to install (or update) the homebrew package, which will then allow you to run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/opt/homebrew/bin/brew install apache
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have having trouble choosing a local web server or downloading it, a useful guidance tool is: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.javatpoint.com/how-to-install-apache-on-mac&#34;&gt;https://www.javatpoint.com/how-to-install-apache-on-mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default location where web servers run is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://localhost:80&#34;&gt;https://localhost:80&lt;/a&gt;. Hence, once you have downloaded the web server software, to check if it is working, open your browser and go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://localhost:80&#34;&gt;https://localhost:80&lt;/a&gt;. If you have successfully downloaded the web server software, you will be notified of this success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further steps, or multiple uses you may need to start or stop the web server software which can be done using the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apachectl start
sudo apachectl stop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-modify-your-tor-configuration-file&#34;&gt;Step 3 → Modify your Tor Configuration File&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to create the onion service link, you must mody the the tor configuration file (torrc) by adding the following lines and save the changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/my_website/
HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HiddenServiceDir line is to inform tor of where to save the onion v3 service link, hence you must modify this line to point to a file whose permissions include both readable and writable.
The HiddenServicePort line is informing Tor of the port people visiting your Onion Service will be using, which is currently set as localhost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the torrc file is saved in different places depending on the operating system being used, for MacOS, the file can be found at this filepath:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; /Library/”Application Support”/TorBrowser-Data/Tor/ 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-create-the-hidden-service-folder-optional&#34;&gt;Step 4 → Create the Hidden Service Folder (Optional)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this step is not necessary, doing this reduces the chance of problems later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have modified your tor configuration file, you should create the HiddenServiceDir directory where Tor will create the hostname file, which will contain your new onion v3 service address. For MacOS, this file should be created in the tor folder which can be found with this file path:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HiddenServiceDir /opt/homebrew/etc/tor/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The folder should be given the permissions to allow tor to read and write to it, which can be done by calling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;filename chmod 700 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-restart-tor-and-check-for-the-onion-service-link&#34;&gt;Step 5 → Restart Tor and Check for the Onion Service Link&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have restarted Tor, it should have created the file hostname with the new onion v3 service in the directory which you pointed it to with the HiddenServiceDir line in your torrc.
If it has not, potential areas to check for faults are:
- The HiddenServiceDir directory’s file permissions
- If Tor was properly restarted
- The torrc file modifications and if there are any incorrect file paths or mistakes
- The log files which you can find using &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.torproject.org/#Logs&#34;&gt;https://support.torproject.org/#Logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-test-your-onion-service&#34;&gt;Step 6 → Test Your Onion Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have successfully acquired your onion service link, you can then run it on Tor and it should direct you to the page which has been initially configured on apache (the same page we saw at localhost:80). If not, potential problems could include:
- Your web server software is no longer running and needs to be started
- The page is found at a different port
- One important thing to remember is that once you have gotten your onion address, a new one will not be generated, this is your permanent link whose content can be manipulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-7-build-the-file-web-page-being-used&#34;&gt;Step 7 → Build the File/Web Page Being Used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your onion service link is up and running, it is now time to display on it the html files you intend to share. To do so, if the files are a Node app or a progressive web app, and not a static html page or website, it is important to build the code first by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run build 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A potential problem could be that when you run a web service, especially a Node app or a progessive web app, it renders links for the domain it thinks it is at, not the one you intend it to be at. For a typical static website it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter because it is a static set of pages; however, when using a live node application, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to know what the public address is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix this problem, to your code you should add the following line which points directly to your new onion service address, like the example here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public:’2xx7phs7hw5fduqulcrthkmfaesxbsy5om5xpkpsn4y54mnbj4b6ekd.onion’
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-8-run-the-file-and-test-your-onion-service&#34;&gt;Step 8 → Run the File and Test your Onion Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- For this step, there are two potential methods depending on the type of content you intend to display on your Onion Service. For html documents or simple websites, the simplest method to run the file is to copy it into the folder which localhost:80 (or whichever port you are using) is connected to. For MacOS, the folder can be found at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/Library/WebServer/Documents
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To copy, the command to run is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo cp /path/from /path/to
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that is done, simply restart your Tor browser, head to your new onion service address and your html file can be found there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- To run a Node app or progress website, first the file needs to be running on your local server. To do so, one tip is to specify the port you intend to run it on, especially other ports that are running other websites or html content. For that, run the following command (changing it to point to the port you are using):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run service – –port 4000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To connect to this npm web server on port 4000 instead of apache, we need to modify the onion service configuration in the torrc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:4000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;accessing-the-onion-site&#34;&gt;Accessing the Onion site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the website is running on localhost at the port you have specified, restart your Tor service. Then, navigate to your new onion service address where your website is now live for all the people you have shared your secure link with. You can use any Tor-enabled browser, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/download/&#34;&gt;Tor Browser for Desktops&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/download/&#34;&gt;Tor Browser for Android&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionbrowser.com&#34;&gt;Onion Browser for iOS&lt;/a&gt; devices. You can also use a Tor-enabled vpn like &lt;a href=&#34;https://orbot.app&#34;&gt;Orbot for Android and iOS&lt;/a&gt;, to allow any browser, like Chrome or Brave, to access an onion address.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion Browser Release 2.6 Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/06/02/onion-browser-release-2.6-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/06/02/onion-browser-release-2.6-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about the best practices to browse the web securely on iOS using &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionbrowser.com&#34;&gt;Onion Browser&lt;/a&gt; Release 2.6 and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;Tor network&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionbrowser.com&#34;&gt;Onion Browser for iOS&lt;/a&gt; is a free, open-source web browser app developed originally by &lt;a href=&#34;https://mike.tig.as/&#34;&gt;Mike Tigas&lt;/a&gt;, with Release 2.6 as a collaboration with the Guardian Project. Onion Browser has Tor built-in and uses Tor to protect your web activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also watch the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL4-CVUWabKWeHeBpadBLjzlWVa7binXpj&#34;&gt;Onion Browser Video Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image25.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image25.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size1&#34; src=&#34;image25.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-this-tutorial-designed-for&#34;&gt;Who is this Tutorial designed for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few questions for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your internet content being blocked?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you concerned about your privacy while browsing the web?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you want to protect your data from aggressive advertisers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of these are true, this tutorial is for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-have-an-ios-device&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have an iOS device?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image21.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image21.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size1&#34; src=&#34;image21.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34;&gt;Try Orbot&lt;/a&gt;, the Tor connection for Android devices developed by the Guardian Project. Orbot allows you to route the apps on your phone through Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image20.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image20.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size1&#34; src=&#34;image20.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also try the &lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;Tor Browser for Android&lt;/a&gt;, the official Tor browser for Android developed by the Tor Project team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-what-exactly-is-the-tor-network&#34;&gt;First, what exactly is the Tor network?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image11.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image11.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size1&#34; src=&#34;image11.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tor network is a collection of servers, run by volunteers, that allows users to improve their privacy and security on the Internet. Tor&amp;rsquo;s users employ this network by connecting to their favorite services through a series of virtual tunnels rather than making a direct connection, thus allowing both organizations and individuals to share information over public networks without compromising their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how Tor works: When you connect to the internet using Tor, a circuit is created. A circuit is a group of 3 different Tor relays located in different parts of the world that work together with encryption to obfuscate your connection to websites and web services, making it hard for third parties to trace the activity back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image17.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image17.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image17.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;onion-browser-with-tor-is-an-important-application-for-ios-users&#34;&gt;Onion Browser, with Tor, is an important application for iOS users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because when you use Onion Browser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All your browsing is private, since your traffic is encrypted through the Tor network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one can see your activities, save your history, or influence your browsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And there is no trace left behind since tabs don&amp;rsquo;t hang around. They close when you&amp;rsquo;re done, so every search is new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-onion-browser-different-from-other-browsers-for-ios&#34;&gt;How is the Onion Browser different from other browsers for iOS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security and privacy require some compromises, and you should be aware that there are some limitations when using the Onion Browser:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple requires all web browser apps to use the same core web rendering engine. Due to this limitation, we are unable to compile and include our own web engine, based on Firefox Gecko, as with Tor Browser for desktop and Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onion Browser only tunnels traffic within the Onion Browser app. If you are using a smartphone be aware that information outside of Onion Browser is not protected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes your bandwidth speeds will be reduced, depending on the relays you are connecting to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites that flag Tor as suspicious will show a CAPTCHA loop and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to access them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certain features of many websites may be disabled or work poorly on Onion Browser, especially at the higher security levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;onboarding&#34;&gt;Onboarding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/onion-browser/id519296448&#34;&gt;downloading Onion Browser from the App Store&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ll give you a smooth start to using the app. After the initial loading screen, you&amp;rsquo;ll be invited to connect to Tor before you start browsing. Be advised: Onion Browser always needs to connect to Tor before you browse. There&amp;rsquo;s no operational mode that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- ![](image24.png) --&gt; &lt;!-- ![](image14.png) --&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image24.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image24.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image14.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image14.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two options here: connecting directly to Tor, as most users do, or connecting via a special &amp;ldquo;bridge&amp;rdquo;. This latter option requires configuration, and we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss it in a separate section of this tutorial. Select &amp;ldquo;Connect to Tor&amp;rdquo; and the app will let you know when it is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image18.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image18.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image18.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on &amp;ldquo; Next&amp;rdquo; to set up your security level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image30.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image30.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image30.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three levels of security you can select, according to your needs. For many users, Level 2 is the best choice to start. Click on &amp;ldquo;Learn More&amp;rdquo; to see more details about each option. Tap &amp;ldquo;Start Browsing&amp;rdquo; to begin using Onion Browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-onion-browser-home-page&#34;&gt;The Onion Browser Home Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the home page of Onion Browser you&amp;rsquo;ll see a couple of website suggestions, as well as more information about the app. We&amp;rsquo;d welcome your support for our work. Use the Donate Link to see the ways you can contribute with a donation. You can also subscribe to the Tor Newsletter to get updates about security and privacy on the Internet from the Tor team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image22.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image22.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image22.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the home page, in the top navigation bar, you&amp;rsquo;ll see there are two icons you don&amp;rsquo;t find in other browsers, a Shield on the top left side and an Onion on the top right side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- ![](image15.jpg) --&gt; &lt;!-- ![](image5.jpg) --&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image15.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image15.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image5.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image5.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss these in a bit. The Onion Browser also includes features you&amp;rsquo;ll recognize like Bookmarks, Share, New Tab, Switch Tabs, and Accessing Settings. These are common in other browsers and work in the same manner here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;visiting-websites&#34;&gt;Visiting websites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you visit websites, Onion Browser will give you additional information about the security and nature of your connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTPS websites will show a green lock on the right side of the URL bar, tap on it to verify the Certificate Information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image1.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image1.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image1.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap on the Shield icon to see your current security level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image13.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image13.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image13.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap on the Onion icon to see the Tor circuit you are using, sometimes your current circuit will be too slow or it will not work properly, for those cases use the &amp;ldquo;New Circuit&amp;rdquo; button and you will be automatically connected to a new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image7.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image7.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image7.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this drop-down menu, you will also find the option to connect to Tor using bridges. Please remember that you should always try to connect to Tor without using bridges and only use them if that fails. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about bridges later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Share icon allows you to send a link to the website you are looking at using other apps in your device. It also allows you to open the link using Safari if the site is not opening properly using Tor. This will be out of the Tor network and is not safe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image19.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image19.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image19.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same applies to open images and links with Safari. But you can also open links safely on a new tab, and navigate them the same way you will do it on any other browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image12.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image12.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image12.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your screen times out or you send the browser to the background all your current tabs will disappear when you return to your browser, this is a security feature that can be changed in your settings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downloading content is easiest with the Share icon. Display your content (such as a PDF-formatted article) in a tab, then tap the Share icon. Select &amp;lsquo;Save to Files&amp;rsquo;, then on the next screen, choose the desired locations (&amp;ldquo;Downloads&amp;rdquo; folder is shown here). Tap &amp;lsquo;Save&amp;rsquo; and the content will be saved in the Downloads folder for later use or further sharing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- ![](image23.png) --&gt; &lt;!-- ![](image16.png) --&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image23.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image23.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image16.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image16.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;security-connectivity&#34;&gt;Security &amp;amp; Connectivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bridges&#34;&gt;Bridges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a special way to connect to the Tor network, designed for users in the most restrictive geographies or users personally at risk of invasive monitoring. Bridges are like special on-ramps for Tor that are more aggressive about defeating monitoring. That comes at a cost in performance, though. We like to reserve these pathways for most impacted users, so please use them sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know bad actors are monitoring Tor usage in your geography, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to configure a bridge immediately when you first open Onion Browser. You can do that right from the first onboarding screen, before connecting to Tor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image6.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image6.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image6.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you configure your bridge immediately or after you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Onion Browser for a while, you need to be careful how you get your bridge information. You have several options. See the Bridge Configuration settings (accessed during on-boarding as above or by tapping on the Onion icon when viewing a website and then tapping &amp;lsquo;Bridge Configuration&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image2.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image2.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image2.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first option should be the list of bridges using the so-called Obfs4 technology, a list already built into Onion Browser. Select the &amp;ldquo;Built-in Obfs4&amp;rdquo; option and Onion Browser will instruct Tor to use that selection of bridges as it attempts to connect. Tap &amp;ldquo;connect&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the bridges on that list can become crowded and connection may fail here, too. If you know a trustworthy person who uses a bridge to connect to Tor, your second option is to have your friend help you by sending you a bridge QRCode your device can scan and automatically configure to use that bridge. Or, less securely, you can copy/paste a bridge identifier that your friend sends you via another service (messaging, for example). To use this option, tap &amp;ldquo;Custom Bridges&amp;rdquo;, and then either scan the provided QRCode or paste your provided bridge into the text area shown, then tap &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- ![](image4.jpg) --&gt; &lt;!-- ![](image8.jpg) --&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image4.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image4.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image8.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image8.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If these options fail, you can get access to a fresh selection of Obfs4 bridges using the service called MOAT to get up-to-date information in real-time. This option works in a way that does not expose itself to suspicion. To use this option, select &amp;ldquo;Built-in Meek/Azure&amp;rdquo; and tap &amp;ldquo;connect&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, the Tor Project itself also maintains a list of bridges. For this option, tap &amp;lsquo;Custom Bridges&amp;rsquo;, then &amp;lsquo;Request Bridges from torproject.org&amp;rsquo; and follow the instructions there. You&amp;rsquo;ll get a bridge identifier, and you&amp;rsquo;ll paste it into the text area, same as you would if a friend provided it to you. After pasting, tap &amp;ldquo;connect&amp;rdquo;. Note that this method of contacting the Tor Project to get a bridge identifier is an action that itself might be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we want to steer you away from using bridges. The degradation of the user experience can be extreme and please remember that there are people who actually require this capability to get any connection at all. As capacity is limited, we want to give those people the first opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;biometric-authentication&#34;&gt;BioMetric Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can place a second level of access security on Onion Browser by using its authentication option. You might prefer this option if you believe you face a physical security threat, if there is a chance your device might get stolen or if your device might be otherwise misused by people you don&amp;rsquo;t trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to set up your iOS device to require security at login via a 6-digit numeric Passcode, FaceID or TouchID. Use the iOS Settings app. Select and configure the method you prefer. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already done that, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to change. Be aware that all manipulations of our authentication settings here will require you to enter your password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image10.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image10.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image10.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now tap the Onion Browser settings icon to get to the Settings page. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a selection option for &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lock App with TouchID/FaceID or Device Passcode&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Select that option to enable it and restart Onion Browser. On your next use, Onion Browser will require your ID (in whatever form you&amp;rsquo;ve requested) before it will start up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;useful-tips&#34;&gt;Useful Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-mode&#34;&gt;Dark Mode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Onion Browser has a built-in Dark Mode that allows it to comply with the system setting for the &amp;ldquo;dark&amp;rdquo; color scheme. To set Dark Mode, visit the iOS Settings application and tap Display &amp;amp; Brightness. Select your appearance here and Onion Browser will comply with this setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image3.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image3.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image3.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tab-security-hide-web-pages-when-switching-apps&#34;&gt;Tab Security - Hide Web Pages When Switching Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiding web pages when switching apps is a feature required by people who are in danger of having their device removed from their person by other bad actors. If that happens, the contents of their open tabs can be seen and perhaps screen-shotted by those bad actors and used in prosecution. While hiding web pages sounds great at first, it means you lose your browsing &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo; when switching back to Onion Browser later. Frankly, it is terribly inconvenient for most users. So, there are lesser options, too. From the Onion Browser Settings page, tap &amp;ldquo;Tab Security&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image29.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image29.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image29.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then select from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;forget-in-background&#34;&gt;Forget in Background&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happens when you tap the HOME button, otherwise switch apps, or the display times-out and the login screen is presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;forget-at-shutdown&#34;&gt;Forget at Shutdown&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happens only when user actually closes the app or shuts down the device&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;remember-tabs&#34;&gt;Remember Tabs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tabs are NOT hidden; this setting is also called &amp;ldquo;Startup in last state&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of &amp;ldquo;remove web pages when switching apps&amp;rdquo; because it means your browsing state is saved between sessions. For many, this is a tremendous time-saver, but users concerned about their device being taken from them should not enable this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: Your bookmarks are also an indication of your browsing interests. Creating many bookmarks on the device leaves a certain &amp;ldquo;fingerprint&amp;rdquo; about your browsing intentions in the same way open tabs indicate what&amp;rsquo;s actually being used. See the&lt;/em&gt; Nextcloud Bookmarks &lt;em&gt;feature as a way to resolve this problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;onion-browser-as-your-default-system-browser&#34;&gt;Onion Browser As Your Default System Browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of ways you can acquire a link to web content and resources. Many applications, when seeing a link, will offer the option to open that link in the web browser. On iOS, Safari is the system browser, registered to open links, and iOS doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually allow other browsers to have that privilege. Safari doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Tor, so it&amp;rsquo;s not safe to open links that way. We can&amp;rsquo;t make Onion Browser the &amp;ldquo;system browser&amp;rdquo;, but there is a way to disable Safari and allow Onion Browser to open your links. Follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the iOS Settings app. Tap &amp;ldquo;Screen Time&amp;rdquo; (if it&amp;rsquo;s your first time using this feature, several help screens will follow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image28.png) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image28.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image28.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tap &amp;ldquo;Content &amp;amp; Privacy Restrictions&amp;rdquo; to enable it. Tap &amp;ldquo;Allowed Apps&amp;rdquo;. Tap &amp;ldquo;Safari&amp;rdquo; to disable it. This way, Safari won&amp;rsquo;t be opened when links are clicked in any app starting with http:// or https://. OnionBrowser can now open the links safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nextcloud-bookmarks&#34;&gt;NextCloud Bookmarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookmarks make it easy to access frequently-desired content as well as to preserve access to infrequently-visited, but necessary, sites. However, bookmarks can also represent intent or interest and, for those in danger of losing their device to bad actors, this can be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use NextCloud, you can manage your Onion Browser bookmarks on your other devices and synchronize them with Onion Browser. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- ![](image26.png) --&gt; &lt;!-- ![](image9.png) --&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image26.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image26.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image9.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size2&#34; src=&#34;image9.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tap the Bookmarks icon, then tap &amp;lsquo;Sync with Nextcloud&amp;rsquo;.Enter the link for your Nextcloud server along with your username and password, then tap &amp;lsquo;Sync Bookmarks&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not a Nextcloud user and this sounds interesting, find more about NextCloud at nextcloud.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-failure-modes-and-how-to-recover&#34;&gt;Some Failure Modes and How to Recover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about ways in which Onion Browser - and the mountain of software and Internet network architecture behind it - can let you down. Yes, it DOES happen. Sometimes your network just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the performance and responsiveness it requires. Sometimes your network is under heavy surveillance. Sometimes the Tor network is under direct attack by bad actors. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a few of the failures you might experience and see what you can do to mitigate at least some of the impacts. We regret that this list is not complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-start-up&#34;&gt;On Start-up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I have no network connection of any kind and I don&amp;rsquo;t realize it? What if my network connection is very slow? What if Tor is blocked in my country?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if you know - via friends or trusted information sources - that Tor is blocked in your country, you&amp;rsquo;ll need configure access via a bridge on your very first startup. Please revisit the prior discussion on how to properly configure Tor bridge access. Please remember, bridges tend to degrade the user experience in a number of ways. They&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;ldquo;last resort&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not connected to a local or wide-area network (and don&amp;rsquo;t realize it) or if your connection is very poor (low-bandwidth), or if Tor is blocked in your country, Onion Browser won&amp;rsquo;t be able to start. Unfortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s no safe way to automatically distinguish between these different conditions. First, try to verify that the device itself has a connection or move to another location &amp;amp; network. Please remember, Tor can be slow to start up - especially on your first use - even under the best circumstances because it has to discover its network of nodes (at least partly) before it can build circuits. This does take a little patience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-restart&#34;&gt;On Restart&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if Tor fails to start or restart properly within Onion Browser (can this happen, for example, when switching tabs)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Tor fails on start/restart, Onion Browser assumes that it&amp;rsquo;s because the Tor nodes available from your location are blocked. Onion Browser will urge you to configure bridges. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to proceed, though. You actually need to stop Onion Browser (switch to another app, or kill the app by swiping it out of iOS&amp;rsquo; app-cards overview) and then start it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you experience a lot of this type of failure, you may want to consider the Onion Browser setting that allows you to &amp;ldquo;Remember Tabs&amp;rdquo; (also called &amp;ldquo;start up in last state&amp;rdquo;). That&amp;rsquo;s available using &amp;ldquo;Settings -&amp;gt; Tab Security -&amp;gt; Remember Tabs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;after-a-heavy-use-session&#34;&gt;After A Heavy-Use Session&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on within Onion Browser and sometimes after a lot of use (or maybe due to a lot of tabs open for a long time) Onion Browser will run out of working memory on the device. In this case, iOS will probably kill the app by itself (though you may have to swipe it away from the app-cards overview under certain circumstances). When you start it again, it will be a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another good time to remember, if your situation allows it, use the &amp;ldquo;Remember Tabs&amp;rdquo; feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;failures-under-regular-use&#34;&gt;Failures Under Regular Use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may experience using Onion Browser in a normal way, seemingly fine, and then when tapping a link or visiting a new site nothing seems to happen. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to know if the link or site is the problem, or if Onion Browser or Tor is the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check if Tor is still running by creating a new tab and visiting, for example, DuckDuckGo.com. If Tor really has failed, you should leave the app and enter back after a few seconds (that is, switch to another app, then return). That action should restart Tor. If that fails to help, go to iOS&amp;rsquo; app-cards overview, swipe-away Onion Browser and start it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the new tab opening to DuckDuckGo.com does work, then Tor is still operating and that&amp;rsquo;s a good indicator that the link or website you visited contains some JavaScript Onion Browser thinks is unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onion Browser has a pop-up and ad blocker integrated. These, unfortunately, might interfere with the web page in a way that makes it break. These features cannot be switched off, currently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, failure can happen when the Security Level currently set for the page is denying the website from taking certain actions. Loading media is one such action, though not every time. If you&amp;rsquo;re sure leaking your browsing information to somebody listening on your connection isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem, you might want to lower the security level to &amp;ldquo;Bronze&amp;rdquo;, at least for that site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-these-circuits-you-talk-about&#34;&gt;What Are These &amp;ldquo;Circuits&amp;rdquo; You Talk About?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circuit is the path your communications take through the Tor network (whose nodes exist in many countries in the world). Normally, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to take specific care regarding the circuit, because that&amp;rsquo;s Tor&amp;rsquo;s business. However, depending on the &amp;ldquo;exit node&amp;rdquo; Tor has chosen, you might see a website localized wrongly or a website that mistakes you for a hostile due to your country-of-origin (which Tor has set). In those cases you can request a new circuit. It&amp;rsquo;s easy, right there on the circuit display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](image7.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;ctr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;image7.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&#34;size3&#34; src=&#34;image7.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circuit display could also hint to the reason of a slow connection. If you&amp;rsquo;re routed around the world, that might be the problem. However, Tor typically tries to avoid these situations automatically and chooses circuits with hops near you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;custom-site-settings&#34;&gt;Custom Site Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve introduced &amp;ldquo;Security Levels&amp;rdquo; in the new Onion Browser, there&amp;rsquo;s much less need to store custom settings for individual websites. That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing because these settings are hard to remember once customized. For example, did you remove all restrictions from a website because you were once on a less restricted network? Well, when you&amp;rsquo;re back on your surveilled network, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to remember that you customized just that one site. That can lead to an unplanned exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you like the new &amp;ldquo;Security Levels&amp;rdquo; mechanism - it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to monitor how much risk you&amp;rsquo;re exposed to using this mechanism. Enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;support&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on Onion Browser during 2019 and through mid-2020 was funded by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opentech.fund/&#34;&gt;Open Technology Fund&lt;/a&gt; and sponsored by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/&#34;&gt;Guardian Project&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtigas&#34;&gt;Mike Tigas&lt;/a&gt; was development architect, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tladesignz&#34;&gt;Benjamin Erhart&lt;/a&gt; was lead developer. &lt;a href=&#34;https://okthanks.com/&#34;&gt;OkThanks&lt;/a&gt; provided user-centered design services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To contribute to the long-term maintenance of Onion Browser, please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionbrowser.com/donate&#34;&gt;donation page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onions on Apples: A New Release of Onion Browser for iOS</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/10/08/onions-on-apples-a-new-release-of-onion-browser-for-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/10/08/onions-on-apples-a-new-release-of-onion-browser-for-ios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During 2019, Guardian Project has been working with developer Mike Tigas to make improvements to his Tor-enabled web browser for iOS, &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionbrowser.com/&#34;&gt;Onion Browser&lt;/a&gt;.  Here we re-cap the major improvements currently - and soon-to-be - available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike developed Onion Browser on his own, in close collaboration with the Tor Project.  Though we’ve worked with Mike in the recent-past, this 2019 project &amp;ndash; funded by the Open Technology Fund &amp;ndash; gave us significantly more bandwidth to address the challenges of running Tor on iOS, especially alongside a full web-browsing feature set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Onion Browser, our Tor connectivity runs in the same process as the browser itself.  Tor Browser for Android uses a similar model, though the general purpose Orbot app for Android is separate from the applications using its services (apps configure Orbot as a proxy, in the same manner as SOCKS).  This latter model is not available on iOS and, it turns out, iOS puts some additional restrictions on apps like ours as well.  These have, over time, created some thorny problems for Onion Browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest release of Onion Browser upgraded to Tor version 0.4.0.5 which greatly improves reliability when the app comes back from background. The application was updated with modern versions of all the incorporated 3rd-party libraries.  This includes an upgrade to the underlying Endless browser-core.  The often-requested ability to &amp;ldquo;open the app in its last state&amp;rdquo; feature was added as well as a mechanism to hide the browser’s content when switching between applications.  Advanced users of the app had reported issues configuring bridges in previous releases and these have been fixed.  It’s now possible to report a bug or rate the app from within the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our new work, an important network traffic leakage discovered in earlier releases have been mitigated.  Web browsers generally utilize the services of the Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP) to determine if a website’s security certificate is still valid. Status checks on iOS are provided by a system library that can’t use the Tor service, so these service calls leak.  A mechanism has been found to prevent leakage in a large number of circumstances, but not completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re now completing our second big development push which will feature an upgraded and simplified on-boarding experience as well as improvements to the organization of application settings.  We’ve also upgraded the experience of setting per-website security parameters (which can be either one-time-only or “sticky”).  The leakage corrections we implemented will also allow us to implement the ability to download and save files in non-HTML content formats, or share such files with other applications. Additionally, we implemented an improved technique to limit Javascript “re-insertion” attacks in WebRTC pages. We expect this release to happen during October or early November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onion Browser’s medium- and long-term maintenance are a volunteer effort.  If you wish to support this project into the future, please visit Mike Tigas’s Patreon page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tor Project: Orfox Paved the Way for Tor Browser on Android </title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/09/03/tor-project-orfox-paved-the-way-for-tor-browser-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/09/03/tor-project-orfox-paved-the-way-for-tor-browser-on-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, we tagged the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/Orfox/releases/tag/Orfox-Final-RIP-v16&#34;&gt;final release of Orfox&lt;/a&gt;, an important milestone for us in our work on Tor. Today, we pushed this final build out to all the Orfox users on Google Play, which forces them to upgrade to the official Tor Browser for Android..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;orfoxrip.png&#34; alt=&#34;Orfox RIP app image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was never to become the primary developer or maintainer of the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; tor-enabled web browser app on Android. Instead, we chose to act as a catalyst to get the Tor Project and the Tor Browser development team themselves to take on Android development, and upstream our work into the primary codebase. This has happened, and it is a great news for everyone. The work for developing and updating Tor Browser on the desktop and Android are now coordinated and synchronized, and end-users benefit from more frequent updates and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/amoghbl1&#34;&gt;Amazing Amogh&lt;/a&gt; can focus on his PhD studies, and not on continuing the heroic task of trying to merge Firefox releases, Tor Browser patches, and Android proxy setting code for four different HTTP network libraries! Thanks, Amogh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.torproject.org/orfox-paved-way-tor-browser-android&#34;&gt;Tor Project&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; announcing the last release of Orfox:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile browsing has increasingly become the primary way many people go online. In 2014, Tor Browser was used by millions of people on their desktop computers, but there was not yet a way to use Tor on a mobile device. We have long recognized the need for protecting people&amp;rsquo;s rights to privacy and freedom online, including on mobile devices, but as a small nonprofit organization, we were not yet ready to meet that demand. That&amp;rsquo;s when our friends at Guardian Project began exploring the possibility of providing Tor Browser on Android themselves. Their answer was Orfox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orfox was first released 23 September 2015. Over the next three years, Orfox continously improved and became a popular way for people to browse the internet with more privacy than standard browsers, and Orfox was crucial for helping people circumvent censorship and access blocked sites and critical resources. It was installed over 14 million times, and maintained over 1 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 2017, we began working on our own Tor Browser for Android. Because of Orfox&amp;rsquo;s success, the development path for us was clearer and more in reach. We were able to build upon Guardian Project&amp;rsquo;s work and bring a browser with the full protections of Tor Browser to Android. We released the alpha version of Tor Browser for Android in September 2018 and launched the stable version this May. After nearly a year since we released the alpha version of Tor Browser on Android, the time for sunsetting Orfox has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have Orfox, you will see the upgrade and prompt to install Tor Browser for Android soon. Otherwise, you can just &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.torbrowser&amp;amp;hl=en_US&#34;&gt;go directly to install and get it now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tor Project: Orfox Paved the Way for Tor Browser on Android </title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/09/03/tor-project-orfox-paved-the-way-for-tor-browser-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/09/03/tor-project-orfox-paved-the-way-for-tor-browser-on-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, we tagged the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/Orfox/releases/tag/Orfox-Final-RIP-v16&#34;&gt;final release of Orfox&lt;/a&gt;, an important milestone for us in our work on Tor. Today, we pushed this final build out to all the Orfox users on Google Play, which forces them to upgrade to the official Tor Browser for Android..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;orfoxrip.png&#34; alt=&#34;Orfox RIP app image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was never to become the primary developer or maintainer of the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; tor-enabled web browser app on Android. Instead, we chose to act as a catalyst to get the Tor Project and the Tor Browser development team themselves to take on Android development, and upstream our work into the primary codebase. This has happened, and it is a great news for everyone. The work for developing and updating Tor Browser on the desktop and Android are now coordinated and synchronized, and end-users benefit from more frequent updates and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/amoghbl1&#34;&gt;Amazing Amogh&lt;/a&gt; can focus on his PhD studies, and not on continuing the heroic task of trying to merge Firefox releases, Tor Browser patches, and Android proxy setting code for four different HTTP network libraries! Thanks, Amogh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.torproject.org/orfox-paved-way-tor-browser-android&#34;&gt;Tor Project&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; announcing the last release of Orfox:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile browsing has increasingly become the primary way many people go online. In 2014, Tor Browser was used by millions of people on their desktop computers, but there was not yet a way to use Tor on a mobile device. We have long recognized the need for protecting people&amp;rsquo;s rights to privacy and freedom online, including on mobile devices, but as a small nonprofit organization, we were not yet ready to meet that demand. That&amp;rsquo;s when our friends at Guardian Project began exploring the possibility of providing Tor Browser on Android themselves. Their answer was Orfox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orfox was first released 23 September 2015. Over the next three years, Orfox continously improved and became a popular way for people to browse the internet with more privacy than standard browsers, and Orfox was crucial for helping people circumvent censorship and access blocked sites and critical resources. It was installed over 14 million times, and maintained over 1 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 2017, we began working on our own Tor Browser for Android. Because of Orfox&amp;rsquo;s success, the development path for us was clearer and more in reach. We were able to build upon Guardian Project&amp;rsquo;s work and bring a browser with the full protections of Tor Browser to Android. We released the alpha version of Tor Browser for Android in September 2018 and launched the stable version this May. After nearly a year since we released the alpha version of Tor Browser on Android, the time for sunsetting Orfox has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have Orfox, you will see the upgrade and prompt to install Tor Browser for Android soon. Otherwise, you can just &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.torbrowser&amp;amp;hl=en_US&#34;&gt;go directly to install and get it now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetCipher update: global, SOCKS, and TLSv1.2</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/06/25/netcipher-update-global-socks-and-tlsv1.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2019/06/25/netcipher-update-global-socks-and-tlsv1.2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/code/netcipher&#34;&gt;NetCipher&lt;/a&gt; has been relatively quiet in recent years, because it kept
on working, doing it was doing. Now, we have had some recent
discoveries about the guts of Android that mean NetCipher is a lot easier
to use on recent Android versions.  On top of that, TLSv1.2 now reigns
supreme and is basically everywhere, so it is time to turn TLSv1.0 and
TLSv1.1 entirely off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-single-method-to-enable-proxying-for-the-whole-app&#34;&gt;A single method to enable proxying for the whole app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of Android 8.0 (26 aka Oreo), it is now possible to set a
&lt;code&gt;URLStreamHandlerFactory&lt;/code&gt;, which creates &lt;code&gt;URLConnection&lt;/code&gt; instances
with custom configurations.  If an app is using the built-in
&lt;code&gt;HttpURLConnection&lt;/code&gt; API for its networking, it is now possible to
enable global proxying with a single method call when the app starts:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/NetCipher/libnetcipher/info/guardianproject/netcipher/NetCipher.html#useGlobalProxy--&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NetCipher.useGlobalProxy()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Then the actual proxy configuration can be set dynamically, using
things like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/NetCipher/libnetcipher/info/guardianproject/netcipher/NetCipher.html#useTor--&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NetCipher.useTor()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/NetCipher/libnetcipher/info/guardianproject/netcipher/NetCipher.html#clearProxy--&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NetCipher.clearProxy()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;URL.setURLStreamHandlerFactory()&lt;/code&gt; method is a little odd because it cannot be unset or changed after it has been set.  NetCipher handles this by letting the app configure the proxy settings separately, so they can be disabled even though the custom &lt;code&gt;URLStreamHandlerFactory&lt;/code&gt; is still active.  Also, it is possible to use &lt;code&gt;URL.setURLStreamHandlerFactory&lt;/code&gt; on Android 7.x also, but it leaks DNS, so it is not recommended for privacy proxies.  It would still be useful as a failsafe for apps that use &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/NetCipher/libnetcipher/info/guardianproject/netcipher/NetCipher.html#getHttpURLConnection-java.lang.String-&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NetCipher.getHttpURLConnection()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in case there are any calls to &lt;code&gt;URL.openConnection()&lt;/code&gt; added with the right proxy setup.  At the very least, the content will be proxied on Android 7.x, even if it leaks DNS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;native-socks-support&#34;&gt;Native SOCKS Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Android 7.0 (24 aka Nougat), Google switched over to OpenJDK, which brought working SOCKS support to Android.  SOCKS is the best protocol for effective proxying, and it is the protocol that Tor itself has always natively supported.  Orbot has always provided a separaete HTTP Proxy to support Android, but that has always proven brittle, and was often the source of problems.  Since Android 7.0 and above natively support SOCKS, calling &lt;code&gt;NetCipher.useTor()&lt;/code&gt; will now default to using SOCKS if the device is running Android 7.0 or higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bye-bye-tlsv1-0-and-tlsv1-1&#34;&gt;Bye bye TLSv1.0 and TLSv1.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transport Layer Security (TLS) is the protocol that powers most of the internet these days.  It gives HTTPS the S for &amp;ldquo;Secure&amp;rdquo;. After many years of slow updates and an increasing number of vulnerabilities, there is finally critical mass to stop using the old, broken versions.  TLS version 1.2 is not seriously vulnerable and is supported basically everywhere.  TLSv1.2 was finalized in 2008, so this is very far from the bleeding edge.  TLSv1.2 is supported all the way back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/javax/net/ssl/SSLSocket#protocols&#34;&gt;Android 4.1&lt;/a&gt;.  TLSv1.0 and TLSv1.1 are due to be officially deprecated by the IETF, the standards body that actually creates the TLS standard.  The major browser vendors have all promised to drop them in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to enforce TLSv1.2 support would be to configure the server-side to stop supporting TLSv1.0 and TLSv1.1, like is recommend with SSLv2 and SSLv3.  Using NetCipher to do this on the client side
means that old app versions and devices of F-Droid and old devices will continue to work.
Also, doing it client-side means that all TLS connections will gain this protection regardless of which server the client is connecting to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;NetCipher&lt;/em&gt; approach means apps will never use TLS older than v1.2 since they will refuse to connect unless TLSv1.2 is available.  The server-side can then safely support TLSv1.0 and TLSv1.1, so older clients and Android devices will still be able to connect, even if they do not support TLSv1.2.  It is win-win
for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one case that will fail entirely is connections to servers that do not support TLSv1.2.  If a webserver does not support TLSv1.2, it is really too old to be used safely anyway.  Even the oldest supported Red Hat Enterprise Linux release (6) supports TLSv1.2, and that was released in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;webview-proxying&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;WebView&lt;/code&gt; Proxying!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/webkit/WebView&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;WebView&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an easy way to show a webpage or build a web app.  If you want that page to always go over Tor, that is difficult since &lt;code&gt;WebView&lt;/code&gt; has no API to configure proxying.  NetCipher has a long running collection of hacks that span the Android versions to get proxying working in &lt;code&gt;WebView&lt;/code&gt;.  We have revived those, modernized them, and added a full test suite to confirm whether the proxying is leaking.  The good news is that proxying is working pretty well on all but Android 5.x (21 and 22), where it totally fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another new Android API we discovered is &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/webkit/WebViewClient.html#shouldInterceptRequest(android.webkit.WebView,%20android.webkit.WebResourceRequest)&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;WebViewClient.shouldInterceptRequest()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  This is an official API for manipulating HTTP requests in &lt;code&gt;WebView&lt;/code&gt;.  It is an an easy place to insert custom &lt;code&gt;HttpURLConnection&lt;/code&gt; instances, like NetCipher needs to configure proxy support and stronger TLS.  Using this API means eliminating Java reflection hacks.  But it has a large caveat: it only works for &lt;em&gt;GET&lt;/em&gt; requests.  Since the request body is not accessible via this API, it is not possible to implement &lt;em&gt;POST&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt; requests.  One nice approach for the best of both works is to handle &lt;em&gt;GET&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;code&gt;WebViewClient.shouldInterceptRequest()&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;POST&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUT&lt;/em&gt; could then be implemented separately using the reflection methods in NetCipher WebView.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tests&#34;&gt;Tests!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release also brings with it an extensive, new test suite.  These let us confirm that things are working on all the supporting Android versions, while also serving as simple example cases.  For example, the tests now confirm which Android releases support &lt;code&gt;WebView&lt;/code&gt; proxying, based on Cure53&amp;rsquo;s very useful &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cure53/HTTPLeaks&#34;&gt;HTTPLeaks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbot v16: a whole new look, and easier to use!</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2018/01/05/orbot-v16-a-whole-new-look-and-easier-to-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 13:14:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2018/01/05/orbot-v16-a-whole-new-look-and-easier-to-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot/&#34;&gt;Orbot: Tor for Android&lt;/a&gt; has a new release (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/orbot.git/tag/?h=16.0.0-RC-2&#34;&gt;tag&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/orbot.git/diff/CHANGELOG?h=16.0.0-RC-1-CHANGELOG&amp;amp;id=5542e8e192fcff24284179e7fdb31cf877f79efd&#34;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt;), with a major update to the user experience and interface. This is the 16th major release of Orbot, since it was launched in late 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main screen of the app now looks quite different, with all the major features and functions exposed for easy access. We have also added a new onboarding setup wizard for first time users, that assists with configuring connections to the Tor network for users in places where Tor itself is blocked. This release also continues to support users looking to use Orbot to unblock specific apps, that may not be available on their network or country. From the main screen, users can activate Orbot’s built-in VPN feature, and easily choose which specific apps they want to be routed over the Tor network. You can also refresh your Tor identity, rebuilding all circuit connections through the network, using the circular reload icon in the expanded notification provided by Orbot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The update is rolling out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.android&#34;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;, and will also be available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/fdroid/&#34;&gt;Guardian Project’s F-Droid Repo&lt;/a&gt; soon. You can also find &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n8fr8/orbot/releases&#34;&gt;Android APKs on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THANKS TO: pgerber, syphyr, Khsed4, BjarniRunar, Unpublished, igortoliveira, goapunk, SpotComms, AkshatAgrawal05, dixidroid, arrase and others for the bug reports and fixes on the Orbot app. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wwwiretap&#34;&gt;Sina&lt;/a&gt; with Team Cymru for the extra infrastructure provided to help users in places where Tor itself is blocked. Also, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mrphs&#34;&gt;Nima&lt;/a&gt; for the guidance, support and motivation to get this release out sooner rather than later!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;gallery-13&#39; class=&#39;gallery galleryid-13934 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-medium&#39;&gt;
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122015.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122015-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122015-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122015-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122015-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122015.png 1440w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122035.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122035-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122035-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122035-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122035-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122035.png 1440w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122111.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122111-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122111-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122111-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122111-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122111.png 1440w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122301.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122301-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122301-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122301-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122301-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122301.png 1440w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122344.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122344-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122344-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122344-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122344-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/device-2018-01-05-122344.png 1440w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#39;clear: both&#39; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/** v16.0.0 RC 1 / 5 Jan 2018 / 309c42be916d866a28adacb0a4f92d692cbd6009 **/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7e9890e tweak default bridge behavior based on locale&lt;br /&gt;
fec853c updates to notification for Android O / SDK26&lt;br /&gt;
b161043 Merge pull request #106 from Unpublished/fix_binary_search&lt;br /&gt;
ab472d5 Merge branch ‘syphyr-master’&lt;br /&gt;
4fc3e7e Merge branch ‘master’ of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syphyr/orbot&#34;&gt;https://github.com/syphyr/orbot&lt;/a&gt; into syphyr-master&lt;br /&gt;
792ee2b Merge branch ‘BjarniRunar-master’&lt;br /&gt;
0d4a735 Merge branch ‘master’ of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BjarniRunar/orbot&#34;&gt;https://github.com/BjarniRunar/orbot&lt;/a&gt; into BjarniRunar-master&lt;br /&gt;
c7b1441 add comment about app updates URL&lt;br /&gt;
d21ff80 update strings and code for switching Locale in app&lt;br /&gt;
5c5790c fix binary search&lt;br /&gt;
38b0063 update build to &lt;sup&gt;16000005&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; for 16.0.0-BETA-2&lt;br /&gt;
7da26a3 update strings from transifex&lt;br /&gt;
ce714fa use the proper localized start/end params&lt;br /&gt;
38cc29c externalize more strings&lt;br /&gt;
8bcc9a4 update gitignore&lt;br /&gt;
6e3b6ba add onboarding strings localizatoin&lt;br /&gt;
154e373 ensure appupdater check starts up&lt;br /&gt;
703f8a1 move update back to older (reduce version code)&lt;br /&gt;
b556518 move update back to older version&lt;br /&gt;
680d108 update json for testing&lt;br /&gt;
e4f6348 test updating json&lt;br /&gt;
dafcdd7 enable AppUpdater notificatoins through Github&lt;br /&gt;
3b5a361 update handling of vpn enabled and app onclick&lt;br /&gt;
e21474c updates to layout and strings for bridge wizard&lt;br /&gt;
2a9691c make sure the back arrow works&lt;br /&gt;
244231c remove activity no longer used&lt;br /&gt;
0284130 remove out activity no longer used&lt;br /&gt;
e487f34 update strings&lt;br /&gt;
8fd0bd0 update tor-android to 0.3.19b (updated geoip databases)&lt;br /&gt;
ad51bed update transifex configuration&lt;br /&gt;
a08c707 update app store descriptions&lt;br /&gt;
2ced17a update build SDK targets to 26&lt;br /&gt;
5c22de2 manifest updates: remove superuser, enable chromebooks&lt;br /&gt;
b4aa9d8 more improvements for bridge wizard&lt;br /&gt;
df37b8c add bridge wizard testing code&lt;br /&gt;
14ce4f6 big update for new onboarding, bridge wizard&lt;br /&gt;
2ceacf6 move bridges to raw resources&lt;br /&gt;
938a740 improve vpn app enable view on main activity&lt;br /&gt;
ba358a4 add new orfox and settings icon&lt;br /&gt;
5bd5a56 VPN should be off by default&lt;br /&gt;
e464044 connection might be null&lt;br /&gt;
51216a4 Add new preference: pref_open_proxy_on_all_interfaces&lt;br /&gt;
21b4521 Update version strings in help-&amp;gt;about&lt;br /&gt;
5500b50 update spuport library version&lt;br /&gt;
546310a improve notifications, add refresh/newnym button&lt;br /&gt;
877406f tweak layout&lt;br /&gt;
b68132b fix title for tor app section&lt;br /&gt;
7210223 fix handling of intents&lt;br /&gt;
47e10e7 fix issues with bridge selection UI&lt;br /&gt;
e6bd23a more UI updates and small improvements&lt;br /&gt;
d9bd32a more UI updates&lt;br /&gt;
7303a33 work on the new UI update&lt;br /&gt;
6a19bf6 update UI tweaks for next release&lt;br /&gt;
3741434 don’t show app selection each time you turn VPN on/off&lt;br /&gt;
4df2fcf move “other” installer back to tor resource installer&lt;br /&gt;
f3f9162 don’t delete installed binaries&lt;br /&gt;
6493d8d Merge pull request #104 from igortoliveira/remove-java-file&lt;br /&gt;
fc4d6aa improve app loading time for VPN app dialog&lt;br /&gt;
fbeff25 Remove leftover Java file&lt;br /&gt;
544ea7b update build to use tor version constant from tor-android-binary&lt;br /&gt;
977167b ZMerge branch ‘master’ of github.com:n8fr8/orbot&lt;br /&gt;
b07d4fe removed unused submodules, moved to gradle tor-android&lt;br /&gt;
d392ecd remove unneeded external dirs for making tor&lt;br /&gt;
3d729fc switch to using tor-android binary in TorService&lt;br /&gt;
6f364de use the new tor-android gradle dependency &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n8fr8/tor-android&#34;&gt;https://github.com/n8fr8/tor-android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
c7f834b moving binary files, use tor-android gradle&lt;br /&gt;
3b5e27e removing external depends, moving to tor-android gradle&lt;br /&gt;
898f64a Merge pull request #99 from goapunk/update-BUILD-instructions&lt;br /&gt;
e14d647 update BUILD&lt;br /&gt;
fce5bde add autopoint to dependencies&lt;br /&gt;
72c7e04 Merge pull request #97 from SpotComms/padding&lt;br /&gt;
8cf412a Merge pull request #98 from goapunk/add-lzma-zstd-as-dependency&lt;br /&gt;
c1dfc29 Update BUILD instructions&lt;br /&gt;
9ca36e1 Add lzma and zstd&lt;br /&gt;
6e4b700 Expose *ConnectionPadding&lt;br /&gt;
71e3464 Merge pull request #94 from Unpublished/fix88&lt;br /&gt;
cbffc1d remove some transproxy left overs&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Signing Server</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/12/18/building-a-signing-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 05:43:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/12/18/building-a-signing-server/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Android APK signing model sets the expectation that the signing key will be the same for the entire lifetime of the app. That can be seen in the recommended lifetype of an Android signing key: &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/publish/app-signing.html#considerations&#34;&gt;20+ years&lt;/a&gt;. On top of that, it is difficult to &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2015/12/29/how-to-migrate-your-android-apps-signing-key/&#34;&gt;migrate an app to a new key&lt;/a&gt;. Since the signing key is an essential part to preventing APKs from impersonating another, Android signing keys must be kept safe for the entire life of the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The F-Droid repo signing keys follow a very similar model: the signing key is the essential way to safely identify an F-Droid repo. So the same considerations apply to F-Droid repo signing keys as to APK signing keys. This also provides some really useful benefits. Since the integrity of the repo index file and the APKs are guaranteed by the repo signature, the files can be delivered via whatever method is most convenient, and their integrity will be automatically verified by the F-Droid client app, the &lt;em&gt;f-droid.org&lt;/em&gt; deploy process, and Repomaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means the security burden is shifted from the online, public webserver to a private signing machine. Just keeping that machine out of the public eye goes a long way towards improving security. There are a number of additional measures that can be taken to further improve the security of the signing process. Here are some approaches, starting with the easiest and least security, and going on to more secure setups that require more work to setup and run. Signing is not an resource intensive process, so any machine will work, even a 10 year old, basic laptop. We recommend using a minimal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; install, and rebuilding the machine from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;automated-signing-server-with-with-hsm&#34;&gt;Automated Signing Server with with HSM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a fully automated signing setup, the machine running the signing needs to be online and running. Ideally this machine would have no remote access, at the very least remote access should be very carefully controlled and monitored. A laptop makes it easy to work with even when remote access is disabled, since it provides a built-in keyboard and monitor. If remote access is required, then any basic PC will work fine. Using a Hardware Security Module (HSM) to store the keys prevents them from being stolen if the server is broken into. An attacker could only run the signing process on that server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, this machine would only be accessible via Tor. That hides the physical location of the server, and hides the traffic from network. This makes it much harder attackers to find the actual machine to attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the HSM, we recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nitrokey.com/&#34;&gt;Nitrokey&lt;/a&gt; hardware, since they are free software/hardware, and provide a wide range of options. Use a separate machine to put the signing keys on HSM. A good HSM will keep an audit trail of how many signatures have been made, so that information could be used to create an automatic auditing process to raise alarms if too many signatures have been made. That could mean that this server was breached and used to sign unauthorized packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other possibility it to use a setup like &lt;a href=&#34;https://pagure.io/sigul&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;‘s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devops-blog.net/koji/gpg-signing-rpms-with-sigul-signing-server-koji-integration&#34;&gt;Sigul&lt;/a&gt; that involves three machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-laptop-dedicated-to-signing&#34;&gt;Basic laptop dedicated to signing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with a laptop that can be wiped clean and rebuilt from scratch. What is most important is that only the essential software is installed on it, and nothing else. Do not include any browser at all, for example, since that is the most common vector of attack. No remote access setup (e.g. SSH or VNC) should be installed or configured. To sign apps and repos, someone would take out this laptop, connect it to the network, and run the signing process. The signed results can then be published via the network connection. When the signing is complete, the machine can be turned off and disconnected and kept in a safe place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be made quite automatic with some custom scripts. The person running the process would only need to take out the machine, connect it, turn it on, wait until the process completes, then put it all away again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fully-offline-signing-laptop-with-usb-thumb-drives&#34;&gt;Fully offline signing laptop with USB thumb drives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt;: apt-offline has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/871656&#34;&gt;security bug&lt;/a&gt; so it was removed from Debian/buster. It is no longer recommended! Instead, use the Debian &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/doc/manuals/apt-offline&#34;&gt;apt offline&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; setup._&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is based on the same basic, stripped down laptop as the previous example. But this time, the networking should be entirely disabled before the install process. For example, it is easy in many laptops to physically remove the WiFi card. Therefore, it makes sense to use a laptop that does not include an ethernet jack, which are usually not possible to remove. Otherwise, blacklisting all kernel modules related to neworking can suffice. Since this machine is fully offline, the extra work of using an HSM is not as important, but it can’t hurt to include it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the full &amp;ldquo;CD&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;DVD&amp;rdquo; image of Debian to run the install. Be sure to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/CD/verify&#34;&gt;verify&lt;/a&gt; the GPG signatures and the SHA-256 hashes. One essential utility is &lt;em&gt;apt-offline&lt;/em&gt;, which automates the process of downloading Debian packages, verifying their signatures, and copying them over to an offline machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be extra careful, all of the software used should be verified. Chromebooks are nice, cheap laptops that run Linux natively. They also use Coreboot for the BIOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;buy-a-computer-off-the-shelf-with-cash-avoid-having-it-shipped-especially-across-borders&#34;&gt;
  Buy a computer off the shelf with cash, avoid having it shipped, especially across borders
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;buy-a-debian-supported-chromebook-with-removeable-wifi-hardware-and-needs-no-binary-blobs&#34;&gt;
  Buy a Debian-supported &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/chromium-os/developer-information-for-chrome-os-devices/acer-c720-chromebook&#34;&gt;Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; with removeable WiFi hardware, and needs no binary blobs
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;install-a-reproducibly-built-coreboot-binary&#34;&gt;
  Install a reproducibly built coreboot binary
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;install-from-a-reproducibly-built-debian-image-wiping-out-chrome-os-entirely&#34;&gt;
  Install from a reproducibly built Debian image, wiping out Chrome OS entirely
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-physical-environment&#34;&gt;The Physical Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing to consider is the physical location where signatures happen, and where essential equipment is stored. The signing environment must be physically secure. Otherwise, there is no way to prevent laptops or HSMs from being lost or used to sign inappropriate content. For the offline machines, keeping them in a locked room is a good start. For an online machine, forcing all network traffic and remote access over Tor hides the physical location of the machine from network observers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For high risk signing keys, using multiple layers of defense is important:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restricted physical access to HSMs or smart cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onsite security guards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visitor logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tools-resistant server safe for online code-signing servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The signing server should be physically separate from the rest of the infrastructure. And the logs, machine, and network should be periodically audited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;difficult-decisions&#34;&gt;Difficult decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally all of these practices would be put into place, but each of these security measures comes at a cost of difficulty, expense, and complexity. They can also delay the process of getting regular updates out. So there are risks of implementing too strict security policies, much like the risks of not implementing enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No more “Root” features in Orbot… use Orfox &amp; VPN instead!</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/10/27/no-more-root-features-in-orbot-use-orfox-vpn-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 13:02:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/10/27/no-more-root-features-in-orbot-use-orfox-vpn-instead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I first announced the available of Orbot: Tor for Android about &lt;a href=&#34;https://nathan.freitas.net/2009/10/22/orbot-proxy/&#34;&gt;8 years ago&lt;/a&gt; (wow!), myself and others have been working on various methods in which to make the capabilities of Tor available through the operating system. This post is to announce that as of the next, imminent release, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n8fr8/orbot/releases/tag/15.5.0-RC-1-multi-SDK16&#34;&gt;Orbot v15.5,&lt;/a&gt; we will no longer be supporting the Root-required “Transproxy” method. This is due to many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it turns out that allowing applications to get “root” access on your device seems like a good idea, it can also be seen as huge security hole. I am on the fence myself, but considering that the ability to access root features hasn’t been standardized as part of Android, which 8 years ago I hoped it would, it means there are a whole variety of ways that this capability is managed and safeguarded (or not, in most cases). At this point in time, given the sophistication we are seeing mobile malware and rootkits, it seems like a capability that we did not want to focus time and energy on promoting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, for those who do want to use root features, and know what they are doing, there are a bunch of other apps that do that job better than Orbot did. I admit, we let our code in that area degrade a bit, as the dev team themselves moved away from phones with root features. So, instead, if you really want to do cool things with iptables rules, you can use AFWall+, available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/dev.ukanth.ufirewall/&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dev.ukanth.ufirewall&#34;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone &#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ukanth/afwall/0502e6f17ceda08069720ff2f260902690e65e9b/screenshots/Main_2.0.png&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make AFWall+ work with Orbot, you can follow Mike Perry’s excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.torproject.org/mission-impossible-hardening-android-security-and-privacy&#34;&gt;“Mission Impossible Android”&lt;/a&gt; guide in which he provides “DroidWall Scripts” necessary to enable automatic Tor routing on boot. You can also check out the sadly no longer maintained, but useful, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orwall.org/&#34;&gt;Orwall app&lt;/a&gt; which was meant to take on all the root features of Orbot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, we really, really think it is a bad idea to just send all of the traffic of your device through the Tor network. While it sounds like a great idea in theory, much like many “magical” Tor router kickstarter projects, it turns out that unless you can be assured an app is using TLS properly, then there is a chance that bad things could happen to your traffic as it exits the Tor network. Rather than promote some kind of auto-magical “enable Tor for my whole device”, we want to focus on ways to enable specific apps to go through Tor, in a way we can ensure is as safe as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, we now have an excellent browser app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orfox&#34;&gt;Orfox&lt;/a&gt;, that is based on Tor Browser, and works perfectly with Orbot. If you just want to access the web and onion services, like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.nytimes.com/https-open-nytimes-com-the-new-york-times-as-a-tor-onion-service-e0d0b67b7482&#34;&gt;new New York Times onion&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes3xbfgragh.onion/&#34;&gt;https://www.nytimes3xbfgragh.onion/&lt;/a&gt;, then just use &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orfox&#34;&gt;Orfox&lt;/a&gt;. There is no need for any fancy rooting or transproxying. There are also many others that supporting routing through Orbot directly, such as Conversations.im, Facebook for Android, DuckDuckGo, F-Droid, OpenArchive and many more to come! If you are interested in enabling your app to work with Orbot, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/netcipher&#34;&gt;NetCipher SDK&lt;/a&gt;, which makes it easy to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, Orbot has for some time supported use of Android’s VPN features as a way to tunnel traffic through Tor. You just open the left-side menu, and tap “Apps VPN Mode” or tap on “Apps…” on the main screen. Choose the apps you want to run through Tor, press the back button, and then the VPN will start up, rerouting outbound traffic back through the local Tor port. This method is 100% support by Android, and requires no vulnerabilities or exploits of your device to gain root access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-13829&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn3-169x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn3-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn3-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn3-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn3.png 1080w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-13830&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn2-169x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn2-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn2-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn2-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn2.png 1080w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-13831&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn1-169x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn1-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn1-768x1365.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn1-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/orbotvpn1.png 1080w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Orbot Apps VPN view, home screen with Apps… button, and VPN sidebar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that even with all of these justifications, some users will be disappointed with the fact we have removed root features from Orbot. Perhaps that will motivate some to reignite development of Orwall, or maybe help us make the VPN features in Orbot work even better. Another route is to support the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.torproject.org/mission-impossible-hardening-android-security-and-privacy&#34;&gt;Tor’s Android phone prototype&lt;/a&gt; or perhaps integrate Tor “root” features directly into a community Android OS project like Copperhead or Legacy. We would be happy to see all of these happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, though, removing root means we can focus on making Orbot more streamlined, more stable, and more compatible with Android, for our 2 million+ active users, who are mostly focused on finding an easy solution for unblocking sites and apps, and allowing them to communicate and browse freely without fear of reprisal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking usage without tracking people</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/06/08/tracking-usage-without-tracking-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 10:58:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/06/08/tracking-usage-without-tracking-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that has become very clear over the past years is that there is a lot of value in data about people. Of course, the most well known examples these days are advertising and spy agencies, but tracking data is useful for many more things. For example, when trying to build software that is intuitive and easy to use, having real data about how people are using the software can make a massive difference when developers and designers are working on improving their software. Even in the case of advertisers, they mostly do not care exactly who you are, they want to know what you are interested in so that they can more effectively promote things to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning Guardian Project has focused on privacy, and worked to practice what we preach in our own software. For example, we have entirely disabled Apache web logs on our website for the past couple of years, so that we would not even have access to that rich data. We felt that we could not even store that data without fear of violating people’s privacy, let alone working with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have changed in the past few years, and there are now a number of well tested techniques for tracking how people are using software without actually tracking who they are. It is now possible to keep some usage data while feeling safe that no one who might get that data could use it to identify individuals. One good example of this is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor Project’s tracking data&lt;/a&gt;. They provide a wide variety of tracking data to follow how Tor is being used, and how well the Tor network is operating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we believe that it is now possible to responsibly track usage without violating anyone’s privacy. One piece of work along these lines is the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cleaninsights/cleaninsights-android-sdk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clean Insights Android SDK&lt;/a&gt;. Nathan is leading the development of that effort. And this blog post announces another new development that we are starting: tracking usage data from F-Droid app repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry-300x133.png&#34; alt=&#34;tracking by country&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;133&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-13632&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry-300x133.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry.png 747w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, the Apache web logs for this site will be configured to store, but only information that is not fine-grained enough to identify people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only the date is stored, not the time or time zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referer, IP Addresses, User Agent are never stored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;country is stored by looking up the IP Address in the &lt;em&gt;geoip&lt;/em&gt; database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, a log entries look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;189.4.73.81 testy.at.or.at - [08/Jun/2017:13:55:46 +0200] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;-&#34; &#34;F-Droid&#34;
119.29.81.134 199.119.112.126 - [08/Jun/2017:14:46:48 -0400] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;http://testy.at.or.at/fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar&#34; &#34;Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 9.0; Windows NT 6.1)&#34;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stripped version looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;0.0.0.0 - - [08/Jun/2017:00:00:00 +0000] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;-&#34; &#34;-&#34; AT
0.0.0.0 - - [08/Jun/2017:00:00:00 +0000] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;-&#34; &#34;-&#34; ZH
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the raw data is processed by the webserver, the extra information will be discarded and never written to disk. Only the sanitized usage tracking information is ever stored. This is based on Tor Project’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/webstats.git/tree/src/sanitize.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;web tracking&lt;/a&gt;. It is possible to do this with &lt;em&gt;Apache&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;lighttpd&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt;, and probably other webservers. For &lt;em&gt;Apache&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/maxmind/geoip-api-mod_geoip2/blob/master/INSTALL.md#configuration&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;mod_geoip&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; needs to be installed, then only a single line is needed to configure this private logging mode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;LogFormat &#34;0.0.0.0 - %u %{[%d/%b/%Y:00:00:00 %z]}t \&#34;%r\&#34; %&gt;s %b \&#34;%{Referer}i\&#34; \&#34;-\&#34; %{GEOIP_COUNTRY_CODE}e&#34; privacy+geo
CustomLog ${APACHE_LOG_DIR}/access.log privacy+geo
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we hope that we can work towards providing value from tracking data, without violating anyone’s privacy. Indeed, we are still prioritizing privacy over any value derived from tracking data. So anyone else who also wants to go follow this route needs to be fully aware that any tracking must be very carefully done, since it can easily result in inadvertent leaks. Do not take this as a stamp of approval on any tracking activity!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOWTO: get all your Debian packages via Tor Onion Services</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/07/31/howto-get-all-your-debian-packages-via-tor-onion-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 17:28:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/07/31/howto-get-all-your-debian-packages-via-tor-onion-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png&#34; alt=&#34;leakage&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-12699&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-100x66.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-150x99.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-200x132.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png 410w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Following up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some privacy leaks that we looked into a while back&lt;/a&gt;, there are now official Debian &lt;a href=&#34;https://onion.debian.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt; for getting software packages and security updates, thanks to the Debian Sys Admin team. This is important for high risk use cases like TAILS covers, but also it is useful to make it more difficult to do some kinds of targeted attacks against high-security servers. The default Debian and Ubuntu package servers use plain HTTP with unencrypted connections. That means anyone with access to the network streams could both monitor and fingerprint traffic. When an request for a security update is spotted, an attacker knows that machine is vulnerable to an exploit, and could reliably exploit it before the security update is applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.riseup.net/code/issues/8143&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HTTPS to get security updates&lt;/a&gt; improves this situation a lot, but by measuring the size of data transfers, it is still possible to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/G.Danezis/papers/TLSanon.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;track which files are being downloaded&lt;/a&gt;. A Tor Onion Service provides end-to-end encryption like the HTTPS connection. It also mixes up the traffic with lots of other traffic, so its not easy to see what traffic goes together. That makes it a lot harder for a network observer to tell when a security update is being downloaded. Additionally, using a Tor Onion Service forces the traffic over Tor, so that the Debian mirror server cannot see which server is requesting the updates. That helps prevent targeted attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other benefits as well, besides just for the person running the high security server in this example, especially if all of the traffic is coming over Tor. When updates are delivered over Tor, then that means the Debian mirror operators have less to worry about because they are handling less metadata that might have privacy concerns. It means that when law enforcement requests logs from the mirror operators, the mirror operators can more easily hand over anything they have since the mirror operator knows that there is not private information in the logs. Reducing the legal risks and privacy concerns makes it easier to run mirrors, and that helps internet services work better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One disadvantage of this approach as it now stands is that your server will get updates from the same mirror every time. There is only a single Tor Onion Service for the main archive. An alternate approach using the combination of Tor and &lt;a href=&#34;http://httpredir.debian.org/&#34;&gt;http://httpredir.debian.org/&lt;/a&gt; as the package source means that your server will get updates from a different mirror each time Tor changes its exit node (I believe that’s every 10 minutes or so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you set up your Debian machine to get updates over Tor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11-300x173.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;debian and tor&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;173&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-13395&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11-300x173.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11-768x444.jpg 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11.jpg 800w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Right now, the best way to set up a Debian machine to force traffic over Tor is to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TransparentProxy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;transparent proxying&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;em&gt;iptables&lt;/em&gt; rules. If you have that setup, then you can add the onion addresses as Debian apt sources as if they are any other HTTP Debian mirror. Another option is to install &lt;em&gt;apt-transport-tor&lt;/em&gt; like TAILS does, then you can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.skolelinux.org/pere/blog/Always_download_Debian_packages_using_Tor___the_simple_recipe.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;special syntax to add the Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt;. And another way is to install an HTTP proxy like &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; and enable apt HTTP proxy support as &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I described before&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;apt-transport-tor&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; approaches both have the downside of having to trust an added piece of software, whereas the transparent proxy technique uses what is already present in the Linux kernel. I’ve been using the &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; method since that is what I got working in 2014 and it has been working reliably on multiple servers since then. Also, I need &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; installed for another application anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to set up the apt sources to get packages and updates via Tor Onion Services without delaying security updates. First, remove &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/*.list&lt;/em&gt; to start with a clean slate. Next add &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/00.vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion.list&lt;/em&gt; to get the main Debian repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie main
deb-src http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie main

# aka volatile
deb http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie-updates main
deb-src http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie-updates main

deb http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian jessie-backports main
deb-src http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie-backports main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next add the new Tor Onion Service for the security update repository at &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/00.sgvtcaew4bxjd7ln.onion.list&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://sgvtcaew4bxjd7ln.onion/ jessie/updates main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then last, include the normal HTTP security.debian.org archive to ensure that your server gets the latest security updates, even if the &lt;a href=&#34;https://onion.debian.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Onion Service mirror&lt;/a&gt; is behind or there is some other issue related to Tor. This goes in &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/99.security.debian.org.list&lt;/em&gt; to ensure that it is always the last repository that is tried, and apt loads files from /etc/apt/source.list.d/ in alphabetical order, so it’ll always try to get the security updates from the Onion Service before falling back to the HTTP source as a last resort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://security.debian.org/ jessie/updates main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also run an unofficial mirror of the security updates on &lt;a href=&#34;http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian&#34;&gt;http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian&lt;/a&gt; if you want to add another backup, i.e. &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/00.dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion.list&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian-security/ jessie/updates main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the most private app store</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/06/02/building-the-most-private-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:08:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/06/02/building-the-most-private-app-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;App stores can work well without any tracking at all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/whichdoor.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/whichdoor-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;whichdoor&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-13337&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attackers are increasingly seeing app stores as a prime &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2015/02/24/phishing-for-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attack&lt;/a&gt; vector, whether it is aimed at the masses like &lt;a href=&#34;http://researchcenter.paloaltonetworks.com/2015/09/more-details-on-the-xcodeghost-malware-and-affected-ios-apps/&#34;&gt;XCodeGhost&lt;/a&gt; or very targeted like in FBI vs Apple. When we install software from an app store, we are placing a lot of trust in a lot of different parties involved in getting the source code from the original developer delivered to our device in a useful form. Most people are entirely unaware of how much trust they are putting into this system, which they are entrusting with their personal data. Even for people who do understand the technical details involved, figuring out whether the people and the system itself is trustworthy is difficult to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are building an app store that requires the bare minimum of trust: only the software developers themselves and the code they produce. We consider the app store operators and servers a threat. Building an ecosystem that enables automated, effective auditing lets the computers verify to make trust decisions easier. Effective external auditing requires an ecosystem that cannot deliver targeted content to just the auditing system, while feeding users something else (aka “binary transparency”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most app stores track as much as possible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of apps stores track their users actions in detail. Some is necessary when using the business model of the app store operator taking a percentage of sales, but none of the tracking is inherent to running an app store. For example, payment verification can be handled in the app itself like shareware. A software delivery system that tracks its users makes it simple to hide malware delivery since it can target any auditing system. Most app stores know a lot about their users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;account name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;payment methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;everything you search for in the app store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;everything you look at in the app store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;everything you download, install, uninstall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;which apps you actually run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;where you are, based on IP, declared preference, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your preferred language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps stores need to know very little in order to function: how to give you the files you request. That means indexes, descriptions, icons, apps, and install/delete requests (for “push” install/delete). Given that information, the client can do everything needed to provide a full app store user experience. For this work, we chose to build upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;, a community-run Android app store that distributes verified Free Software. The community has had an interest in privacy all along, and has always worked to avoid tracking. The security architecture is based on models proven by &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/SecureApt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/theupdateframework/tuf/blob/develop/docs/tuf-spec.txt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Update Framework&lt;/a&gt; , and others:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTPS connections by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pinned TLS certificate built into the client app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updates verified based on the signature on the app itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file integrity protected by signed metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;signed metadata includes hashes of the app and its signing key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;signed metadata generated on a separate machine, which can be fully offline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;public key for verifying metadata signatures built into F-Droid client app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;signed metadata includes timestamp and expiry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the current setup is already a solid platform, we are implementing a number of improvements. The signed metadata will include list of official mirrors, then the client chooses mirrors based on availability and freshness based on local criteria like whether Tor is in use, closest on the internet, etc. We are also moving the standard HTTP “etag” cache check from the server to the client so it cannot be abused to track users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to defend against an attacker that holds the signing keys for the app repository, there must be a trustworthy source of information to compare against. Reproducible builds means that anyone with the same source code will produce the exact same binary. When paired with an auditing system, it is easy to catch malware inserted in the build process, rather than the source code, like XCodeGhost. Reproducible builds also makes it possible to have all builds of a release binary have the exact same hash. Then any app repository can build apps only from source code, and have a source of verification data from any other app repository building the same app. Building software from source has become cheap enough that many companies like gitlab.com and Travis CI are offering free, automated build services in the cloud. Since the whole F-Droid toolset is free software and designed to be easy to setup, the barriers to setting up automatic auditing are quite low. People in separate areas of the world with different risk profiles can run verification servers to provide more trustworthy information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key aspect of the F-Droid project is to provide the complete toolset needed to run an app store. This enables a more decentralized ecosystem. Therefore, one key goal is to lower the risks of running the services, so that more people can run their own app stores. If the app store does not track its users, then that removes the hassle of protecting personal data from any attacker. These services can be run without fear of responding to secret orders for personal information. It also means that the server setup is a lot simpler because it does not need dynamic content. The app store serve only needs to serve files (e.g. indexes, apps, etc.). The app repository is generated on a secure machine, or even a fully offline machine, and posted to the server. The main server is purely a mirror of the offline machine where the signed repository is generated. Mirrors just shuffle bits from place to place, they are no longer an attack vector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting all these pieces together provides a system where users need only audit the source code in order to verify a trustworthy app delivery. The file pipeline provides redundantly secure data transmission, the apps can be reproducibly from source code, the app repositories can be automatically audited. Of course, this system relies not only on the power of cryptography, but also the power of transparency. Debian provides a great example of the power of transparency: Debian gives a thousand volunteers root access to every Debian install (by virtue of their ability to upload signed packages that get installed as root). Yet this system has been proven over the past 20+ years to provide solid security. Ultimately we hope that this will de-emphasize the signing key as the sole protection against abuse. If malware has a decent change of being spotted, it makes it much less likely to be used since malware authors either rigorously defend their exploits, or use well known exploits that are not difficult to automatically detect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One attack vector that is not well covered is malware that installable by everyone, that then uses data on the local device to target specific users. That would be a way to target individuals using an app store that does not track its users. We are starting to implement automated dynamic analysis of every app using tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.mwrinfosecurity.com/tools/drozer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Drozer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also working towards making as many apps as possible build reproducibly. Some of our quick checks show that a large number of the apps in f-droid.org already will build reproducibly, given the right build environment. We are working on making the process of setting up that build environment as automated as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The F-Droid “verification server” has been prototyped, and it will be further developed with the aim of making it dead simple to run in common cloud services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have the infrastructure in place to do verified double-signing, where the developer first signs the release bulid, then once f-droid.org reproduces that build, it adds its signature. Then Android would enforce that both signatures need to be present in order for it to be a valid update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the full localization support is built out, the language that a user is using will not be reported to the server. While speaking Spanish in Spain does not provide much information, speaking Quechua in Uzbekistan can narrow it down to a single user. Instead of dividing the index metadata by language, it will instead be grouped by app. We will then group apps so that it is difficult to tell which app in the group is the one people are interested in. For example, if one very popular app is only grouped with apps that are rarely downloaded, then it is an easy assumption that someone getting info about that block of apps is most likely looking for that popular app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orfox: Aspiring to bring Tor Browser to Android</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2015/06/30/orfox-aspiring-to-bring-tor-browser-to-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 15:32:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2015/06/30/orfox-aspiring-to-bring-tor-browser-to-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 24 September, 2015: Orfox BETA is now on Google Play: &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.orfox&#34;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.orfox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2014 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.mayfirst.org/pipermail/guardian-dev/2014-August/003717.html&#34;&gt;https://lists.mayfirst.org/pipermail/guardian-dev/2014-August/003717.html&lt;/a&gt;{.external}), we announced that the results of work by Amogh Pradeep (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/amoghbl1&#34;&gt;https://github.com/amoghbl1&lt;/a&gt;{.external}), our 2014 Google Summer of Code student, has proven we could build Firefox for Android with some of the settings and configurations from the Tor Browser desktop software. We called this app Orfox, in homage to Orbot and our current Orweb browser. This was a good first step, but we were doing the build on Mozilla’s Firefox code repository, and then retrofitting pieces from Tor Browser’s code, which wasn’t the right way to do things, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer (2015!), with fantastic continued effort by Amogh, we have switched to building the Orfox mobile app directly from the Tor Browser code repository, successfully working through any mobile OS incompatibilities in the security hardening patches added by the Tor Browser team. We also had the additional task of reviewing the Android application code in Firefox, that is not part of Tor Browser, in order to modify and patch it to work inline with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser/design/&#34;&gt;Tor Browser requirements and design document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, we have a stable alpha release ready for testing, and are rapidly moving towards a public beta in a few weeks. Our plan is to actively encourage users to move from Orweb to Orfox, and stop active development of Orweb, even removing to from the Google Play Store. If users really want to continue using a WebView-based solution and do not need all of the capabilities that Orfox/Tor Browser provides, they can use Lightning Browser (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/anthonycr/Lightning-Browser&#34;&gt;https://github.com/anthonycr/Lightning-Browser&lt;/a&gt;{.external}), a lightweight, open-source app that offers automatic Orbot (SOCKS) proxying on start-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you will find screenshots and our current set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/orfox-private-browser/wiki/Orfox_vs_Tor_Browser_FAQ&#34;&gt;Orfox Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/orfox-private-browser/wiki&#34;&gt;project wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access the current Orfox release by installing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/&#34;&gt;F-Droid app&lt;/a&gt; and subscribing to our F-Droid Alpha Channel at by clicking on the following link on your phone: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/debug/info.guardianproject.orfox/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/debug/info.guardianproject.orfox/fdroid/repo&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;gallery-11&#39; class=&#39;gallery galleryid-12999 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-medium&#39;&gt;
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133152.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133152-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-11-13003&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133152-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133152-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133152.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-11-13003&#39;&gt;
      Recognized as Tor Browser
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133103.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133103-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-11-13005&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133103-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133103-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133103.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-11-13005&#39;&gt;
      A match made by onions!
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133624.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133624-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-11-13000&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133624-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133624-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133624.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-11-13000&#39;&gt;
      Bookmark support!
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133414.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133414-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-11-13001&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133414-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133414-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133414.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-11-13001&#39;&gt;
      Easy access to onion sites!
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133223.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133223-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-11-13002&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133223-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133223-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133223.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-11-13002&#39;&gt;
      Tabs!
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133130.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;169&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133130-169x300.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-medium size-medium&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-11-13004&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133130-169x300.png 169w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133130-576x1024.png 576w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/device-2015-06-30-133130.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-11-13004&#39;&gt;
      Tor-relevant default sites
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can I find all the relevant Orfox project pieces?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Orfox project tracker roadmap is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/orfox-private-browser/roadmap&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/orfox-private-browser/roadmap&lt;/a&gt;{.external}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Orfox branch of the Tor Browser repository is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/tor-browser&#34;&gt;https://github.com/guardianproject/tor-browser&lt;/a&gt;{.external}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Orfox build project is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/orfoxfennec&#34;&gt;https://github.com/guardianproject/orfoxfennec&lt;/a&gt;{.external}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The primary Tor Browser repository is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/tor-browser.git/&#34;&gt;https://gitweb.torproject.org/tor-browser.git/&lt;/a&gt;{.external}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated debug builds of Orfox alpha are available via F-Droid here (install F-Droid on your phone, then copy/paste or open the link to add the repo): &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/debug/info.guardianproject.orfox/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/debug/info.guardianproject.orfox/fdroid/repo&lt;/a&gt;{.external}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is Orfox different than Tor Browser for desktop?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orfox is built from the same source code as Tor Browser (which is built upon Firefox), but with a few minor modifications to the privacy enhancing features to make them compatible with Firefox for Android and the Android operating system. In as many ways as possible, we will adhere to the design goals of Tor Browser (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser/design/&#34;&gt;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser/design/&lt;/a&gt;{.external}), by supporting as much of their actual code as possible, and extending their work into the additional AF-Droid appndroid components of Firefox for Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Orfox code repository is at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/tor-browser&#34;&gt;https://github.com/guardianproject/tor-browser&lt;/a&gt;{.external} and the Tor Browser repository is here:&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/tor-browser.git/&#34;&gt;https://gitweb.torproject.org/tor-browser.git/&lt;/a&gt;{.external}. The Orfox repository is a fork of the Tor Browser repository with the necessary modification and Android-specific code as patches on top of the Tor Browser work. We will keep our repository in sync with updates and release of Tor Browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox is built from the Tor Browser repo based on ESR38 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5146&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5146&lt;/a&gt;{.external}&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/news/221&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/news/221&lt;/a&gt;{.external}) and has only two modified patches that were not relevant or necessary for Android&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox does not currently include the mobile versions of HTTPS Everywhere, No Script and the Tor Browser Button, but these we will be added shortly, now that we have discovered how to properly support automatic installation of extensions on Android (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5360&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5360&lt;/a&gt;{.external})&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox includes a “Request Mobile Site” option that allows you to change the user-agent from the standard Tor Browser agent to a modified Android specific one: “Mozilla/5.0 (Android; Mobile; rv:31.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/31.0”. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5404&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5404&lt;/a&gt;{.external}). This is useful for being able to see the mobile version of a website, but does reduce the amount your browser blends in with other browsers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox currently allows for users to bookmark sites, and may have additional data written to disk beyond what the core gecko browser component does. We are still auditing all disk write code, and determining how to appropriately disable or harden it. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5437&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5437&lt;/a&gt;{.external})&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox cannot yet be built deterministically, but based on work with the FDroid project, we are aiming for this to be possible in the next year (&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/deterministic-builds-part-one-cyberwar-and-global-compromise&#34;&gt;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/deterministic-builds-part-one-cyberwar-and-global-compromise&lt;/a&gt;{.external} &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/wiki/page/Deterministic,_Reproducible_Builds&#34;&gt;https://f-droid.org/wiki/page/Deterministic,_Reproducible_Builds&lt;/a&gt;{.external})&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is Orfox different than Firefox for Android?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the core Tor Browser components, Orfox also must ensure all Android-specific code is properly routed through the Tor proxy, and otherwise hardened to protect against data and privacy leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox adds patches at the Android Java code layer to enable proxying of all Java network HTTP communications through the local Orbot HTTP proxy (HTTP localhost:8118 for now, but moving to SOCKS). (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5235&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5235&lt;/a&gt;{.external} &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5317&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5317&lt;/a&gt;{.external})&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox removes the Android permissions for Contacts, Camera, Microphone, Location and NFC (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/3822&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/3822&lt;/a&gt;{.external}) since the capability of using these features are not in line with the spirit of Tor Browser&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orfox removes features like WebRTC and support for interaction with Chromecasts or Roku devices, since this type of communication is not compatibility with proxying communication through a TCP-based network like Tor (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5358&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5358&lt;/a&gt;{.external} &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5357&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/5357&lt;/a&gt;{.external})&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is Orfox different than Orweb?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orweb is our current default browser for Orbot/Tor mobile users (&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orweb&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orweb&lt;/a&gt;{.external}) that has been downloaded over 2 million times. It is VERY VERY SIMPLE, as it only has one tab, no bookmark capability, and an extremely minimal user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orweb is built upon the bundled WebView (Webkit) browser component inside of the Android operating system. This has proven to be problematic because we cannot control the version of that component, and cannot upgrade it directly when bugs are found. In addition, Google has made it very difficult to effectively control the network proxy settings of all aspects of this component, making it difficult to guarantee that traffic will not leak on all devices and OS versions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orweb also only provides a very limited amount of capability of Tor Browser, primarily related to reducing browser fingerprinting, minimizing disk writes, and cookie and history management. It trys to mimic some of the settings of Tor Browser, but doesn’t actually use any of the actual code written for Tor Browser security hardening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orweb does have an advantage which is that it less than 2MB while Orfox is in the 25-30MB range. This is primarily because Orweb relies on many components built into Android, so it does not need to bundle them. Orfox contains the full stack of code necessary for a complete browser, and thus is more secure and dependable, but also larger. The Mozilla Mobile team is working on reducing the size of their binaries, and the Orfox team is focused on this, as well, since we are disabling some of the components that have contributed the browser bloat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing metadata leakage from software updates</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 12:48:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: now you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2016/07/31/howto-get-all-your-debian-packages-via-tor-onion-services/&#34;&gt;do this with Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png&#34; alt=&#34;leakage&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-12699&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-100x66.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-150x99.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-200x132.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png 410w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Many software update systems use code signing to ensure that only the correct software is downloaded and installed, and to prevent the code from being altered. This is an effective way to prevent the code from being modified, and because of that, software update systems often use plain, unencrypted HTTP connections for downloading code updates. That means that the metadata of what packages a machine has installed is available in plain text for any network observer, from someone sitting on the same public WiFi as you, to state actors with full network observation capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that potentially private information is leaking. That private information could be which packages you have installed and which versions. That information can help an attacker figure out the best way to break into the target machine. Also, a unique fingerprint can be generated based on which packages a machine has installed, and that could help de-anonymize traffic that goes over Tor or other anonymity tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who use &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; in Debian, Ubuntu or any related GNU/Linux distro, there is a lot of metadata leaked to the internet when &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; contacts Debian repositories using a standard configuration. Mostly, that is because by default, the connections are unencrypted (http, ftp, rsync). The integrity of the package itself is not reason enough to use HTTPS since the GPG signing is much more reliable for that task. Here is how I break it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package authenticity&lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;software can be modified while being downloaded&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repo availability&lt;br /&gt;
( &lt;em&gt;whole sites or specific URL paths can be selectively blocked by governments and companies&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package availability&lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;software security updates can be individually blocked&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who’s downloading what package (&lt;em&gt;currently visible to anyone who can see the&lt;br /&gt;
network traffic, including open wifi, etc.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current apt model covers #1 well, but only covers #2 and #3 with a two week window (the expiration date on the repo metadata). And it does not cover #4 at all. Using HTTPS for apt repos is a simple way to improve the security of all 4. It adds a weak backup security layer for #1, it makes it much more difficult for a portion of a large internet mirror to be seletively blocked (e.g. #2 and #3). For example, if you use HTTPS to mirrors.kernel.org, everything has to be blocked to block Debian repos or packages. And pipelining downloads through a reused HTTPS connection makes it very difficult for the network observer to track metadata about packages, #4).&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leakage control&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-12701&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-100x100.jpg 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-200x200.jpg 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are some relatively easy steps that greatly reduce the amount of metadata that is leaked: using HTTPS connections to the mirrors and running those connections through Tor. Setting &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; to pipeline as many transactions into a given HTTPS session is also useful, but currently only supported for HTTP and not HTTPS. Even though HTTPS/TLS has security weaknesses, it is a lot better than nothing, and can help provide real world protection. The downside is that it is not common for Debian machines to connect to apt mirrors using HTTPS, so that potentially marks the install as a machine worth targeting. There are more and more HTTPS mirrors, and more interest in using them, so I think in time, that will only lessen as a concern. Here are the HTTPS mirrors that I have had good luck with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mirrors.ece.ubc.ca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mirrors.kernel.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mirror.cse.unsw.edu.au&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spout.ussg.indiana.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, here is the config that I have been using on a number of Debian-deriv machines, and it has been working well. It requires &lt;code&gt;apt-transport-https&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntuguide.org/wiki/Tor#Privoxy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;privoxy&lt;/code&gt; setup as an HTTP proxy for Tor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;$ cat /etc/apt/apt.conf.d/99force-tor
# force everything through privoxy HTTP proxy to tor
Acquire::ftp::Proxy &#34;http://127.0.0.1:8118&#34;;
Acquire::http::Proxy &#34;http://127.0.0.1:8118&#34;;
Acquire::https::Proxy &#34;http://127.0.0.1:8118&#34;;

# don&#39;t use SSL, its insecure, only use TLS
Acquire::https::SslForceVersion &#34;TLSv1&#34;;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found about 10 official Debian mirrors that have reliable HTTPS. Then I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/eighthave/7285154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;script that finds all of them&lt;/a&gt;, but many have self-signed certs and other issues. A number of the HTTPS mirrors also mirror the “security” archive, but I recommend that the &lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; URL to the official &lt;code&gt;security.debian.org&lt;/code&gt; repo is still included to make sure that security updates are promptly available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a test security repo running that is only available via an .onion address. I hope to encourage people to run official mirrors on a Tor Hidden Service, then HTTPS is not needed. Note that &lt;code&gt;apt-transport-tor&lt;/code&gt; is not required if a tor proxy is setup. To try mine, add it to your &lt;code&gt;sources.list&lt;/code&gt; (and make sure &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; is somehow using Tor). The order is important, that determines the priority of where &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; will get the package from is all other variables are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;deb http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian-security/ wheezy/updates main
deb http://security.debian.org/ wheezy/updates main
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Use the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://onion.debian.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debian Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt; now, &lt;tt&gt;dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion&lt;/tt&gt; is deprecated and will be shut down!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-specific-example-tails&#34;&gt;A specific example: TAILS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tails&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-12711&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-100x100.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-200x200.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails.png 256w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TAILS&lt;/a&gt; is an operating system that aims to be as private and anonymous as possible to enable, and has allowed &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.press/blog/2014/04/help-support-little-known-privacy-tool-has-been-critical-journalists-reporting-nsa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2014/10/laura-poitras-crypto-tools-made-snowden-film-possible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laura Poitras&lt;/a&gt; to work without leaking information despite being targeted by some very skilled and highly resourced organizations. TAILS mostly works as a “live CD”, meaning the whole operating system is downloaded as a single “image” file, then either burned to a CD/DVD, or to a USB thumb drive. Updates work the same way. But TAILS has an optional feature to use the Debian package system to install and persist packages that are not included by default. TAILS does not use the default set of mirrors that a standard Debian install uses, it is set up by default with a range of possible Debian package sources, including the current stable version (called wheezy), the versions in testing, and packages backported to the stable version. That means that when this feature is used, TAILS fetches the metadata for all of those sections of Debian (stable/wheezy, testing, wheezy-backports, unstable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given all of the proven fingerprinting approaches, like using the font list from the browser, I think its a safe assumption that the apt-get metadata will also provide similar fingerprinting opportunities. For basic TAILS use, this is all avoided since updates are done via ISO images. But once a user installs packages via &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt;, that changes since TAILS then goes out onto the internet to fetch all of the repo metadata. That goes over Tor since TAILS forces all network traffic over Tor, so that helps break the link between the machine downloading the updates and those that can see that machines internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems quite likely that the set of mirrors and the order in which they are run will provide a way to identify the system as TAILS. As for identifying individual machines, &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; sends a lot of metadata, like language that the system is using, which packages need updates, etc. On top of the set of mirrors used, there is potentially enough metadata there to fingerprint the individual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One open question is how the &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; downloads map to different Tor circuits. If all of the traffic from a given &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; session goes over a single Tor circuit, then the exit node, the mirror server, and any network observer that can see the traffic between those two can use that as the fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To expand on this, if TAILS fetched all of its apt sources (wheezy, backports, testing, etc) via HTTPS from the same mirror (e.g. mirrors.kernel.org), then the exit node and network observer could not really distinguish the distro the machine making the connection was running since mirrors.kernel.org hosts many distro mirrors. There are two key parts here: using HTTPS to encrypt the data, and using HTTP pipelining so that network connections are reused for multiple downloads, rather than the default behavior of making a new HTTPS for each individual download. This setup would also prevent the custom pattern of apt sources from being distinguished since it would just show as downloading some series of files, and those files could be packages, package metadata, perl modules, source tarballs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic, private distribution of our test builds</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/06/06/automatic-private-distribution-of-our-test-builds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 17:17:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/06/06/automatic-private-distribution-of-our-test-builds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing we are very lucky to have is a good community of people willing to test out unfinished builds of our software. That is a very valuable contribution to the process of developing usable, secure apps. So we want to make this process as easy as possible while keeping it as secure and private as possible. To that end, we have set up an &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FDroid&lt;/a&gt; repository of apps generated from the test builds that our build server generates automatically every time we publish new code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this big burst of development focused on FDroid, it has become clear that FDroid has lots of promise for becoming a complete solution for the whole process of delivering software from developers to users. We have tried other ways of delivering test builds like HockeyApp and Google Play’s Alpha and Beta channels and have found them lacking. The process did not seem as easy as it should be. And of course, both of them leave a lot to be desired when it comes to privacy of the users. So this is the first step in hopefully a much bigger project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use our new test build service, first install FDroid by downloading it from the official source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34;&gt;https://f-droid.org&lt;/a&gt;. Then using a QR Code scanner like &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.zxing.client.android&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Barcode Scanner&lt;/a&gt;, just scan the QR Code below, and send it to FDroid &lt;strong&gt;Repositories&lt;/strong&gt;. You can also browse to this page on your Android device, and click the link below to add it to FDroid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/fdroid/repo?fingerprint=F8ED4C73C125E7A67F99DB269480DAF50BE1758952E07EE5ABF116FE4B2DB1E8&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info/fdroid/repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/fdroid/repo?fingerprint=F8ED4C73C125E7A67F99DB269480DAF50BE1758952E07EE5ABF116FE4B2DB1E8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/dev.guardianproject.info-QR-e1402010770323.png&#34; alt=&#34;dev.guardianproject.info&#34; width=&#34;245&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-12462&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use our test repo via an anonymized connection using the Tor Hidden Service (as of this moment, that means downloading an &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/repo/org.fdroid.fdroid_710.apk&#34;&gt;official FDroid v0.71 build&lt;/a&gt;). Just get &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.android&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; and turn it on, and the following .onion address will automatically work in FDroid, as long as you have a new enough version (0.69 or later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://k6e4p7yji2rioxbm.onion/fdroid/repo?fingerprint=F8ED4C73C125E7A67F99DB269480DAF50BE1758952E07EE5ABF116FE4B2DB1E8&#34;&gt;http://k6e4p7yji2rioxbm.onion/fdroid/repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://k6e4p7yji2rioxbm.onion/fdroid/repo?fingerprint=F8ED4C73C125E7A67F99DB269480DAF50BE1758952E07EE5ABF116FE4B2DB1E8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/k6e4p7yji2rioxbm.onion-QR-e1402010779963.png&#34; alt=&#34;k6e4p7yji2rioxbm.onion&#34; width=&#34;245&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-12463&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your own private dropbox with free software</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/11/12/your-own-private-dropbox-with-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 12:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/11/12/your-own-private-dropbox-with-free-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of file storage and sharing software packages out there that make it easy for a group of people to share files. Dropbox is perhaps the most well known of the group, it provides an easy way for a group of people to share files. The downside of Dropbox is that it is not a private service, just like any cloud-based service. Dropbox has total access to your files that you store there. That means its likely that the NSA and its collaborators do too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dropbox also knows where the computers are that are accessing their service because they can see the IP address of the incoming connections. To help with this, it is possible to use use Dropbox over Tor, thankfully they have provided proxy settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our shared files, we use &lt;a href=&#34;http://sparkleshare.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SparkleShare&lt;/a&gt;. It provides an experience very similar to Dropbox: you have a SparkleShare folder that is synced up with the service, and in turn any other users who are also linked up to it. Once its setup, it is as easy to use as Dropbox, but setting it up takes a bit more work than Dropbox. It builds upon two software packages well known for security and reliability: &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt;, and works with Tor Hidden Services. It runs on Windows, Mac OS X, and GNU/Linux, and there is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NewProggie/SparkleShare-Android&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Android client&lt;/a&gt; in the works.&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/sparkleshare-onion.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/sparkleshare-onion.png&#34; alt=&#34;sparkleshare-onion&#34; width=&#34;312&#34; height=&#34;342&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-11936&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/sparkleshare-onion.png 312w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/sparkleshare-onion-273x300.png 273w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 312px) 100vw, 312px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use any git service as the server for SparkleShare, including github, bitbucket, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitorious.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gitorious&lt;/a&gt;, etc. But these have the same issues as putting your files on Dropbox: that service has complete access to your files. For extra protection, SparkleShare &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hbons/SparkleShare/wiki/Client-Side-Encryption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;can encrypt the files on the client-side&lt;/a&gt;, have encrypted shared folders with SparkleShare, so that the server does not have access to the files. For the last piece of setting up a private SparkleShare, you need a computer that you can &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; to, and has &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and Tor on it. This computer could even be an old Android device running &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/code/lildebi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lil’ Debi&lt;/a&gt;, it only needs enough disk space for your SparkleShare files and a steady network connection. Running it on your own computer means it can use a Tor Hidden Service, and that all of the metadata related to who is editing what files remains private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, setup a Tor Hidden Service to the sshd port. You can read all about that process in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/docs/tor-hidden-service.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor instructions&lt;/a&gt;, but basically, you need to add something like this to the &lt;code&gt;torrc&lt;/code&gt; configuration file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/ssh_hidden_service/
HiddenServicePort 22 127.0.0.1:22
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then restart tor, and it will generate two files in &lt;code&gt;/var/lib/tor/ssh_hidden_service/&lt;/code&gt;, open the file called &lt;code&gt;hostname&lt;/code&gt; to see your new .onion address. We’re going to use &lt;code&gt;fakefakefakefake.onion&lt;/code&gt; as our made-up one for this HOWTO. That is the address you will use in SparkleShare as the server address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; needs to be setup to use Tor to access the .onion address of the Tor Hidden Service. To do that we need the wonderful Netcat tool (&lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt;). On Debian/Ubuntu, run &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install netcat-openbsd&lt;/code&gt; to get it, its included with Mac OS X by default. Now edit your SSH config file, its usually in &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt;, and add this section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;Host *.onion
     Compression yes
     ProxyCommand nc -X 5 -x 127.0.0.1:9050 %h %p
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Windows, you need to use &lt;code&gt;connect&lt;/code&gt; proxy, which is thankfully included in SparkleShare. You can optionally use &lt;code&gt;connect&lt;/code&gt; instead of Netcat/&lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; on Mac OS X (&lt;code&gt;fink install connect&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;brew install connect&lt;/code&gt;) and GNU/Linux (e.g. &lt;code&gt;apt-get install connect-proxy&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;yum install connect-proxy&lt;/code&gt;). Instead of the snippet above, use this snippet in &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;connect&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;Host *.onion
     Compression yes
     ProxyCommand connect -5 -S 127.0.0.1:9050 %h %p
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now its time to set up the git repo on the server that will be the conduit for sharing files between the different users. Basically, all you need to do is create a new folder, then make it a “bare” git repo (you can read &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Git-on-the-Server-Setting-Up-the-Server&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;all about it in the git book&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;ssh g&amp;#x69;t&amp;#x40;&amp;#x66;a&amp;#x6b;e&amp;#x66;&amp;#x61;k&amp;#x65;f&amp;#x61;&amp;#x6b;e&amp;#x66;a&amp;#x6b;&amp;#x65;.&amp;#x6f;n&amp;#x69;&amp;#x6f;n
mkdir /home/git/MyPrivateShare
cd /home/git/MyPrivateShare
git init --bare
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sshing to the git, we set up a single account called &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, then to grant access, we add the SSH key (SparkleShare calls this the &lt;em&gt;Client ID&lt;/em&gt;) to the &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; account’s &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/authorized_keys&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now everything should be ready to start adding clients! In SparkleShare, go to Add Hosted Project…, choose On my own server, then enter your username and .onion address (&lt;em&gt;ssh:&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x67;&amp;#x69;t@fak&amp;#x65;&amp;#x66;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x6b;efake&amp;#x66;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x6b;&amp;#x65;.onio&amp;#x6e;&lt;/em&gt;) in &lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt; and the path to the git repo (&lt;em&gt;/home/git/MyPrivateShare&lt;/em&gt;) in &lt;strong&gt;Remote Path&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screenshot-SparkleShare-Setup.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screenshot-SparkleShare-Setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;SparkleShare Setup&#34; width=&#34;686&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-11945&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screenshot-SparkleShare-Setup.png 686w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screenshot-SparkleShare-Setup-300x186.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 686px) 100vw, 686px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the client will download the entire git repository from the server, and you’ll then have a working shared dropbox! If there are a lot of files in it, then the first sync can take a long time before any files show up. This is because git first downloads the entire history first, then it checks out the files. After that initial setup, then the new files show up quite quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this SparkleShare setup keeps your files on computers that you control, it prevents information and metadata from being leaked to the network while people are using this SparkleShare setup. When using Client Side Encryption, even less data is leaked. The server cannot access the content of the files at all since they are encrypted. The the server in this case would only be able to see the network traffic, and which ssh key was used to access the server. If everyone accessing this setup used the same user account (i.e. &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;) and ssh key, then the server would not even know which user is making the changes. This is about as private as you could hope for in a shared dropbox folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last nice feature of this setup is that git server does not need a domain name, static IP or even a public IP, it just needs a working internet connection. As long as it can connect to Tor, then the Hidden Service will work. So if this private dropbox is for extra sensitive stuff, it could be stashed anywhere it can get power and wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues when distributing software</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/10/31/issues-when-distributing-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 15:51:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/10/31/issues-when-distributing-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is currently a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.debian.org/debian-security/2013/10/msg00027.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;discussion underway on the Debian-security list&lt;/a&gt; about adding TLS and Tor functionality to the official repositories (repos) of Debian packages that is highlighting how we need to update how we think about the risks when distributing software. Mostly, we are used to thinking about making sure that the software that the user is installing is the same exact software that has been posted for distribution. This is generally handled by signing the software package, then verifying that signature on the user’s machine. This is how it works on Mac OS X, Windows, Debian, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the authenticity of a software package is not the only issue that needs to be addressed, especially these days where many companies and governments around the world are trying to track everything that anyone is doing on the internet. In order to understand why Tor and TLS would be useful here, it good to break down the various concerns (or threats if you prefer):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package authenticity &lt;em&gt;(software can be modified while being downloaded)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package availability &lt;em&gt;(software security updates can be individually blocked)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repo availability &lt;em&gt;(internet services can be blocked by governments and companies)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who’s downloading what package &lt;em&gt;(currently visible to anyone who can see the network traffic, including open wifi, etc.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people distributing software are used to thinking about #1 verifying packages when thinking about the security of software distribution. #2, #3, and #4 are also important, and currently not well addressed. This is where TLS and Tor come in. Both can help prevent Man-In-The-Middle manipulations as well as reduce the amount of information that is leaked to the network. Tor can also help with #3. Since Tor is difficult to block, it is often uses to circumvent censorship. In this case a software repo could be blocked entirely, and Tor could help with gaining access to it. The Update Framework has &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/theupdateframework/tuf/blob/develop/README.md&#34; title=&#34;TUF: The Update Framework -  Security&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a good overview of the possible attacks&lt;/a&gt; against software repos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So having software repos available with both TLS and Tor available as options is a very good idea. As far as I have seen, there are not any Debian repos available via a Tor Hidden Service. There are a number of official mirrors that already support TLS/HTTPS. You can find them using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/eighthave/7285154&#34; title=&#34;the script in a gist paste&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this script:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;#!/usr/bin/python

import urllib2
import re
import ssl
import sys

# # find generic mirrors
mirrors = urllib2.urlopen(&#39;http://www.debian.org/mirror/list&#39;)
https = []
for line in mirrors.readlines():
    m = re.match(&#39;.*&amp;lt;td valign=&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http(.*)&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.*&#39;, line)
    if m:
        url = &#39;https&#39; + m.group(1)
        print &#39;trying: &#39;,
        print url,
        print &#39;...&#39;,
        sys.stdout.flush()
        try:
            response=urllib2.urlopen(url, timeout=1)
            https.append(url)
            print &#39;success!&#39;
        except urllib2.URLError as err:
            print &#39;fail!&#39;
        except ssl.SSLError as err:
            print &#39;bad SSL!&#39;

# print &#39;HTTPS apt repos:&#39;
#for url in https:
#    print url


# # find security mirrors
mirrors = urllib2.urlopen(&#39;http://www.debian.org/mirror/list-full&#39;)
securitys = []
for line in mirrors.readlines():
    m = re.match(&#39;.*&amp;lt;/tt&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Security updates over HTTP: &amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http(.*)&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.*/debian-security/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.*&#39;, line)
    if m:
        url = &#39;https&#39; + m.group(1)
        print &#39;trying: &#39;,
        print url,
        print &#39;...&#39;,
        sys.stdout.flush()
        try:
            response=urllib2.urlopen(url, timeout=1)
            securitys.append(url)
            print &#39;success!&#39;
        except urllib2.URLError as err:
            print &#39;fail!&#39;
        except ssl.SSLError as err:
            print &#39;bad SSL!&#39;

# print &#39;HTTPS security repos:&#39;
# for url in securitys:
#     print url


# now find the backports mirrors
mirrors = urllib2.urlopen(&#39;http://backports-master.debian.org/Mirrors/&#39;)
backports = []
for line in mirrors.readlines():
#&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://be.mirror.eurid.eu/debian-backports/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;/debian-backports/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
    m = re.match(&#39;.*&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http(.*)&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.*/debian-backports/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.*&#39;, line)
    if m:
        url = &#39;https&#39; + m.group(1)
        print &#39;trying: &#39;,
        print url,
        print &#39;...&#39;,
        sys.stdout.flush()
        try:
            response=urllib2.urlopen(url, timeout=1)
            backports.append(url)
            print &#39;success!&#39;
        except urllib2.URLError as err:
            print &#39;fail!&#39;
        except ssl.SSLError as err:
            print &#39;bad SSL!&#39;

#print &#39;HTTPS backports repos:&#39;
#for url in backports:
#    print url


# now find the CD image mirrors
mirrors = urllib2.urlopen(&#39;http://www.debian.org/CD/http-ftp/&#39;)
cds = []
for line in mirrors.readlines():
# &amp;lt;a rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://mirror.easyspeedy.com/debian-cd/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;HTTP&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    m = re.match(&#39;.*&amp;lt;a rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http(:.*)&amp;quot;&amp;gt;HTTP&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;.*&#39;, line)
    if m:
        url = &#39;https&#39; + m.group(1)
        print &#39;trying: &#39;,
        print url,
        print &#39;...&#39;,
        sys.stdout.flush()
        try:
            response=urllib2.urlopen(url, timeout=1)
            cds.append(url)
            print &#39;success!&#39;
        except urllib2.URLError as err:
            print &#39;fail!&#39;
        except ssl.SSLError as err:
            print &#39;bad SSL!&#39;

print &#39;HTTPS CD image repos:&#39;
for url in cds:
    print url


# now write everything to a file
f = open(&#39;/tmp/https-debian-archives.txt&#39;, &#39;w&#39;)

f.write(&#39;HTTPS apt repos\n&#39;)
f.write(&#39;---------------\n&#39;)
for url in https:
    f.write(url + &#39;\n&#39;)

f.write(&#39;\n\nHTTPS security repos\n&#39;)
f.write(&#39;---------------\n&#39;)
for url in securitys:
    f.write(url + &#39;\n&#39;)

f.write(&#39;\n\nHTTPS backports repos\n&#39;)
f.write(&#39;--------------------\n&#39;)
for url in backports:
    f.write(url + &#39;\n&#39;)

f.write(&#39;\n\nHTTPS CD image repos\n&#39;)
f.write(&#39;--------------------\n&#39;)
for url in cds:
    f.write(url + &#39;\n&#39;)


f.close()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orweb Security Advisory: Possible IP leakage with HTML5 video/audio</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/08/21/orweb-security-advisory-possible-ip-leakage-with-html5-video/audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 16:15:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/08/21/orweb-security-advisory-possible-ip-leakage-with-html5-video/audio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/orweb&#34;&gt;Orweb browser app&lt;/a&gt; is vulnerable to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/issues/1754&#34;&gt;leak the actual IP of the device&lt;/a&gt; it is on, if it loads a page with HTML5 video or audio tags on them, and those tags are set to auto-start or display a poster frame. On some versions of Android, the video and audio player start/load events happen without the user requesting anything, and the request to the URL for the media src or through image poster is made outside of the proxy settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Android WebView component upon which Orweb is built, does not &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/OnionKit/blob/master/libonionkit/src/info/guardianproject/onionkit/web/WebkitProxy.java&#34;&gt;pass on the proxy settings&lt;/a&gt; for the web page to embedded media players it displays. Additionally, even though the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/webkit/WebSettings.PluginState.html&#34;&gt;proper API calls are made&lt;/a&gt; to turn off all plugins, apparently HTML5 video and audio players not considered plugins, and there is no way to disable them at an API level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently working to determine which versions of Android these issues occur on. We have a fix implemented that filters all video and audio tag instances out of retrieved content, and on newer versions of Android, that requires a user gesture/tap before media players are loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect to have a fix out in the next 24 to 48 hours. In the meantime, if you are using Orweb with the goal of strong anonymity, and not just circumvention or proxying, we advise you to avoid all sites that may include HTML5 video or audio content embedded in the pages, or to just stop using the app all together. Alternatively, you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mobile/&#34;&gt;Firefox for Android&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/proxymob-firefox-add-on/&#34;&gt;Proxy Mobile&lt;/a&gt; add-on (load this XPI within Firefox: &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/releases/proxymob-latest.xpi&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/releases/proxymob-latest.xpi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This does NOT affect users who use the root mode with transparent proxying, as that handles proxying the entire traffic of the entire device or a particular app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbot v12 now in beta</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/07/24/orbot-v12-now-in-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 12:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/07/24/orbot-v12-now-in-beta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much too long, we’ve got a new build of Orbot out, and it is… a stable beta! Nothing radically new here, just many small changes to continue to improve the experience of our hundreds of thousands of active users out in the world. There will likely be one or two more “beta” releases to iron out small issues in v12, but for now, this one is good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/mightyorbot.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;mightyorbot&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/mightyorbot-225x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;a very might orbot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really exciting aspect of this release is that we have ironed out some integration points with other apps, like our own Gibberbot, and third-party apps like DuckDuckGo. These apps can now tell if Orbot is installed, running, and if not, request it to start up. Once Orbot is started, it will return to the calling app, and let them know they can proceed with routing their traffic over Tor. We hope that through use of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/OnionKit/blob/master/libonionkit/src/info/guardianproject/onionkit/ui/OrbotHelper.java&#34;&gt;OrbotHelper utility&lt;/a&gt; (part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/OnionKit&#34;&gt;OnionKit/NetCipher library&lt;/a&gt;), many more apps will choose to provide their users with better anonymity and privacy of their network traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;Since we haven’t done a release in awhile, and we have some new build &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;tools, I mostly want to make sure I have not done something terribly &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;wrong in the build process. Please confirm back if you are able to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;successfully use this release. You can report issues &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/orbot/issues/new&#34;&gt;on our bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve switched versioning styles to a simpler major.minor.bugfix “semantic” model, so this is now Orbot 12.0.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signed 12.0.1 beta release build is here:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rink.hockeyapp.net/apps/92ace552aa5344d1a802decb71525897/&#34;&gt;https://rink.hockeyapp.net/apps/92ace552aa5344d1a802decb71525897/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct APK is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/releases/Orbot-release-12.0.1-beta-1.apk&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/releases/Orbot-release-12.0.1-beta-1.apk&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/releases/Orbot-release-12.0.1-beta-1.apk.asc&#34;&gt;gpg sig&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have automated “nightly” debug builds from the development branch:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/builds/Orbot/&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/builds/Orbot/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates in 12.0.1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;updated to Tor 0.2.4.15-RC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;flashy screen bug fixed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;now shows traffic stats in notification area&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;better handling of preference settings changes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;added superuser permission for Cyanogen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better support for “start” Intent, integration with other apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tagged source is here:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/n8fr8/orbot.git/log/refs/tags/12.0.1&#34;&gt;https://gitweb.torproject.org/n8fr8/orbot.git/log/refs/tags/12.0.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Way to Visit Strongbox on a Phone</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/05/16/the-only-way-to-visit-strongbox-on-a-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 17:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/05/16/the-only-way-to-visit-strongbox-on-a-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; magazine just launched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/closeread/2013/05/introducing-strongbox-anonymous-document-sharing-tool.html&#34;&gt;Strongbox&lt;/a&gt;, a whistleblower submission system that’s hosted on a hidden website. There’s only one way to access the hidden site on a phone or tablet, and that’s with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.browser&amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Orweb app&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s a simple breakdown of how to do securely and anonymously blow the whistle, explained in an interactive tutorial:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3719  aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy19&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19-199x300.png&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19.png 400w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Visit &lt;a title=&#34;strongbox tutorial&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&lt;/a&gt; for an interactive tutorial on using Strongbox on your phone.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The website exists as a hidden site on what is widely known as the darknet, since you are going there hidden or “in the dark.” Instead of a .com, .org, or .info address (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;) the sites like Strongbox show up with a .onion. And like you need a web browser to go to a .com web address, you need a darknet browser to go to a .onion darknet address. On a mobile, we make the most secure and anonymous darknet &amp; web browser, Orweb. And if you want to get to strongbox on your phone, we’re the only way to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  To browse, you’ll need our &lt;a title=&#34;orweb&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orweb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orweb&lt;/a&gt; app. It’s currently only available for Android and you can &lt;a title=&#34;Orweb anonymous browser&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.browser &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;get it here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have another type of phone or tablet, unfortunately you’ll have to use a computer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  For Orweb to be anonymous and give you access to the darknet .onion addresses, you’ll need to enable onion routing with our &lt;a title=&#34;orbot&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; plugin. This plugin gives Orweb and other compatible apps (like our &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.otr.app.im&#34;&gt;Gibberbot secure chat&lt;/a&gt;  for Facebook, Google, &amp; Jabber) the ability to send web traffic through the darknet, thus avoiding tracking as well as blocking. You can &lt;a title=&#34;Orbot on Android&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.android  &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;download Orbot here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the official app of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://TorProject.org&#34;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt;, which develops the onion routing protocol, on Android.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Once both are installed, you just need to go to this hidden site: &lt;a title=&#34;Strongbox Onion Site&#34; href=&#34;http://tnysbtbxsf356hiy.onion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://tnysbtbxsf356hiy.onion&lt;/a&gt; . Make sure that you’re using the Orweb browser and that Orbot is running. From there, you can easily submit messages to The New Yorker. Unfortunately you can’t yet submit files to them through the phone just yet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Overall, this is an exciting step in the right direction. With an increase in tracking and crackdown on political dissidents and whistleblowers around the world, there need to be safe and trusted ways of sharing information that has the potential of saving lives and making the world a better place. &lt;a title=&#34;the new yorker magazine&#34; href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most trusted journalistic outfits in the world and it will be interesting to follow how they understand and vet information that comes in from anonymous sources. It will be a lesson for the entire privacy community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/PihUXCmJzW/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3730 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;On the Internet, algorithms can infer you&#39;re a dog.&#34; alt=&#34;Dog Algorithm&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-300x300.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm.jpg 612w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  At the same time, it’s not yet a trusted technology. While the code is accessible and &lt;a href=&#34;http://deaddrop.github.io/&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; it is unclear whether it’s a full version of the DeadDrop code that it came from or a fork of it. It also hasn’t been audited yet. Already, we’re seeing issues popping up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deaddrop/deaddrop/issues&#34;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully it will be fully vetted as a solution and stand up to the ambitious and crucial claims that it is able “to provide you with a greater degree of anonymity and security than afforded by conventional e-mail.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  In the months before January, I worked a few seats down from Aaron Swartz in the ThoughtWorks offices. Since those shocking days, it’s been inspiring to continue to see his legacy. I spoke with him a bunch of times about using technology to introduce truly disruptive techniques for empowering people whose rights were otherwise being trampled. At the time, we were working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbelinsky.com/crowdring/&#34;&gt;Crowdring&lt;/a&gt;, an intiative from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.therules.org/&#34;&gt;/The Rules&lt;/a&gt;. And we spoke about the power of leveraging telephony to give voice so widely, and the trade off of handing over personally identifiable information. He recognized the need for constantly evolving and shifting tactics and was expert at integrating that into both strategy and code. It’s an honor to continue to work with him now, and with the rest of the open source community as we all contribute code and ideas to make the world better.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Having just won the Knight News Challenge for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2013/01/27/informacam-wins-knight-news-challenge/&#34;&gt;Informacam project&lt;/a&gt;, we’re excited at the growing interest from the world of journalism in making sure that sources are kept truly secure and anonymous in the digital age. We’re working to build our whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=6502754515281796553&#34;&gt;suite of tools&lt;/a&gt; to make it easier and better to do so. If you want to reach out to us, anonymously or otherwise, to &lt;a title=&#34;Guardian Contact&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/ &#34;&gt;let us know how we can help&lt;/a&gt;, you can use Orbot and Tor to do so over any of these methods. We look forward to it!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Awareness Party</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/04/26/security-awareness-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 09:05:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/04/26/security-awareness-party/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the security world, there’s a pesky belief that a tool can either be secure or easy to use, but not both. Some experts also argue that training people to be safe online is too hard and doesn’t accomplish much (see Bruce Schneier’s recent post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/03/security_awaren_1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security Awareness Training&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Without a thoughtful approach, that’s usually how it plays out. But it doesn’t have to be that way! We’re committed to making online security fun to learn and fun to use, and we’re launching a new series of interactive tutorials to make it happen. Consider this post an invitation to our festive Security Awareness Party. &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/home/how-you-can-work-with-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beer is encouraged&lt;/a&gt;, especially if it comes from &lt;a title=&#34;Android-powered beer kegerator&#34; href=&#34;https://kegbot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an Android-powered kegbot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Guardian, security is always our #1 priority. We owe that to our users who rely on us to keep them safe in places like Syria or Iran. But the time we spend on encryption is wasted if users don’t like using our tools, or can’t figure out how they work. We want to make security apps that are enjoyable and easy to use everyday, and don’t take a PHD to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activists in Iran and Syria know firsthand how important technologies like Tor and VPNs are for staying safe online. Our friends and neighbors might not be living under a repressive dictatorship, but that doesn’t mean they couldn’t use a little digital security in their lives. Maybe your nephew wants to get past the block on Facebook at school, or your co-worker wants to watch March Madness at work (make sure she gets that decoy spreadsheet ready). Maybe your friend just wants to send his wife a few…private messages, and he’d rather not have them stored by Google or Verizon. These people might not be pros, but they’re curious and happy to poke around their technology. With a little fun and interactive guidance, they can be well on their way to becoming a power user. Everyone starts somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make life safer and easier for at-risk activists and everyday people alike. That’s why we make accessible and straightforward guides to help you quickly and easily get past censors, internet police, or the office IT department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gibberbot-tutorial&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gibberbot Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newest tutorial is for our secure chat app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.otr.app.im&amp;feature=search_result&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibberbot&lt;/a&gt;. With your Android phone in one hand and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/chatsecurely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibberbot Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; in the other, you can be chatting securely on Google or Facebook chat in minutes! But Google and Facebook can’t even tell what you’re talking about. It’s also more convenient to have all of your chat apps rolled into one so that it doesn’t matter where your friends message you, it still goes to the same place. Gibberbot works even if someone is trying to monitor or block your phone’s communications. If you know another language and would like to contribute, &lt;a title=&#34;Gibberbot Tutorial Transifex Translations&#34; href=&#34;https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/gibberbot-tutorial/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;we’d love your help translating the tutorial (we’ve got English and Tibetan covered)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3291&#34; style=&#34;width: 251px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/chatsecurely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3291&#34; class=&#34; wp-image-3291&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy5&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/galaxy5.png&#34; width=&#34;241&#34; height=&#34;361&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-3291&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    So you want to chat securely?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
     
  &lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Orbot Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    With our Android app Orbot, browsing the web securely and safely through Tor has been a piece of cake for a while now. But we just created &lt;a title=&#34;How to Orbot Tutorial&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/browsefreely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an interactive tutorial to get you started&lt;/a&gt; and show how easy it is circumvent censorship, even if the Google Play Store is blocking direct access to our app.
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    The tools themselves are getting smarter too. A new tool from &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project&#34; href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;, called &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project Obfsproxy&#34; href=&#34;http://www.torproject.org/projects/obfsproxy.html.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pluggable Transports&lt;/a&gt;, hides your Tor traffic to look like regular Internet traffic, making it even easier for Tor users to stay ahead of surveillance and censorship. To use this new tool with Orbot, just follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/How-to-browse-freely-on-your-phone-if-your-internet-is-blocked.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our new one-page guide&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a title=&#34;How to browse freely on your phone if your internet is blocked - Farsi&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/How-to-browse-freely-on-your-phone-if-your-internet-is-blocked-Farsi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in Farsi&lt;/a&gt;) and you’re all set! For a more in-depth guide to using Orbot, watch our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dcf5sh99ze0&#34;&gt;video tutorial&lt;/a&gt; (now in English and Arabic).
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3585&#34; style=&#34;width: 250px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/browsefreely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3585&#34; class=&#34; wp-image-3585&#34; alt=&#34;orbot galaxy s3&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15.png&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;361&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15.png 400w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15-199x300.png 199w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p id=&amp;quot;caption-attachment-3585&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;wp-caption-text&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  So you want to escape censorship?
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      As we continue to grow our team and create new tools, we need your feedback!  Please tell us what we can do to go from security awareness training to a full-on security awareness party. Feel free to leave a comment on this post or tell us how we can make things easier through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/&#34;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt;. You can also let us know about any upcoming parties that we should be attending.
    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;This post is partially a response to Bruce Schneier’s recent piece: &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Schneier Security Awareness Training&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/03/security_awaren_1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Security Awareness Training&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumble and the Bandwidth – Anonymous CB radio with Mumble and Tor</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/01/31/mumble-and-the-bandwidth-anonymous-cb-radio-with-mumble-and-tor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 02:05:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/01/31/mumble-and-the-bandwidth-anonymous-cb-radio-with-mumble-and-tor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/mumble-and-the-bandwidth.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3186&#34; alt=&#34;mumble and the bandwidth&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/mumble-and-the-bandwidth.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;478&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/mumble-and-the-bandwidth.jpg 800w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/mumble-and-the-bandwidth-300x179.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey towards anonymous and secure voice communication is a long one. There’s lots of roadblocks to get your voice from point A to point B over the Internet if you need to prevent eavesdropping or censorship. There is the limited bandwidth of mobile data connections. There is the high latency of the TCP protocol. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/about/overview.html.en#whyweneedtor&#34;&gt;To achieve anonymity via Tor&lt;/a&gt;, there’s even more latency added to each packet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mumble.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Mumble&lt;/a&gt; is a non-standard protocol that was originally designed for realtime voice chat for video games. If you’ve ever played Halo or World of Warcraft, this should sound familiar. If not, think of it as a conference call you don’t have to ring. You simply connect to a Mumble server over the Internet and your voice will transmit to everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mumble clients are available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.morlunk.mumbleclient&amp;amp;feature=nav_result#?t=W251bGwsMSwxLDMsImNvbS5tb3JsdW5rLm11bWJsZWNsaWVudCJd&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mumble/id443472808?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&#34;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a cross-platform desktop client. The server software is also cross-platform. Guardian Project is focusing on the Android client named &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.morlunk.mumbleclient&amp;amp;feature=nav_result#?t=W251bGwsMSwxLDMsImNvbS5tb3JsdW5rLm11bWJsZWNsaWVudCJd&#34;&gt;Plumble&lt;/a&gt; and the official server &lt;a href=&#34;https://packages.debian.org/search?keywords=mumble&amp;amp;searchon=names&amp;amp;section=all&amp;amp;suite=squeeze-backports&#34;&gt;backported to Debian stable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cool feature of Mumble is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Push-to-talk&#34;&gt;Push To Talk&lt;/a&gt; (PTT) method to speak to the channel. Your voice is only transmitted when you press the PTT button in the user interface. Another lower level feature that’s important for our anonymity goal is TCP support. For any application to run over Tor, it must use the TCP protocol. This rules out most VoIP clients, since they use UDP. Here is a case where Mumble’s non-standard protocol works to our advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Tor is running and your Mumble client is configured to use TCP, connecting to your local SOCKS5 proxy offered by Tor allows you to join a Mumble server anonymously. The big problem is as suspected, latency. The traffic passing through the Tor network must make &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/about/overview.html.en#thesolution&#34;&gt;an indeterminate number of proxy hops&lt;/a&gt; to be anonymized successfully. Each hop adds more and more latency. This makes a typical syncronous voice call impossible since there’s no way to determine when one person has stopped talking and when the other can respond without interrupting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latency in human speech transmision has deep psychological impact on a conversation. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/qurihara/top-english/speechjammer&#34;&gt;Japanese research project called SpeechJammer&lt;/a&gt; exploited this part of our senses by inventing a “shut up gun.” When pointed at a person it makes them immediately stop talking. Everyone who has used a cell phone knows the frustration of “echo” where you hear your own voice, slightly delayed. The delay is caused by the network latency of the cellular carrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another similar example is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voip&#34;&gt;VoIP&lt;/a&gt; call on a congested network. The side effect of the latency is that one person accidently interrupts the other person because he thinks the other person has finished talking, when in reality the other person’s voice hasn’t yet arrived at the other end. Interruption ensues, no one is happy nor do they know anything new since the transmission was not understood. High latency makes &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Full-duplex#Full-duplex&#34;&gt;full-duplex communication ineffective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contemporary telephone you are acustomed to allows both sides to talk and listen simultaneously. This is called full-duplex. Early radio telephones like walkie talkies, CB radio or aviation radio are half-duplex systems, meaning that for any given transmission, only one side can talk while the other side listens. Running Mumble over Tor takes a full-duplex technology and effectively reduces it to half-duplex. Even though the protocol is full-duplex, when run through a high latency network like Tor, the transmit and receive channels are so far out of sync there is no point in allowng both sides to talk at once. Again, interruption ensues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it hit me. Radio telephones have been around since the turn of the 20th century, when people figured out a reasonable way to do voice chat without the technology causing accidental interruptions in the conversation. In particular, the use of procedure words, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procedure_word&#34;&gt;prowords&lt;/a&gt;, are essential for one speaker to acknowledge the transmission of the other (Roger), to signify that one party is finished speaking (Over), or indicate when one party has left the conversation (Out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in the USA, some prowords evolved into a coloquial language, complete with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_CB_slang&#34;&gt;slang&lt;/a&gt; thanks to the Citizen Band radio boom of the 1960s and the truck driving culture that used it to communicate while on the road. The 1977 film &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0076729/?ref_=sr_1&#34;&gt;Smokey and the Bandit&lt;/a&gt; is more than just a touching love story with world class actors, it is an amazing dramatization of an information culture that resembled pre-Internet &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulletin_board_system&#34;&gt;BBS systems&lt;/a&gt; and current day &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IRC&#34;&gt;Internet Relay Chat (IRC)&lt;/a&gt; networks around the globe. The truck drivers portrayed in that movie have a mobile, decentralized information sharing network that is anonymous. The users have pseudonyms and a language of their own. Many of them have never met their CB radio friends IRL. They are invisible companions on the lonely road of the US of A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old ideas are worth bringing back if they have strong roots. CB and general purpose radio telephones have a long history, unlike the standard the standard of tody, VoIP. Perhaps these features are thought of as obsolete or not cutting-edge enough to model into a digital system. Regardless of the reason, if you are looking for a mobile and open source PTT solution to use on the Internet with anonymity and security, Mumble over Tor is currently the state of the art. All you have to do is throw in some prowords to keep the conversation flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Guardian Project is operating a private Mumble server during a testing phase, and we have plans to open this to the public as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wiki/OSTN&#34;&gt;OSTN research effort&lt;/a&gt;. When that happens, I will post application-specific tutorials to install and configure the Plumble client. I will also publish a cookbook to build a Mumble server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, an example transmission log with some prowords:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internet&lt;/em&gt;: Guardian Project. I have a ping response from your server, over.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;GP&lt;/em&gt;: Roger Internet. Ping was sent, over.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Internet&lt;/em&gt;: Guardian Project. Build anonymous PTT system with open source software, over.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;GP&lt;/em&gt;: Internet, build anonymous PTT system with open source software, wilco. Out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voice over Tor?</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/12/10/voice-over-tor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 11:00:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/12/10/voice-over-tor/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/onioncart.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-2968&#34; title=&#34;onioncart&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/onioncart.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;425&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/onioncart.jpg 700w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/onioncart-300x182.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voice calls over &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project&#34; href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; are supposed to be impossible. It seems this may no longer be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without being able to do voice over IP (VOIP) conversations over the Tor network, people are prevented from being able to route  calls outside of censored networks. People ask us if there is any way they can route voice traffic through Tor to avoid blocks. To our surprise, we tested &lt;a title=&#34;skype&#34; href=&#34;http://skype.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; and found that it can work acceptably over &lt;a title=&#34;Orbot&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main reasons that it has been held that VOIP will not practically work over the Tor network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A technical problem with the transport layer that Tor supports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The network is too slow for the latency demands of a real-time voice conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it turns out Skype has some pretty robust signaling capabilities such that it works on a variety of network conditions. Also, in practice the latency is more usable then one would have thought. This is good news for the future of VOIP traffic over the Tor network, and not only over Skype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;problem-1-transport-protocol&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem 1: Transport Protocol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP is the most common transport protocol for the Internet. It guarantees reliable communication and is used for nearly everything you do in an Internet browser. UDP is a more relaxed protocol used for real-time communications because it reduces latency. The cost for this is that UDP is not reliable and will occasionally drop traffic. For this reason, it is useful for real-time applications that benefit from lower latency. While dropping packets is never ideal, in a real-time communications it usually doesn’t significant affect the quality and even then the time it would take to re-transmit lost packets with TCP might preclude the data being relevant to the stream anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that Tor only supports TCP for its transport layer. Meanwhile, VOIP applications use UDP. So they’re not supposed to work over Tor and one of the main difficulties for VOIP users to apply strong anonymity to real-time voice communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you tunneled UDP traffic through Tor it would be encapsulated in TCP and lose any benefits that UDP provides for real-time traffic. The TCP mechanisms attempt to account for lost packets and hold delivery of future packets until a resend is complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about networking, I would highly recommend &lt;a title=&#34;Computer Networks by Peterson and Davie&#34; href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books/about/Computer_networks.html?id=eftSAAAAMAAJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Computer Networks by Peterson and Davie.&lt;/a&gt; Its takes a practical approach to teaching the technology and avoids strict adherence to the layered model of the Internet. Beyond that, any TCP/IP or Internet technology introductory resource will get you far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution: &lt;/strong&gt;Here either Tor needs to support UDP or you need a VOIP client that supports TCP. It had been suggested that Skype will fallback to use TCP connections in instances in which the user has UDP traffic blocked. This is not a very uncommon network policy for some Internal networks and reflects Skype’s effort to make their application work in many hostile network conditions (NATs, firewalls, ect.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;problem-2-latency&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem 2: Latency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Tor relays and mixes its traffic across multiple nodes which greatly increases latency. People generally have pretty high performance expectations for latency over a two-way phone conversation. Adding even a couple of  milliseconds of lag between conversations can be very noticeable to the user. It causes jerks and jumps in the conversation, making it hard to communicate. For this reason, it is likely that widespread routing of voice traffic through Tor is unlikely. However, people already cope with quite a bit of latency using VOIP internationally, and there are very real security and censorship demands that would require VOIP over Tor. In many situations latency will be quite usable. Let’s see how it actually feels over Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution here is just accepting the latency. The latency is not ideal but in practice, it is still quite usable. As Tor network performance increases (and one-day supports UDP), real-time communications will begin to have better performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;skype-over-tor&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skype over Tor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For testing, I used two Nexus One phones running Gingerbread and the latest Skype binary from the Android App Store. Orbot will transparently route traffic through Tor if you use its transproxy features. The transproxy will drop UDP traffic since it can’t be routed through Tor. It is this feature that causes Skype to fallback to TCP and work over Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I looked at normal Skype traffic leaving the phone. It uses some TCP connections to contact Microsoft servers and authenticate your account. Once you start a voice chat you will see lots of UDP traffic as expected. However, if you turn on Orbots transproxy you will see Skype being forced to start up a conversation using only TCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a Wireshark screenshot of failed UDP connections to Microsoft servers. I did this by letting the UDP traffic through, logging it, and then dropping it before it left my test environment. So you can see the UDP connections going one way to a variety of IP addresses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/croppedUDP.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2976&#34; title=&#34;croppedUDP&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/croppedUDP.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/croppedUDP.png 988w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/croppedUDP-300x128.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 988px) 100vw, 988px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set one of the phones to route through Tor by turning on the transproxy. Then logged into Skype on each phone and placed a call. Skype worked over Tor! We were having a conversation across two IPs from two different ISPs. The latency wasn’t great, but it was surprisingly usable. I’ve included two-packet captures. One should just look like Tor traffic and is a Skype conversation over Tor. The other is an actual log of the dropped UDP packets (I dropped them at an intermediary device rather than using the Transproxy to capture this). In the UDP log set you’ll see a bunch of UDP traffic originating form a single address (the phone) with no return traffic. They UDP traffic was being immediately dropped after the log.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out you can have a workable VOIP chat over Tor if you use Skype. The findings are interesting because they are relevant to the general problem of trying to use real-time communication through the Tor network. It may also be useful for VERY specific and limited threat models that involve censorship bypass in which there is little risk in being caught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to hoping for UDP over Tor in the future. Until then, Guardian Project is working on a design for high latency voice communications. The idea is that you could send quick voice messages with the click of a button similar to how you use an old hand-held radio. We’re toying with names like Push to Torlk and Onion Ringer. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: In my opinion, Skype is not a secure standard for VOIP communication. It uses non-standard closed source encryption and has likely become CALEA compliant upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/ericjackson/2012/07/22/its-terrifying-and-sickening-that-microsoft-can-now-listen-in-on-all-my-skype-calls/&#34;&gt;acquisition&lt;/a&gt; by Microsoft. That means that they have infrastructure in place to intercept communications and relay that information to law enforcement agencies around the world. It is unwise to assume that other state and non-state actors would not also have means to access that data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes the best solution is a library, not an app</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/08/27/sometimes-the-best-solution-is-a-library-not-an-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 12:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/08/27/sometimes-the-best-solution-is-a-library-not-an-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/framework_wheel.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/framework_wheel-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;thinking about frameworks&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2792&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Our general approach to software development starts with surveying existing solutions that are available and in use, to see if there is already enough of an ecosystem or whether we need to seed that. When there is already an adundance of tools and apps out there, we work to find the good ones, provide feedback and auditing, and then build apps and tools to fill in any gaps. For example, this was our approach in the Open Secure Telephony Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there is not an ecosystem around a given problem, then we aim to make it as easy as possible for people writing software to address the issues. In this case, we focus on making developer tools. For example, most of the data on our phones is easily accessible to someone who has physical access to the device, be it the secret police or a thief. IOCipher and SQLCipher-for-Android both provide tools to easily encrypt data, using APIs that are very familiar to anyone doing Android development. We specifically aim to take complex technical challenges and bundle them up into packages that allow developers to add functionality in a matter of hours or days rather than weeks or months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the developer tools that Guardian Project is creating, the impact is not as overt as in other software development since they are largely invisible to the users if we have done our jobs right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for our developer projects to have a good impact, there are many different aspects that need to be covered. After assessing the current available tools to determine the general approach, the technical approach is chosen. This will influence the development time, the efficiency, and ease of use. As soon as the project is developed to a basic usable state, it is time to get feedback from willing testers to validate the techical approach. After more development and feedback, next comes documentation and beta releases. Once the project gets to a point where the releases and documentation are good enough for most people to figure out what they need, then we start evangelizing the tool and lobby the developers of existing software to adopt the new tool. As part of that, we also offer meetups and workshops for people to see demos, discuss ideas with us, get started, and learn best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Current Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have a couple well known developer tools out there, like SQLCipher-for-Android and Orlib. We have many more in development. Here’s a quick overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orlib is an Android library to make it very easy to include Orbot/Tor support in any app. Any app that uses orlib can transparently route all traffic through the Tor network without requiring that the device be rooted. It is a well established project that mostly needs more documentation, developer support, and evangelizing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLCipher is a custom version of the SQLite database that provides easy-to-use, flexible and robust encryption. Guardian Project created SQLCipher-for-Android, which mirrors the standard Android database API, so developers already know how to use it, and need only add support for handling the passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libsqlfs provides a complete virtual disk on top of a SQLCipher database. The virtual disk is encrypted and contained in a single file, which can be easily moved around, copied, shared, etc. It is a standard FUSE filesytem that can work on Android, GNU/Linux, and Mac OS X. libsqlfs is a pre-existing tool that was abandoned by its authors and has been adopted by the Guardian Project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOCipher is a cousin to SQLCipher-for-Android: it provides virtual encrypted disks for Android apps without requiring the device to be rooted. It uses the standard Java API for working with files, so developers already know how to use it, and only need to handle the passwords and opening and closing the virtual disks. It is based on libsqlfs and SQLCipher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard (GnuPG) for Android brings the widespread standard in OpenPGP encryption to Android. GnuPG provides solid encryption for keeping emails and files private, and for verifying that emails and files are who you think they are. GnuPG is built-in to basically every GNU/Linux distro, in GPGTools for Mac OS X and Apple Mail, a plugin for Outlook and Thunderbird, etc. We are working to bring GnuPG to Android to make it the cornerstone of Android encryption like it is elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ffmpeg is a popular, widespread framework for transcoding and filtering digital videos. It has been essential to our apps ObscuraCam, InformaCam, and Murrow/StoryMaker. We want to now work to make it dead simple for developers to build their own apps on it. We are also extending it to provide a full framework for audio and image redaction, metadata management, and encryption of sensitive parts of the media. This will make it easy for media app developers to build in privacy to their own apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Shared Security Tokens (PSST) is our project to tackle the issues of digital identity and crypto key management. This is perhaps the most vexing issue facing deployment of secure mobile devices today. Public-key cryptography (HTTPS/SSL, OTR chat, PGP email, etc.) is a proven, powerful way to validate digital identity while keeping the contents private. Their cryptographic keys essentially become their proof of identity, and as such that identity must be portable across computing contexts (mobile devices, desktop environments, etc.). An interoperable standard and associated developer libraries needs to be developed to make possible a portable and secure solution for establishing one’s identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always Secure Messaging (“AweSoMe”) is a collaborative effort to build interoperable, open-source, secure messaging applications, that work from mobile to mobile, as well as mobile to web. In particular, the goal is to create an extremely usable and high quality experience, that simultaneously supports one-to-one and one-to-many (group) end-to-end secure messaging communications across multiple platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bazaar provides the last piece of this puzzle: easy, secure and private distribution of software. Debian GNU/Linux has proven that decentralized software stores can work well. Google Play and the Apple App Store both provide excellent examples for how to make it easy to find and distribute apps, but are often blocked or not available in many parts of the world. Bazaar combines all of these ideas to provide a decentralized, peer-to-peer app store that makes it easy to find and distribute apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Settings Add-on for Firefox Mobile</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/11/08/proxy-settings-add-on-for-firefox-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 03:43:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/11/08/proxy-settings-add-on-for-firefox-mobile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest beta of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.com/en-US/mobile/&#34;&gt;Firefox 4 on Android&lt;/a&gt; is proving to be very usable, stable and an increasingly viable alternative to the built-in webkit browser. However, it is unfortunately lacking the ability to manually configure proxy settings through any sort of standard user interface. This is a common problem for Android, which also lacks the ability to set browser or system wide proxy settings. This has caused real issues for us with getting &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; (aka “Tor on Android”) to work for un-rooted Android devices, because for routing through Tor to work, you must be able to set the HTTP or SOCKS proxy settings. Why this &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=1273&#34;&gt;very basic feature&lt;/a&gt; keeps getting missed or ignored is a mystery to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, we at the Guardian Project have created a very simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/?browse=featured&#34;&gt;Firefox add-on&lt;/a&gt; which exposes the proxy settings through a simple, graphical options menu. This means any user can easily set the HTTP and SOCKS proxy settings for Firefox, enabling access to web browsing on networks which require a proxy to access the we. This also means, that users can connect Firefox to Orbot on Android 2.x devices and &lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;browse the web using the Tor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-579 alignnone&#34; title=&#34;fennecoptions&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;792&#34; height=&#34;499&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions.png 792w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions-300x189.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, it must be stressed that this not a full port of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.torproject.org/torbutton/index.html.en&#34;&gt;TorButton add-on&lt;/a&gt;, and does not provide for strong anonymity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working on porting TorButton to Firefox mobile, so stay tuned for that release. In addition, while there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/search/?q=proxy&amp;amp;cat=all&amp;amp;lver=any&amp;amp;pid=1&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;pp=20&amp;amp;lup=&amp;amp;advanced=&#34;&gt;many, many Proxy add-ons for Firefox&lt;/a&gt; on the desktop, none have been ported to mobile. We hope this small release will encourage one or more of them to port those add-ons to a mobile version. For now though, if you are eager to play and really need to access the web via a proxy, you can find the “ProxyMob” add-on at the following URL. Just navigate to this address from your Firefox mobile browser, and it will handle the add-on installation process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/proxymob&#34;&gt;http://tinyurl.com/proxymob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
aka: &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/proxymob-addon-0.0.5.xpi&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/proxymob-addon-0.0.5.xpi&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/proxymob-addon-0.0.5.xpi.asc&#34;&gt;gpg sig&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all of our work, this is open-source, and we encourage you to contribute to and improve upon what we’ve done via our Github project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/ProxyMob&#34;&gt;https://github.com/guardianproject/ProxyMob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orbot Update: New Setup Wizard at Startup</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/07/29/orbot-update-new-setup-wizard-at-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 17:17:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/07/29/orbot-update-new-setup-wizard-at-startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been working away at the 0.0.9 release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; over the last few months, and have put a decent amount of effort into usability. Specifically, we hoped to better communicate to users what it means to run Tor on your Android phone. In addition, we wanted to clearly lay out how the various configuration options help to improve your mobile web anonymity and ability to circumvent web filters and tracking by your mobile service provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshots below are what you see the first time you install and run Orbot, and also whenever you open the “Help” menu. One important thing to point out is that Orbot can run with or without root, and our setup UI responds to having the capability or not accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately our goal is to provide a useful bootstrap experience for novice and advanced users alike. We welcome your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;gallery-3&#39; class=&#39;gallery galleryid-488 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-thumbnail&#39;&gt;
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-1.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-1-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-489&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-1-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-1-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-489&#39;&gt;
      permissions… we actually will only be asking for INTERNET – so don’t mind the “phone status” permission
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-2.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-2-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-490&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-2-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-2-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-490&#39;&gt;
      Your basic install screen
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-3.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-3-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-491&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-3-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-3-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-491&#39;&gt;
      A friendly welcome
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-4.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-4-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-492&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-4-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-4-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-492&#39;&gt;
      About Orbot!
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-5.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-5-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-493&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-5-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-5-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-493&#39;&gt;
      we ask nicely to get root permissions, if possible
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-7.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-7-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-495&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-7-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-7-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-495&#39;&gt;
      if the user doesn’t have root, we make sure they understand the implications
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-8.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-8-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-496&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-8-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-8-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-496&#39;&gt;
      Offer direct downloads of Orbot/Tor enabled apps
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.5.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.5-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-497&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.5-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.5-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-497&#39;&gt;
      (Root only) choose whether to “Torify All” or choose app by app
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.6.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.6-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-498&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.6-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.6-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-498&#39;&gt;
      (Root only) Select to send all network traffic through Tor
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.7.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.7-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-499&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.7-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.7-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-499&#39;&gt;
      (Root only) Select which apps you want to route through Tor
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-500&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-9-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-500&#39;&gt;
      This is the final step
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-10.png&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-10-150x150.png&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-501&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-10-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/orbot-10-64x64.png 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
    
    &lt;dd class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-501&#39;&gt;
      We’ve got root!
    &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tor on a Tablet</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/05/25/tor-on-a-tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 16:22:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/05/25/tor-on-a-tablet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently acquired a Moons e-7001 “iRobot” tablet which runs Android 1.5. This device is also known as the “aPad”. It is a very basic iPad-clone, though honestly, it can’t really compare with the iPad in terms of quality of screen, build or general use. However, it does only cost $185, supports USB host mode, has a built-in camera, and it is running Android, an actual open-source operating system! It should also be pointed out that you can also now get the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Archos-Home-Tablet-Android-Black/dp/B003COZM2C/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=electronics&amp;amp;qid=1274748337&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Archos 7 Android tablet&lt;/a&gt;, which is basically the same thing as this, from Amazon for $199.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we purchased one of these was to be able to tangibly have Orbot (aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/docs/android.html&#34;&gt;Tor on Android&lt;/a&gt;) running on a tablet “MID” style device. Since it is running Android 1.5, we were able to easily do this using Orbot and Orweb together without requiring the device to be rooted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here you have it – Tor on a Tablet, the AnonaPad, GuardianSlate, OrTab, OnionBook, or whatever other clever name you may want to come up with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;gallery-2&#39; class=&#39;gallery galleryid-314 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-thumbnail&#39;&gt;
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3222.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3222-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3222-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3222-64x64.jpg 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3208.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3208-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3208-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3208-64x64.jpg 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3209.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3209-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3209-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3209-64x64.jpg 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3214.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3214-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3214-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3214-64x64.jpg 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3215.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3215-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3215-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3215-64x64.jpg 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3220.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3220-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3220-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_3220-64x64.jpg 64w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
  
  &lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
