<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fennec on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/fennec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fennec on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 03:43:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/fennec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Settings Add-on for Firefox Mobile</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/11/08/proxy-settings-add-on-for-firefox-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 03:43:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/11/08/proxy-settings-add-on-for-firefox-mobile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest beta of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.com/en-US/mobile/&#34;&gt;Firefox 4 on Android&lt;/a&gt; is proving to be very usable, stable and an increasingly viable alternative to the built-in webkit browser. However, it is unfortunately lacking the ability to manually configure proxy settings through any sort of standard user interface. This is a common problem for Android, which also lacks the ability to set browser or system wide proxy settings. This has caused real issues for us with getting &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; (aka “Tor on Android”) to work for un-rooted Android devices, because for routing through Tor to work, you must be able to set the HTTP or SOCKS proxy settings. Why this &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=1273&#34;&gt;very basic feature&lt;/a&gt; keeps getting missed or ignored is a mystery to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, we at the Guardian Project have created a very simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/?browse=featured&#34;&gt;Firefox add-on&lt;/a&gt; which exposes the proxy settings through a simple, graphical options menu. This means any user can easily set the HTTP and SOCKS proxy settings for Firefox, enabling access to web browsing on networks which require a proxy to access the we. This also means, that users can connect Firefox to Orbot on Android 2.x devices and &lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;browse the web using the Tor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-579 alignnone&#34; title=&#34;fennecoptions&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;792&#34; height=&#34;499&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions.png 792w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/fennecoptions-300x189.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, it must be stressed that this not a full port of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.torproject.org/torbutton/index.html.en&#34;&gt;TorButton add-on&lt;/a&gt;, and does not provide for strong anonymity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working on porting TorButton to Firefox mobile, so stay tuned for that release. In addition, while there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/search/?q=proxy&amp;amp;cat=all&amp;amp;lver=any&amp;amp;pid=1&amp;amp;sort=&amp;amp;pp=20&amp;amp;lup=&amp;amp;advanced=&#34;&gt;many, many Proxy add-ons for Firefox&lt;/a&gt; on the desktop, none have been ported to mobile. We hope this small release will encourage one or more of them to port those add-ons to a mobile version. For now though, if you are eager to play and really need to access the web via a proxy, you can find the “ProxyMob” add-on at the following URL. Just navigate to this address from your Firefox mobile browser, and it will handle the add-on installation process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/proxymob&#34;&gt;http://tinyurl.com/proxymob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
aka: &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/proxymob-addon-0.0.5.xpi&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/proxymob-addon-0.0.5.xpi&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/proxymob-addon-0.0.5.xpi.asc&#34;&gt;gpg sig&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all of our work, this is open-source, and we encourage you to contribute to and improve upon what we’ve done via our Github project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/ProxyMob&#34;&gt;https://github.com/guardianproject/ProxyMob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
