<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wind on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/wind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wind on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/wind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution in Depth: Mirrors as a Source of Resiliency</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/07/distribution-in-depth-mirrors-as-a-source-of-resiliency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/07/distribution-in-depth-mirrors-as-a-source-of-resiliency/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;distribution.png&#34; alt=&#34;distribution&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to get the apps and media, even when the Internet is expensive, slow, blocked, or even completely unavailable.  Censorshop circumvention tools from ShadowSocks to Pluggable Transports can evade blocks.  Sneakernets and &lt;a href=&#34;https://briarproject.org/how-it-works/&#34;&gt;nearby connections&lt;/a&gt; work without any network connection.   Hosting on Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) can make hosting drastically cheaper and faster.  One method that is often overlooked these days is repository mirrors.  Distribution setups that support mirrors give users the flexibility to find a huge array of solutions for problems when things are not just working.  Mirrors on local networks can be much cheaper. Mirrors in specific countries are often not blocked or filtered.  Mirrors can be copied onto portable storage and moved to where the users are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repository mirrors are mostly associated with free software distribution.  Every major GNU/Linux distro, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/mirror/list&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; to Red Hat, is available via mirrors.  Software collections like Android/Java&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://maven.apache.org/guides/mini/guide-mirror-settings.html&#34;&gt;Maven Central&lt;/a&gt; and Python&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install/#install-index-url&#34;&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt; support mirrors as well.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/docs/Running_a_Mirror/&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure is also based on mirrors.  Free software repositories have proven so valuable, that there generally are mirrors maintained around the world.  Local mirrors of popular free software repositories are available in all continents, and most countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirrors also add conceptual complexity to distribution. Users who are used to internet services that work without configuration could easily find discussion of mirrors confusing.  Mirrors also mean that more pieces of infrastructure need to be maintained.  When systems with mirrors are well organized, then this work can be broken into small chunks and widely shared, often even by volunteers, so that the overall system is resilient and maintainable even given limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:InternetPopulation2011_DeSabbata_Graham_OII.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;InternetPopulation2011_DeSabbata_Graham_OII.png&#34; alt=&#34;Internet Population&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-repository-mirror-system&#34;&gt;Building a repository mirror system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good mirroring support must disconnect how the data is downloaded from how the data integrity is maintained.  That means data can come from anywhere, and still be properly verified before installing it.  This is usually done with an index of files signed by public key cryptography.  A system built on HTTPS and trusted servers is a bad candidate for mirroring.  This separation of concerns is a key property of distribution systems that allows them to be flexible while still providing fully verified distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, it must be easy for users to configure the mirrors in use.  First and foremost, mirrors should work without the user doing anything.  To ensure flexibility, they must be easy to add and remove, and new mirrors must be easy to find.  Both end users and repository operators should be able to specify mirrors to be used.  Legal requirements must also be heeded: the whole system should not require any service that might be legally questionable in any relevant jurisdiction.  EU users need GDPR-compliant services.  If the aim is to distribute in China, then the system cannot require Google Cloud Services.  Instead, it should also be able to go through cloud services available in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many CDN providers around the world.  Many of these are in effect a mirroring service since they are pointed at a website hosted elsewhere, then they just cache the files.  Some of them are so cheap, that files can be hosted there without signing up.  This happens usually via source code repositories like GitHub.  For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rawgit.org/&#34;&gt;RawGit&lt;/a&gt; is an automatic, CloudFlare-based CDN for any public repository on GitHub, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com&#34;&gt;gitlab.com&lt;/a&gt;, or BitBucket.  These fronting services are so cheap because they are basically only serving cached files.  Each given URL is set to be served from the cache for a long time, up to a year, without checking whether the file has changed.  In order to taken advantage of this kind of CDN setup, the repository must be designed accordingly.  That means each unique file should have a unchanging, unique URL.  There are two techniques for doing that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For software, include the version in the filename or path, e.g. &lt;code&gt;org.fdroid.fdroid_1001000.apk&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;1.10/F-Droid.apk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For media, include the hash of the file in the filename or path, e.g. &lt;code&gt;icon_CQLCGleZNBzDPRNp1ADs121TecVHFmUbe-Au-4qXF08=.png&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;CQLCGleZNBzDPRNp1ADs121TecVHFmUbe-Au-4qXF08=/icon.png&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirrors are like all internet services in that there are always potential &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/&#34;&gt;privacy leaks&lt;/a&gt;.  To protect users&amp;rsquo; privacy, it is important to be conscious of the potential metadata that is visible in the system, and who can get that data.  For example, transport encryption (TLS, HTTPS, etc) should be used even though the signed index provides strong integrity checks in order to reduce metadata leaks.  Even with transport encryption, the oeprators of the mirrors themselves will still see the metadata.  When there are individual files that users can download, the mirror operators could see which user is downloading which file.  Metadata like the description of a movie file or the icon of an app will give away the user&amp;rsquo;s interests.  When possible, this metadata should be grouped to reduce the detail in the metadata.  Icons can be downloaded in random groups of 10.  Text descriptions can be grouped by language or other more neutral grouping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-f-droid&#34;&gt;Example: F-Droid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid repositories, aka &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;repos&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, are collections of packages, mostly Android APK app files, which are organized in a single folder. That folder contains a signed index file which lists the entire contents and related metadata.  This includes descriptive texts, available graphics, etc.  This file structure is not tied to any particular transport method as long as the &lt;em&gt;repo/&lt;/em&gt; folder and index remain intact.  The client keeps the public key of the index signature locally, and uses that to verify the index file.  The index also includes a list of URLs pointing to official mirrors.  By default, repositories are served over HTTPS, but nothing in the repository structure requires that.  This allows F-Droid to use repositories from SD Cards and USB OTG thumb drives using &lt;code&gt;file:///&lt;/code&gt; URLs.  A mirror is then simply defined: a mirror is any available copy of a repository.  The mirror need not even be a complete copy, as long as the index and desired packages are present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid automatically handles much of the process of using the mirrors.  Each &lt;em&gt;repo&lt;/em&gt; can include a list of official mirrors in the index.  The F-Droid Android client will automatically use all of the official mirrors, automatically choosing one when downloading based on which is working.  The mirrors are still completely configurable.  Anyone can create their own mirror, either via the &lt;code&gt;fdroid mirror&lt;/code&gt; command for any &lt;em&gt;repo&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/docs/Running_a_Mirror/&#34;&gt;via &lt;em&gt;rsync&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;f-droid.org&lt;/em&gt;.  And F-Droid user can then &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/tutorials/add-repo/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;subscribe&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; to any mirror via the mirror URL.  Users can also disable any mirror from the repo&amp;rsquo;s details screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;

&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; style=&#34;max-width:60%&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;add-mirror.png&#34; alt=&#34;add-mirror.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;add-mirror.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;h4&gt;click a link to add a new mirror&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; style=&#34;max-width:60%&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;disable-mirrors.png&#34; alt=&#34;disable-mirrors.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;disable-mirrors.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;h4&gt;disabling selected mirrors&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/fdroid/&#34;&gt;Guardian Project&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;repo&lt;/em&gt; includes many of these mirroring channels: Mayfirst webserver, Tor Onion Service, Amazon AWS S3, GitHub Pages, GitHub Raw (Fastly), gitlab.com (Google Cloud), GitCDN/RawGit/Cloudflare and of course SD Card and USB OTG drives.  F-Droid &lt;em&gt;repos&lt;/em&gt; are particularly well suited to this kind of mirroring since the files are available via URLs that do not change.  CDNs cache files by URL.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34;&gt;f-droid.org&lt;/a&gt; is mirrored by free software mirror providers around the world, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirrors.tuna.tsinghua.edu.cn/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fdroid.tetaneutral.net/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ftp.fau.de/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;Germany&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plug-mirror.rcac.purdue.edu/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;Indiana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fdroid-mirror.calyxinstitute.org/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ftp.osuosl.org/pub/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;Oregon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.librelabucm.org/fdroid/repo/&#34;&gt;Spain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ftp.lysator.liu.se/pub/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;Sweden&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lysator7eknrfl47rlyxvgeamrv7ucefgrrlhk7rouv3sna25asetwid.onion/pub/fdroid/repo&#34;&gt;Tor Onion Service&lt;/a&gt;.  Local mirrors mean faster, more reliable, and cheaper access, especially for people in places like China, where government policy and infrastructure design works to downplay access to foreign networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/06/02/building-the-most-private-app-store/&#34;&gt;Extensive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/docs/Security_Model/&#34;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; has gone into making F-Droid the most private &amp;ldquo;app store&amp;rdquo; for mobile devices, including minimizing the potential metadata leaks.  There is a single index file for all the packages, and it includes all the translations.  So all users fetch the exact same index file, so the &lt;em&gt;f-droid.org&lt;/em&gt; and mirror servers cannot infer from the index which language the device is using.  The app icons and screenshsots are downloaded on demand, so that is one metadata leak.  F-Droid requires either HTTPS or Tor Onion Service transport encryption to minimize such leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid &lt;em&gt;repos&lt;/em&gt; default to keeping 3 releases per package available. Also, the index is not tied to the mirror, the F-Droid Android client will happily fetch the index from one mirror, and each package from other mirrors.  F-Droid will keep searching all the mirrors for a package until it finds it, so a mirror can be out of date yet still useful. Today&amp;rsquo;s update might only bring a couple new files, even if a mirror is delayed, it will still have all the previous content.  That property ensures that distribution is not an all-or-nothing prospect.  Instead, it can still transparently provide some level of access when there are troubles with the internet.  This makes lots of different kinds of relibility problems look quite similar from the point of view of the F-Droid client app: outages, network troubles, blocks, and even working around expensive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone with a Raspberry Pi with an SD Card can be a local mirror server, even if they have irregular access to the internet.  The Raspberry Pi can be easily brought to unmetered WiFi, then synced up with the main &lt;em&gt;repo&lt;/em&gt; using &lt;code&gt;fdroid mirror&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt;.  Then when it is brought back to its home, the local users can get apps and updates even if there is no active internet connection in the area.  This also works with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USB_On-The-Go&#34;&gt;USB OTG&lt;/a&gt; flash drives.  A whole &lt;em&gt;repo&lt;/em&gt; can be zipped up and broadcasted using a service like the satellite TV &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://knapsackforhope.org/&#34;&gt;Knapsack for Hope&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; service, their app already makes it easy to decode the broadcast and write it to USB OTG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; style=&#34;max-width:60%&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;usb-otg-mirror.png&#34; alt=&#34;usb-otg-mirror.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;usb-otg-mirror.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;h4&gt;A f-droid.org mirror available via USB OTG drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-ubuntu&#34;&gt;Example: Ubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu uses a system of mixed mirrors and CDNs &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/Mirrors#Country_mirror_requirements&#34;&gt;based on standardized domain names&lt;/a&gt;, which includes some level of &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/DynamicMirrorDecisions&#34;&gt;automatic setup&lt;/a&gt; based on measurement.  The domain name is &lt;code&gt;COUNTRYCODE.archive.ubuntu.com&lt;/code&gt;.  During install, the user chooses the country to set up the device accordingly.  The mirror is then set to use the mirror domain name based on that country, e.g. a device set to Uganda would use &lt;code&gt;ug.archive.ubuntu.com&lt;/code&gt;.  When a country-specific mirrors exists, that domain name points to it.  Ubuntu has over 50 in-country mirrors. Otherwise, any other &lt;code&gt;*.archive.ubuntu.com&lt;/code&gt; domain name points to a mirror running on a major CDN.  This setup allows Ubuntu to change the mirror server-side setup separately from the user&amp;rsquo;s selection on their device.  Additionally, users are then still free to edit the configuration and use any URL that they want, including pointing to local media like CDROMs and thumb drives.  And anyone can &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/Mirrors&#34;&gt;create their own mirror&lt;/a&gt; without first getting permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;select best server&#34; src=&#34;select-best-server.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Select-Ubuntu-Mirror-Archive.png&#34; alt=&#34;Select-Ubuntu-Mirror-Archive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing offline maps with F-Droid and OsmAnd</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/11/28/managing-offline-maps-with-f-droid-and-osmand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/11/28/managing-offline-maps-with-f-droid-and-osmand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When disaster strikes, our mobile devices can provide us with many
tools to deal with a wide variety of problems.  The internet is not
available in every corner of the planet, and large scale outages
happen.  Digital maps allow us to carry detailed maps of the entire
planet in our pockets.  And the good map apps allow the user to
download entire regions to the device so that they operate without
internet at all.  Unfortunately, the big map apps from Google and
Apple provide limited offline capabilities.  For example, it is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://annoyingtechnicaldetails.wordpress.com/2020/09/23/cannot-easily-redistribute-downloaded-offline-files-for-google-maps/&#34;&gt;not possible&lt;/a&gt;
to share offline data from one device to another.  Online maps are
also a major privacy leak, since location data is the most sensitive
data.  With online maps, the service operator sees each tile of the
map that you look at, each time you look at it, as well as all the
locations you search for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osmand.net/&#34;&gt;OsmAnd&lt;/a&gt; is a great map app for offline usage,
since offline usage is the primary mode of operation.  It lets you
download entire regions to your device, then search and navigate
without any network connection at all. This is also a big win for
privacy: In offline mode, OsmAnd can only see which regions you have
downloaded, and nothing else.  OsmAnd provides private, resilient
services. The maps will work as long as your device is working.  The
maps are still usable even if GPS is unavailable, since they can be
searched and operated with only your fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid is the most private and flexible mobile distribution system,
so we recently worked to make it a lot easier to ship OsmAnd map files
via F-Droid repos.  That means that entire countries can be made
available through the F-Droid distribution methods, including offline
methods like mirrors on USB-OTG drives and local repos on a Raspberry
Pi that provides the WiFi connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see an example of this in action, try adding our new
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject-wind.s3.amazonaws.com/fdroid/repo?fingerprint=182CF464D219D340DA443C62155198E399FEC1BC4379309B775DD9FC97ED97E1&#34;&gt;Wind Offline repo&lt;/a&gt;
to F-Droid, and look for the &amp;ldquo;OsmAnd&amp;rdquo; category.  The whole repo is
managed by scripts, which is available on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/guardianproject/wind-repo/&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by the prize money from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wirelesschallenge.mozilla.org/#winners&#34;&gt;Mozilla WINS&lt;/a&gt; competition as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/code/wind/&#34;&gt;Wind&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind is a Mozilla &amp; National Science Foundation Grand Prize Winner</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2018/09/26/wind-is-a-mozilla-national-science-foundation-grand-prize-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 10:54:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2018/09/26/wind-is-a-mozilla-national-science-foundation-grand-prize-winner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 14th, members of the Guardian Project team traveled to Mountain View to compete in the final round of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wirelesschallenge.mozilla.org/&#34;&gt;Wireless Innovation for a Networked Society (WINS) Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. We learned in July that our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2018/07/20/our-wind-project-is-a-mozilla-nsf-challenge-finalist/&#34;&gt;Wind  project was a finalist&lt;/a&gt;, and we now had the opportunity to compete for one of the grand prizes, in a TED-meets-SharkTank style event, at Mozilla HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wind&#34;&gt;Wind&lt;/a&gt; is a network designed for opportunistic communication and sharing of local knowledge that provides off-grid services for everyday people, using the mobile devices they already have. In the Wind network, Chime is the hyperlink, but one that exists in time and space, discoverable through beacon broadcasts and human-to-human sharing. All of this is powered by free and open-source software, running on readily available consumer hardware, and can be deployed at little to no cost, in a very short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fGuiy3rlOVQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:23px&#34;&gt;
  Yesterday, on the Mozilla blog, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2018/09/25/1-6-million-to-connect-unconnected-americans-our-nsf-wins-competition-grand-prize-winners/&#34;&gt;winners were announced.&lt;/a&gt; We are honored to be one of them, claiming the 4th Grand Prize.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;has-background has-pale-cyan-blue-background-color&#34;&gt;
  You can watch our 5 minute power presentation below, or jump to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wind/&#34;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/wind&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; for more detail. We have also published our entire &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/wind/blob/master/Mozilla%20NSF%20Off-Grid%20Challenge_%20Wind.pdf&#34;&gt;Wind Concept Proposal Submission paper.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FOWrappjLsY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are so grateful to be associated not only with the challenge itself, but with all the other impressive finalists and winners. Our work on Wind took quite a different approach than the others, and thus fills some niches and gaps not addressed by the other systems. We believe there are numerous opportunities for collaboration, and looking forward to helping fulfill the complete vision set forth by the WINS challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will use the funding to continue development work on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sabzo/ayanda&#34;&gt;Ayanda&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/chimeapp&#34;&gt;Chime&lt;/a&gt; apps, protocols and libraries. We will also support partners like F-Droid, OpenArchive, LibraryBox to help promote adoption. We will travel and work in the field, finding communities in need both in the U.S., and abroad, who can benefit from a Wind deployment. Lastly, we’ll reach out to colleagues in the humanitarian response communities, to gain feedback and build awareness about our suite of tools and capabilities.&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/wind_v3-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-13904&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/wind_v3-5.jpg 1275w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/wind_v3-5-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/wind_v3-5-300x300.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/wind_v3-5-768x768.jpg 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/wind_v3-5-1024x1024.jpg 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1275px) 100vw, 1275px&#34; /&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some thanks are definitely in order for members of the Guardian Project team and community. Hans’ leadership and collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/&#34;&gt;F-Droid.org team&lt;/a&gt; over the last few years, provided innovative and fully functional foundation for the “Off Grid App Store”. In particular, his work implementing USB sharing with F-Droid (see the video above for that in action), enabled a true sneakernet mode, that was a key part of our demo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/disaster_1-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-14002&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/disaster_1-1.jpg 1920w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/disaster_1-1-300x182.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/disaster_1-1-768x466.jpg 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/disaster_1-1-1024x622.jpg 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&#34; /&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://okthanks.com/&#34;&gt;Okthanks&lt;/a&gt;, our design team, created amazing &lt;a href=&#34;https://okthanks.com/blog/peronas-latin-america&#34;&gt;user-centered foundations, personas and methods&lt;/a&gt; as our guide, and that helped our video presentations turn out great. Rosa and Fabiola ensured we stayed true to communities in Latin America who could benefit from this effort. Fabiola also was a fantastic presenter in front of the judges (again, to the video!). Early on, David conceived of a geocaching based concept that led to the Chime protocol, and which we plan to keep exploring. &lt;a href=&#34;http://sabelo.io/about/&#34;&gt;Sabelo&lt;/a&gt; pushed forward our work on our nearby communications with his &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sabzo/ayanda&#34;&gt;Ayanda software library&lt;/a&gt;. Natalie and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open-archive.org/&#34;&gt;OpenArchive&lt;/a&gt; team let us prototype support for nearby media publishing. Jason and his &lt;a href=&#34;http://librarybox.us/&#34;&gt;LibraryBoxen&lt;/a&gt; provided some early inspiration for how an off-grid system can be useful in everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, our sincere thanks to Mozilla and the National Science Foundation for this wonderful opportunity and financial support. Here’s to a more Windy future for the unconnected world ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our “Wind” project is a Mozilla-NSF challenge finalist!</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2018/07/20/our-wind-project-is-a-mozilla-nsf-challenge-finalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 14:28:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2018/07/20/our-wind-project-is-a-mozilla-nsf-challenge-finalist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, we’ve been working on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wind/&#34;&gt;Wind network concept&lt;/a&gt;, as a nearby, local, off-grid companion, or alternative, to the Web. This year, we decided to participate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wirelesschallenge.mozilla.org/&#34;&gt;Wireless Innovation Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, sponsored by Mozilla and the National Science Foundation. Today, it was announced that we are a finalist in, as they put it, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2018/07/19/a-science-fair-with-1-6-million-in-prizes/&#34;&gt;“A Science Fair with $1.6 Million in Prizes”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video below to learn more about Wind, or jump right over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wind/&#34;&gt;Wind project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/fGuiy3rlOVQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;_&lt;br /&gt;
When disaster strikes, connectivity becomes difficult. Information can save your life, guiding you to safety and services. Networks today are fragile and easy overloaded. There has not been enough investment in the many other possible nets, that may be better suited for situations where connections to the global internet are not available or affordable. The potential in radios, sensors and processing available in the cheapest of smartphones and routers are not fully utilized or realized._&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
