<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 17:43:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Way to Visit Strongbox on a Phone</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/05/16/the-only-way-to-visit-strongbox-on-a-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 17:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/05/16/the-only-way-to-visit-strongbox-on-a-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; magazine just launched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/closeread/2013/05/introducing-strongbox-anonymous-document-sharing-tool.html&#34;&gt;Strongbox&lt;/a&gt;, a whistleblower submission system that’s hosted on a hidden website. There’s only one way to access the hidden site on a phone or tablet, and that’s with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.browser&amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Orweb app&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s a simple breakdown of how to do securely and anonymously blow the whistle, explained in an interactive tutorial:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3719  aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy19&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19-199x300.png&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19.png 400w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Visit &lt;a title=&#34;strongbox tutorial&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&lt;/a&gt; for an interactive tutorial on using Strongbox on your phone.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The website exists as a hidden site on what is widely known as the darknet, since you are going there hidden or “in the dark.” Instead of a .com, .org, or .info address (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;) the sites like Strongbox show up with a .onion. And like you need a web browser to go to a .com web address, you need a darknet browser to go to a .onion darknet address. On a mobile, we make the most secure and anonymous darknet &amp; web browser, Orweb. And if you want to get to strongbox on your phone, we’re the only way to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  To browse, you’ll need our &lt;a title=&#34;orweb&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orweb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orweb&lt;/a&gt; app. It’s currently only available for Android and you can &lt;a title=&#34;Orweb anonymous browser&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.browser &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;get it here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have another type of phone or tablet, unfortunately you’ll have to use a computer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  For Orweb to be anonymous and give you access to the darknet .onion addresses, you’ll need to enable onion routing with our &lt;a title=&#34;orbot&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; plugin. This plugin gives Orweb and other compatible apps (like our &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.otr.app.im&#34;&gt;Gibberbot secure chat&lt;/a&gt;  for Facebook, Google, &amp; Jabber) the ability to send web traffic through the darknet, thus avoiding tracking as well as blocking. You can &lt;a title=&#34;Orbot on Android&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.android  &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;download Orbot here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the official app of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://TorProject.org&#34;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt;, which develops the onion routing protocol, on Android.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Once both are installed, you just need to go to this hidden site: &lt;a title=&#34;Strongbox Onion Site&#34; href=&#34;http://tnysbtbxsf356hiy.onion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://tnysbtbxsf356hiy.onion&lt;/a&gt; . Make sure that you’re using the Orweb browser and that Orbot is running. From there, you can easily submit messages to The New Yorker. Unfortunately you can’t yet submit files to them through the phone just yet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Overall, this is an exciting step in the right direction. With an increase in tracking and crackdown on political dissidents and whistleblowers around the world, there need to be safe and trusted ways of sharing information that has the potential of saving lives and making the world a better place. &lt;a title=&#34;the new yorker magazine&#34; href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most trusted journalistic outfits in the world and it will be interesting to follow how they understand and vet information that comes in from anonymous sources. It will be a lesson for the entire privacy community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/PihUXCmJzW/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3730 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;On the Internet, algorithms can infer you&#39;re a dog.&#34; alt=&#34;Dog Algorithm&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-300x300.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm.jpg 612w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  At the same time, it’s not yet a trusted technology. While the code is accessible and &lt;a href=&#34;http://deaddrop.github.io/&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; it is unclear whether it’s a full version of the DeadDrop code that it came from or a fork of it. It also hasn’t been audited yet. Already, we’re seeing issues popping up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deaddrop/deaddrop/issues&#34;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully it will be fully vetted as a solution and stand up to the ambitious and crucial claims that it is able “to provide you with a greater degree of anonymity and security than afforded by conventional e-mail.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  In the months before January, I worked a few seats down from Aaron Swartz in the ThoughtWorks offices. Since those shocking days, it’s been inspiring to continue to see his legacy. I spoke with him a bunch of times about using technology to introduce truly disruptive techniques for empowering people whose rights were otherwise being trampled. At the time, we were working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbelinsky.com/crowdring/&#34;&gt;Crowdring&lt;/a&gt;, an intiative from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.therules.org/&#34;&gt;/The Rules&lt;/a&gt;. And we spoke about the power of leveraging telephony to give voice so widely, and the trade off of handing over personally identifiable information. He recognized the need for constantly evolving and shifting tactics and was expert at integrating that into both strategy and code. It’s an honor to continue to work with him now, and with the rest of the open source community as we all contribute code and ideas to make the world better.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Having just won the Knight News Challenge for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2013/01/27/informacam-wins-knight-news-challenge/&#34;&gt;Informacam project&lt;/a&gt;, we’re excited at the growing interest from the world of journalism in making sure that sources are kept truly secure and anonymous in the digital age. We’re working to build our whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=6502754515281796553&#34;&gt;suite of tools&lt;/a&gt; to make it easier and better to do so. If you want to reach out to us, anonymously or otherwise, to &lt;a title=&#34;Guardian Contact&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/ &#34;&gt;let us know how we can help&lt;/a&gt;, you can use Orbot and Tor to do so over any of these methods. We look forward to it!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Awareness Party</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/04/26/security-awareness-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 09:05:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/04/26/security-awareness-party/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the security world, there’s a pesky belief that a tool can either be secure or easy to use, but not both. Some experts also argue that training people to be safe online is too hard and doesn’t accomplish much (see Bruce Schneier’s recent post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/03/security_awaren_1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security Awareness Training&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Without a thoughtful approach, that’s usually how it plays out. But it doesn’t have to be that way! We’re committed to making online security fun to learn and fun to use, and we’re launching a new series of interactive tutorials to make it happen. Consider this post an invitation to our festive Security Awareness Party. &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/home/how-you-can-work-with-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beer is encouraged&lt;/a&gt;, especially if it comes from &lt;a title=&#34;Android-powered beer kegerator&#34; href=&#34;https://kegbot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an Android-powered kegbot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Guardian, security is always our #1 priority. We owe that to our users who rely on us to keep them safe in places like Syria or Iran. But the time we spend on encryption is wasted if users don’t like using our tools, or can’t figure out how they work. We want to make security apps that are enjoyable and easy to use everyday, and don’t take a PHD to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activists in Iran and Syria know firsthand how important technologies like Tor and VPNs are for staying safe online. Our friends and neighbors might not be living under a repressive dictatorship, but that doesn’t mean they couldn’t use a little digital security in their lives. Maybe your nephew wants to get past the block on Facebook at school, or your co-worker wants to watch March Madness at work (make sure she gets that decoy spreadsheet ready). Maybe your friend just wants to send his wife a few…private messages, and he’d rather not have them stored by Google or Verizon. These people might not be pros, but they’re curious and happy to poke around their technology. With a little fun and interactive guidance, they can be well on their way to becoming a power user. Everyone starts somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make life safer and easier for at-risk activists and everyday people alike. That’s why we make accessible and straightforward guides to help you quickly and easily get past censors, internet police, or the office IT department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gibberbot-tutorial&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gibberbot Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newest tutorial is for our secure chat app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.otr.app.im&amp;feature=search_result&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibberbot&lt;/a&gt;. With your Android phone in one hand and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/chatsecurely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibberbot Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; in the other, you can be chatting securely on Google or Facebook chat in minutes! But Google and Facebook can’t even tell what you’re talking about. It’s also more convenient to have all of your chat apps rolled into one so that it doesn’t matter where your friends message you, it still goes to the same place. Gibberbot works even if someone is trying to monitor or block your phone’s communications. If you know another language and would like to contribute, &lt;a title=&#34;Gibberbot Tutorial Transifex Translations&#34; href=&#34;https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/gibberbot-tutorial/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;we’d love your help translating the tutorial (we’ve got English and Tibetan covered)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3291&#34; style=&#34;width: 251px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/chatsecurely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3291&#34; class=&#34; wp-image-3291&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy5&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/galaxy5.png&#34; width=&#34;241&#34; height=&#34;361&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-3291&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    So you want to chat securely?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
     
  &lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Orbot Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    With our Android app Orbot, browsing the web securely and safely through Tor has been a piece of cake for a while now. But we just created &lt;a title=&#34;How to Orbot Tutorial&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/browsefreely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an interactive tutorial to get you started&lt;/a&gt; and show how easy it is circumvent censorship, even if the Google Play Store is blocking direct access to our app.
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    The tools themselves are getting smarter too. A new tool from &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project&#34; href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;, called &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project Obfsproxy&#34; href=&#34;http://www.torproject.org/projects/obfsproxy.html.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pluggable Transports&lt;/a&gt;, hides your Tor traffic to look like regular Internet traffic, making it even easier for Tor users to stay ahead of surveillance and censorship. To use this new tool with Orbot, just follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/How-to-browse-freely-on-your-phone-if-your-internet-is-blocked.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our new one-page guide&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a title=&#34;How to browse freely on your phone if your internet is blocked - Farsi&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/How-to-browse-freely-on-your-phone-if-your-internet-is-blocked-Farsi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in Farsi&lt;/a&gt;) and you’re all set! For a more in-depth guide to using Orbot, watch our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dcf5sh99ze0&#34;&gt;video tutorial&lt;/a&gt; (now in English and Arabic).
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3585&#34; style=&#34;width: 250px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/browsefreely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3585&#34; class=&#34; wp-image-3585&#34; alt=&#34;orbot galaxy s3&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15.png&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;361&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15.png 400w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15-199x300.png 199w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p id=&amp;quot;caption-attachment-3585&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;wp-caption-text&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  So you want to escape censorship?
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      As we continue to grow our team and create new tools, we need your feedback!  Please tell us what we can do to go from security awareness training to a full-on security awareness party. Feel free to leave a comment on this post or tell us how we can make things easier through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/&#34;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt;. You can also let us know about any upcoming parties that we should be attending.
    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;This post is partially a response to Bruce Schneier’s recent piece: &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Schneier Security Awareness Training&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/03/security_awaren_1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Security Awareness Training&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
