<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tracking on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/tracking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tracking on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/tracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search for Ethical Apps: Let&#39;s start with governments</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/09/01/the-search-for-ethical-apps-lets-start-with-governments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/09/01/the-search-for-ethical-apps-lets-start-with-governments/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Governments across the world are moving services to mobile apps.  The vast majority of these apps are only available in the Google Play store or in the Apple App store.  Installing apps from these services requires users to agree to their terms of service.  This means governments require their citizens to sign opaque and privacy invading contracts with foreign Big Tech in order to use digital services.  This feeds ever more into Big Tech data control, filtering, and information bubbles.  There are some exceptions here, like China has multiple app stores that are popular.  Chinese Big Tech also require restrictive terms of service agreements.  Additionally, many of apps are developed by the same firms that are tied into the surveillance capitalism ecosystem.  So they include features that track the end users. The governments are not demanding data transparency, and these firms have not been delivering it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Austria, there is a clear example: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.a-trust.at/en/Handy-Signatur/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Handy Signatur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; app.  Public health insurance providers require this app for people to access their accounts online. Since COVID-19 countermeasures forced schools into online-mode, many public schools have been requiring education apps for students, parents and teachers to connect with and interact with the school. People with the that app can also sign petitions and download vaccination certificates those without have to do much more work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile phone users want to know about what apps are doing with their personal data. Citizens around the world gaining consciousness about these issues.  In order to build public pressure, a critical mass must be aware of these problems. To learn, they must first discover how widespread and entrenched this problem is.  We received funding from &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/project/EthicalApps/&#34;&gt;NLnet&lt;/a&gt; to work on this key area.  This project integrates existing tools and builds a &amp;ldquo;software kit&amp;rdquo; to make it easy to generate data about the apps governments require.  This data will be simple to index so that it citizens and search it and discover the terms their governments are requiring them to take to access e-government services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists are just starting to report on this large and growing problem.  One of the few stories in the European media came recently in the Dutch media: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fd.nl/economie-politiek/1383007/overheid-dwingt-burger-in-de-richting-van-google-en-apple&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overheid dwingt burger in de richting van Google en Apple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (The authorities force citizens towards Google and Apple).  On top of transparency, governments should also ensure that the apps they make and use are available without privacy concerns or corporate control, and that they are not feeding data to companies that control search algorithms and limit user autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first step is to make a repository with the apps related to government services.  This then provides a template for others to do the same in other countries.  Next steps are include pushing organizations and companies to do the same, for example school and banking apps; getting more country repositories and perhaps an EU repository; an helping governments, organizations, and companies set up good distribution options.  Governments should also list F-Droid as an option for getting the apps whenever they mention Google Play and Apple App Store.  And when governments go &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/de.bwl.lfdi.app/&#34;&gt;all&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baden-wuerttemberg.datenschutz.de/lfdi-bw-app-f-droid/&#34;&gt;the way&lt;/a&gt;, they should be lauded. ðŸŽ‰&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work partners to make this come to life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F-Droid provides all the tools for securely publishing and managing app repositories.  F-Droid&amp;rsquo;s community app &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/rfp/-/issues&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/fdroiddata/-/merge_requests&#34;&gt;process&lt;/a&gt; gives us a template to build upon for reviewing all apps in an open way.  F-Droid provides another option that does not lock anyone into any service. There are no terms of service, or even &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2022/02/28/no-user-accounts-by-design.html&#34;&gt;user accounts&lt;/a&gt; to sign up for.  And F-Droid provides a decentralized app distribution ecosystem where anyone can publish their own apps via their own repositories.  If the app is free software, it can be included in the main &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34;&gt;f-droid.org&lt;/a&gt; repository.  Millions of users have installed F-Droid themselves, and companies like Fairphone have shipped devices with F-Droid pre-installed.  Anyone can freely install F-Droid on any Android device.  So F-Droid provides app distribution without being locked into any service, unlike Google Play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ITUJ&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mobilsicher.de/&#34;&gt;mobilsicher&lt;/a&gt; project will provide the user facing service for Germany. Their new repository will serve both as an app distribution provider, and as an example of how other organizations can do the same.  Their impressive &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.app-check.org/app-check&#34;&gt;app-check&lt;/a&gt; review &lt;a href=&#34;https://appcheck.mobilsicher.de/&#34;&gt;platform&lt;/a&gt; is a complete stack for human reviewers to do dynamic analysis, and the database they have built up will be integrated into the review process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt; focuses on tracking embedded in Android apps.  It works based on users requesting apps be reviewed.  It is an important source for this project since it is narrowly focused on detecting and reporting tracking in any Android app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EFF created and maintains &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/EFForg/apkeep&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;apkeep&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the essential tool for getting the actual app files to inspect when the source code is not available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.pithus.org/about/&#34;&gt;Pithus&lt;/a&gt; is a mobile threat intelligence platform for activists, journalists, NGOs, researchers that is a entirely open platform supported and maintained by the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/techlore/plexus&#34;&gt;Techlore Plexus&lt;/a&gt; is a catalog of Android apps that have been reviewed in terms of compatibility with Google-free devices.  For example, they list whether an app requires Google Play Services to run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is not the complete solution for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ethicsinapps.eu/&#34;&gt;ethical apps&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a stepping stone towards the end goal of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://publiccode.eu/&#34;&gt;Public&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/10/public-money-public-code-show-your-support-free-software-europe&#34;&gt;Money&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://publiccode.asia/&#34;&gt;Public&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.okfn.org/2017/09/20/public-money-public-code/&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.  This project will push governments down that road by outlining easier steps to take as they move towards free software: making apps available for public audit, allowing users to install apps without agreeing to any terms of service, etc.  It enables users of free platforms like CalyxOS, LineageOS, Murena, etc. to get access to public services via their mobile devices.  It gives users with Google Play devices the option to disable Google Play, because they can get the apps they need via F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-shape-of-the-work&#34;&gt;The shape of the work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the general idea of what this project will do, as outlined in the funding propsal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-low-maintenance-repositories&#34;&gt;1. Low maintenance repositories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch an F-Droid app repository for a pre-curated set of apps that includes direct download links.  Ongoing software maintenance is covered since it will be integrated into F-Droid&amp;rsquo;s core offering.  App updates, verification, and hosting for the Austria repository are all covered indefinitely by existing Guardian Project/F-Droid efforts.   Once complete, other launches will require only a website and a launch campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate APK download tools like EFF&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;apkeep&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;gplaycli&lt;/em&gt;, etc. into &lt;em&gt;issuebot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build existing automation scripts into user tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link repo publishing with &lt;em&gt;issuebot&lt;/em&gt; posts in GitLab project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-ongoing-review&#34;&gt;2. Ongoing Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build a public facing app review site based on existing F-Droid methods and software.  This would clearly show the technical factors that go into the review process.  Chosen contributors can submit and review apps there, the public can watch.  This needs some software development and a GitLab instance (could be free hosting on gitlab.com).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate review tools from collaborators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync tracking lib data with Exodus Privacy&amp;rsquo;s public database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create canonical F-Droid database of proprietary libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build out data publishing system, so all extracted data is navigable by scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-community-review&#34;&gt;3. Community Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expand software tooling to allow submission and review to more contributors.  Stage 2 should be running smoothly before opening it up to the public. On top of software development, this needs staff or committed volunteer time spent on managing the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;user research on how people think about data extracted from apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UX design for &lt;em&gt;issuebot&lt;/em&gt; to represent extracted data in GitLab tracker posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;document tools so community manager can effectively curate user interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-launch-for-new-organization&#34;&gt;4. Launch for new Organization&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch a campaign for other countries and perhaps EU-wide in partnership with civil society organizations and governments.  This could happen after any of the previous stages, e.g. we could help one government setup a &amp;ldquo;pre-curated&amp;rdquo; website and another organization with a &amp;ldquo;community review&amp;rdquo; setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;total-budget-48-000&#34;&gt;Total Budget: 48,000â‚¬&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re a little late in publishing this post, the project runs from April through September 2022&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New insights into clean analytics</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/03/02/new-insights-into-clean-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/03/02/new-insights-into-clean-analytics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There is a giant problem with the &amp;ldquo;collect it all&amp;rdquo; status quo that pervades on the Internet, this has been clear for a long time.  Tracking people has become so &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ghostery.com/study/&#34;&gt;widespread&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;https://noyb.eu&#34;&gt;organizations&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34;&gt;communities&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org&#34;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacylab.yale.edu/&#34;&gt;university&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacylab.at&#34;&gt;labs&lt;/a&gt; have sprung up dedicated to detecting and publicizing their presence.  Data and analytics are clearly useful for software creators and funders, but they also easily lead to harming people&amp;rsquo;s privacy and well-being.  The past year of work on Clean Insights has clarified our goals to make analytics possible without injuring the very people we aim to serve.  Clean Insights takes the world of data analytics and turns it on its head.   The Clean Insights approach starts with thinking about the data, then choosing only the data that is clearly safe to use.  A user&amp;rsquo;s location, complete device description, or other identifying information is dangerous to gather.  A simple count of how many times a feature was used, or a webpage was visited, can be gathered without links to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some widely known efforts for preserving privacy when doing analytics.  The most famous is perhaps &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_privacy&#34;&gt;differential privacy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, which is used by the US Census Bureau and Apple.  This approach has certain assumptions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is collected and stored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A legal compliance team reviews the legal ramifications of storing PII.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A security team defends the stored data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrative staff handles compliance with data regulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A PR team to do outreach when PII is leaked or spilled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These assumptions are only possible for large, well-funded organizations to fulfill.  Apple already has extensive staff around the world to handle all this.  A dissident newspaper from a small country does not.  Metrics are nonetheless valuable for this dissident newspaper, and for so many other small- and medium-sized organizations.  So Clean Insights starts with different core assumptions that are much more broadly applicable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As little data as possible is stored to reduce the security and leakage risks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stored data does not reveal identities if made public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legal review is reduced as much as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No expensive computing resources required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.accessnow.org/understanding-differential-privacy-matters-digital-rights/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;local-vs-global.png&#34; alt=&#34;Clean Insights vs differential privacy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-out-with-clean-insights&#34;&gt;Starting out with Clean Insights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make the Clean Insights approach work, it must start with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-design/-/blob/master/docs/Clean%20Insights%20-%20%20Feb%202020.pdf&#34;&gt;thinking about the data&lt;/a&gt;.  When setting up metrics and analytics, there is a natural temptation to want to have all the information.  We recommend starting with a very small set of safe measurements as a way to avoid temptation, which might lead the project into hazardous ground.  For web server logs, start by eliminating the PII at the source: use a privacy log configuration for &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2017/06/08/tracking-usage-without-tracking-people/&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2019/04/15/privacy-preserving-analytics.html&#34;&gt;NGINX&lt;/a&gt;. Or use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/webstats.git/tree/src/sanitize.py&#34;&gt;sanitizing script&lt;/a&gt;.  For other scenarios, do a quick review and see what kinds of counts can be easily and safely gathered and start with those.  These are not always easy questions to answer.  What kind of data is available?  What can that data actually tell us?  What are the risks of gathering and storing that data?  One of the safest types of useful data is simple counts of events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many times did an image fail to download?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many conversations do users have open?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many notifications are swiped away without being viewed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long did users wait for Tor to be available?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing analytics tools skirt this step, instead making it easy to gather as much as possible.  They can then rapidly display all sorts of pretty graphs and charts derived from the data.  That points to another key problem with the status quo in metrics: the emphasis on what it easy to represent.  When there is a big pile of &amp;ldquo;collect it all&amp;rdquo; data, there are many views that analytics packages instantly provide.  This is often in conflict with what is actually valuable.  These instant graphs oversimplify things, making it easy to forget that good metrics come from first thinking in depth about the problems that can be solved by metrics.  The old adage is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garbage_in,_garbage_out&#34;&gt;garbage in, garbage out&lt;/a&gt;.  Data about campaigns that is easy to graph may end up leading the effort astray if the valuable metrics are hidden behind lots of pretty charts that distract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One recent example of gathering less data is GitHub: they recently &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;GitHub got rid of cookie consent screen https://www.theregister.com/2020/12/17/github_will_no_longer_present/&#34;&gt;removed all non-essential cookies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.  Their analytics did not need the extra data those cookies provided.  On top of that, using such tracking methods now requires an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/03/state-gdpr-2021-cookie-consent-designers-developers/&#34;&gt;extensive and complicated&lt;/a&gt; design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stored-data-needs-maintenance&#34;&gt;Stored data needs maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large collections of PII are valuable to others besides the software designers.  Databases are routinely stolen.  Tracking is also very useful to attackers to find their targets.  PII is also key for building a social graph,  which can be used to uncover networks of dissidents.  Or sometimes it is just vandalism, and the private data is simply dumped onto the open internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are data regulations like the EU&amp;rsquo;s GDPR.  They require that services turn over all the user&amp;rsquo;s personal data when they request it.  Users can also request that their data be deleted.  Implementing such a system is a chunk of work.  First, figure out up front what data is being either deliberately or inadvertently collected. Then compare that to which data is actually technically required.  From that perspective, it is possible to eliminate the need for a complicated system managing user data by ensuring that PII is not gathered at all.  That can also eliminate unwanted surprises down the line. If you find out after years of running a service that you have been collecting personal data, and users make requests, you might suddenly have a pile of work tracking down all that data and assembling it for delivery to the user.  A bug in that system could then leak data to the wrong user, which can lead to large fines from regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;measure-responsibly&#34;&gt;Measure responsibly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with all these methods to do metrics more responsibly, the question remains: does it need to be measured?  There are working projects that have achieved widespread adoption and usage without tracking users.  Debian and F-Droid have risen while not really gathering many metrics at all.  It is not always a simple question: so many important problems require grant funding to solve.  Yet many funders require extensive metrics.  Digital privacy tools have been largely funded by governments, from Tor to Signal.   Governments should measure and evaluate the projects they are funding.  Governments should also be open about the data they have.  The well-established methods governments use to track projects require lots of data, including PII.  This is a catch-22 when working on software privacy, where the goal is to make it impossible to gather PII.  Government-funded agencies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://opentech.fund&#34;&gt;OTF&lt;/a&gt; funded so many key privacy tools. They put a lot of work into running government-funded grants without requirements to track their users.  This meant pushing back against the US Federal Government&amp;rsquo;s widespread policies about measurement and evaluation.  Using metrics based on safe data sources means projects can provide useful analytics and strong privacy at the same time.  Even when considering that usability and user research are &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/18/usability-the-wonderful-powerful-idea-that-betrayed-us/&#34;&gt;central&lt;/a&gt; to driving the big tracking companies&amp;rsquo; ever expanding data collection, we believe that usability and user research can still be done responsibly.  It is possible to use data to inform UX Design without tracking people at all.  As these techniques are widely adopted, they will also help designers focus on what is most important, thereby delivering better digital experiences for users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability: the wonderful, powerful idea that betrayed us</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/18/usability-the-wonderful-powerful-idea-that-betrayed-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/18/usability-the-wonderful-powerful-idea-that-betrayed-us/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Usability triggered a revolution in computing, taking arcane number crunching machines and making them essential tools in so many human endeavors, even those that have little to do with mathematics.  It turned the traditional design approach on its head.  Initially, experts first built a system then trained users to follow it. User experience design starts with goals, observes how people actually think and act in the relevant context, then designs around those observations, and tests with users to ensure it fits the users&amp;rsquo; understanding.  These ideas were pioneered in the Silicon Valley. This was driven by the unusual confluence of a pioneering spirit and deep engineering skills. That merged with a strong &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Midpeninsula_Free_University&#34;&gt;counter&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homebrew_Computer_Club&#34;&gt;culture&lt;/a&gt; looking to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/People%27s_Computer_Company&#34;&gt;empower&lt;/a&gt; individuals and communities. So much of the best of digital technology has its roots in these ideas.  I feel fortunate to have grown up immersed in these ideas in the Silicon Valley of the 70s and 80s, and still feel that sense of idealism that these ideas can truly make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, &amp;ldquo;making the world a better place&amp;rdquo; has become a catch phrase.  It is now mostly associated with single-minded investors (aka Venture Capitalists) looking to make money as fast as possible. One key piece is inspiring engineers to work non-stop by constantly telling them they are doing something valuable.  Yet another social media doodad monetized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surveillance_capitalism&#34;&gt;surveillance capitalism&lt;/a&gt; is clearly the opposite of making the world a better place.  On top of that, these now well honed ideas of usability are widely used to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2018/2/27/17053758/phone-addictive-design-google-apple&#34;&gt;make&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/2254129.2254137&#34;&gt;digital media&lt;/a&gt; technology &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0180094&#34;&gt;literally&lt;/a&gt; an &lt;a href=&#34;https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2Fadb0000379&#34;&gt;addictive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://rali.bournemouth.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/raian_ali_et_al_2015_refsq_the_emerging_requirement_for_digital_addiction_labels.pdf&#34;&gt;drug&lt;/a&gt; so that wealthy investors can make money even faster.  The rise of usability parallels the rise of surveillance capitalism.  These two support each other and feed off of each other.  Software must be fluid and easy in order to become addictive.  Even if the task at hand is mundane: just keep clicking,  look at the pretty animations, and keep following the likes!  The Silicon Valley &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/&#34;&gt;insiders&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/462049229&#34;&gt;know&lt;/a&gt; how destructive their wares are, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.de/international/silicon-valley-parents-raising-their-kids-tech-free-red-flag-2018-2/&#34;&gt;they ban their own children from using them&lt;/a&gt; while continuing to sell them to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of us who still truly believe in usability as a potential force of good are left feeling used and abused, wondering what on earth we can now do to stop the monster we helped create.  Tools and design processes can be used for both good and evil.  It is important to note that does not mean technology is neutral. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://weaponsofmathdestructionbook.com/&#34;&gt;Algorithms are opinions embedded in code&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.  Basically all &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/thoughts-and-reflections/racial-bias-and-gender-bias-examples-in-ai-systems-7211e4c166a1&#34;&gt;technologies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/machine-bias-risk-assessments-in-criminal-sentencing&#34;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://peopleofcolorintech.com/articles/recognizing-cultural-bias-in-ai/&#34;&gt;a bias&lt;/a&gt;, and the designers of those technologies have power to affect those biases.  When someone designs a knife for use in the kitchen, it looks quite different than a knife designed to attack other humans.  Of course, both can be used to attack people, but its much easier to attack with the switchblade, and a switchblade is a bad kitchen tool.  Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.interaction-design.org/courses/gamification-creating-addictive-user-experience&#34;&gt;addictive design&lt;/a&gt;, we have been sold on the idea that a switchblade is an all-purpose tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;paringknife.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paring knife&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;switchblade.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;switchblade&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like social media, a hammer is great when you need it, but otherwise should be left in the toolbox.  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://openresearch.ocadu.ca/id/eprint/1743/ - http://openresearch.ocadu.ca/id/eprint/1743/7/Hsu_Cheryl_2017_MDES_SFI_MRP.pdf&#34;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; of addictive design have convinced us to constantly carry our hammer around.  It buzzes in our pocket, nagging us to try it out in just about any context.  It uses our innate human desire for social approval to reward us whenever we use the hammer.  Now its use is so widespread, wielding the hammer no longer looks out of context.  There are people hammering while eating, working, walking, talking, and even in the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-usability-s-offspring-surveillance-capitalism&#34;&gt;Meet Usabilityâ€™s Offspring: Surveillance Capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile phones could truly benefit people, but it is nearly impossible to open your phone to do one thing.  Apps and ads immediately compete for your attention and time.  Posting updates to family and friends happens through Facebook.  Search, maps, and many other activities happen through Google. YouTube steers us to watch another video.  Facebook inserts itself into our personal relationships.  All of these are designed to keep you using them more and more, since that is how those companies make money.  These services are built on usability, which causes us to use them more and more.  &lt;strong&gt;Remember, with surveillance capitalism, the users are &lt;a href=&#34;https://quoteinvestigator.com/2017/07/16/product/&#34;&gt;not the customer, they are the product&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;  So those companies are using usability design to figure out how to keep users &amp;ldquo;engaged&amp;rdquo;, meaning using that platform as much as possible.  That is the design problem they are solving.  &lt;strong&gt;When the user is the customer, that can look very different.&lt;/strong&gt;  WhatsApp became massively popular with a business model of charging a dollar a year, regardless of usage. Their users were also their customers. Now &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; aims to change all that, and WhatsApp users &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-11/why-whatsapp-s-privacy-rules-sparked-moves-to-rivals-quicktake&#34;&gt;do not like it&lt;/a&gt;.  Turns out it is very difficult to compete with free, so responsible business models are at a tremendous disadvantage.  And many WhatsApp users are now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/13/technology/telegram-signal-apps-big-tech.html&#34;&gt;flooding to Signal&lt;/a&gt;, which is a non-profit foundation working to survive on donations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foundations and governments need to measure and evaluate the projects that they fund, and they are starting to request surveillance capitalism techniques from the projects they fund.  Schools are using web services that use addictive design, ostensibly to help kids learn, but are nonetheless getting kids hooked.   Metrics are central to addictive design, it is based on tracking actual people and what keeps their attention.  A/B testing provides a rapid way to test how to suck people in.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system&#34;&gt;Recommender systems&lt;/a&gt; are very effective at getting users to click on the next video or post.  For those kinds of predictions to work, they first need a lot of data about how lots of people respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://openresearch.ocadu.ca/id/eprint/1743/7/Hsu_Cheryl_2017_MDES_SFI_MRP.pdf&#34;&gt;how designers shift the burden of responsibility through design&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://openresearch.ocadu.ca/id/eprint/1743/7/Hsu_Cheryl_2017_MDES_SFI_MRP.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;shifting-responsibility.png&#34; alt=&#34;how designers shift the burden of responsibility through design&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-driven-design-is-dangerous-and-powerful&#34;&gt;Data-driven design is dangerous and powerful&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data-driven design can also be used to find the borders of what things they will tolerate beyond things in their interest.  For example, so many software business models involve offering a service without payment, then finding ways to get the users to pay.  This can be with their data or by upselling.  An ethical approach to this kind of business model is to clearly define upfront what types of things require payment.  Unfortunately, a more common approach is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nirandfar.com/want-to-hook-your-users-drive-them-crazy/&#34;&gt;first get users hooked&lt;/a&gt; on the service without paying.  Getting users hooked is offered as a design service, the design equivalent of someone pushing addictive drugs.  Once hooked, when the cost of migrating away from the tool is high, hit users with payment requirements.  Using data-driven design, a service can measure that response in detail.  Tracking all the users provides even better targeting of users based on profiling them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data-driven design is clearly powerful but it need not lead to harmful practices.&lt;/strong&gt;  Usage data can let small organizations effectively direct resources to the areas of biggest need.  Crash report analytics quickly point out important bugs that otherwise would have taken days or weeks of effort to track down.  Neither of these need data about people to be effective techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;measure-effectiveness-rather-than-engagement&#34;&gt;Measure effectiveness rather than &amp;ldquo;engagement&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best mobile software would be designed to make users spend as little time as possible using it.  This is hard to measure.  Users who find the software difficult to use would also use it as little as possible.  We need to figure out how to measure that difference.  Once we do, we can begin to understand what makes a good design in which people use the tool to efficiently solve a problem, then put the tool away once they are done. I think this is one of the biggest questions we can now work on as part of our work on Clean Insights.  It is clear that learning to measure effectiveness will not be easy.  Creating the discipline of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience_design&#34;&gt;user experience design&lt;/a&gt; was also not.  After thinking about human-computer interaction and usability for over 25 years, I watched these ideas go from a nice idea to the dominant paradigm.  &lt;strong&gt;It is clearly possible to reclaim usability by thinking ethically about how data is collected and used.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key thing that makes user-centered design work so well is the cycle of research, design, implementation and testing.  This is akin to scientific experiments, where there is a hypothesis that is tested.  It can happen so fast because it can be decentralized and pieced out into a wide range of scales. User-focused design starts by trying to solve a problem, and iterates to continually improve.  The goals often change as well, in response to new use cases, business models, technologies, and even product goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So often, the central focus shifts from real needs to keeping users &amp;ldquo;engaged&amp;rdquo;.  Designing for engagement shifts the focus away from the task at hand, and instead is about making people use the software as much as possible.  That distracts from providing solutions that reduce the time the user needs to complete a task.  For example, no one is asking for software to help them send and receive ever more messages.  The goal is effective communication and organization.  If software is really addressing that need, that means users will spend less and less time using that communication tool.  That is in direct conflict with a design process focused on &amp;ldquo;engagement&amp;rdquo;, which pushes for as much eyeball time as possible.   The same design thinking based on psychology used in addictive design can also be used to actively &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Aditya-Purohit-4/publication/340903372_Designing_for_Digital_Detox_Making_Social_Media_Less_Addictive_with_Digital_Nudges/links/5ea3740ea6fdccd7945168ae/Designing-for-Digital-Detox-Making-Social-Media-Less-Addictive-with-Digital-Nudges.pdf&#34;&gt;avoid addictive qualities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as a person is being tracked and profiled, there is an inevitable pull towards trying to keep that person &amp;ldquo;engaged&amp;rdquo;.  If the data is instead about actions, not people, then the emphasis is on what the user wants to achieve.  Billions have been spent on learning how to effectively track people, that does not need to be thrown away.  The analytics software can be retooled to focus on usage rather than people.  Responsible collection of usage data is the clear place to start in order to shift from &amp;ldquo;engagement&amp;rdquo; to effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Insights: February 2021 Update on Privacy-Preserving Measurement</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/10/clean-insights-february-2021-update-on-privacy-preserving-measurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/10/clean-insights-february-2021-update-on-privacy-preserving-measurement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings, all. I hope this finds you healthy and well, finding ways to enjoy the season (whichever it may be). While everyday still provides new challenges in the life of our team at Guardian Project, we continue to strive to be productive as productive as we can be in our professional and personal lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just posted an updated presentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleaninsights.org&#34;&gt;Clean Insights&lt;/a&gt;, reflecting on the symposium in May, and the work we have done since then. You can see and share it from here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vo6FI-WDLG0&#34;&gt;Watch update on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also listen to this update on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/podcast/2021/clean-insights-update.html&#34;&gt;Guardian Project Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://die.netzarchitekten.com/&#34;&gt;Benjamin Erhart&lt;/a&gt;, our lead developer on Clean Insights, we&amp;rsquo;ve made substantial progress over the last few months on delivering our new software development kits. If you visit our Gitlab project page, you will find design documents and SDKs for Android, iOS, Javascript (both for desktop and web) and soon Python (Thanks, to &lt;a href=&#34;https://irl.xyz&#34;&gt;Iain Learmonth&lt;/a&gt; for this contribution). While this work is ongoing, the code is stable, and we feel it is ready to start getting it into all of your hands, so that you can start asking all the questions we have yet to consider.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights&#34;&gt;Clean Insights on Gitlab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of how easy it is to implement a measurement of a specific event or a visit to certain view in your app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-android-sdk/-/blob/master/app/src/main/java/org/cleaninsights/example/Main2Activity.java#L48&#34;&gt;Sample code for Android integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still relying on Matomo as our backend aggregator, analysis tool and dashboard, and it continues to work well enough for our 1.0 solution. That said, to enhance the privacy of Clean Insight-enabled clients, we&amp;rsquo;ve design and implemented a proxy service, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-matomo-proxy&#34;&gt;Clean Insights Matomo Proxy&lt;/a&gt;. The CIMP reduces the amount of metadata and logging that Matomo can do, since it is only communicate to directly by the no-logging proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-matomo-proxy&#34;&gt;Clean Insights Matomo Proxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this software is available for you to implement and deploy on your own. We also have a public testbed and hosted service available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.cleaninsights.org&#34;&gt;https://metrics.cleaninsights.org&lt;/a&gt; that we can make available for anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t able to run and maintain their own instance. We can also assist you with considering the insights you want to gain, threat modeling the risks it poses to your users, and implementing the SDK into your software, be it a mobile app, web app, desktop app, back-end service or operating system. Our deisgn partners at Okthanks also have a variety of concepts and soon sample projects and code for implementing effective and ethical Consent UX to achieve the right kind of &amp;ldquo;opt-in&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please reach out if you have interest in using Clean Insights. We have weekly scrum meetings, email lists and a public discussion room on the Matrix
network. More info on these on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleaninsights.org/dev&#34;&gt;Developer Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Data Sources: API Key Identifiers and BroadcastReceiver Declarations</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/15/new-data-sources-api-key-identifiers-and-broadcastreceiver-declarations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/15/new-data-sources-api-key-identifiers-and-broadcastreceiver-declarations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A central focus of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/wiki&#34;&gt;Tracking the
Trackers&lt;/a&gt; project has
been to find simple ways to detect whether a given Android APK app
file contains code which tracks the user.  The ideal scenario is a
simple program that can scan the APK and tell a non-technical user
whether it contains trackers, but as decades of experience with
anti-virus and malware scanners have clearly demonstrated, scanners
will always contain a large degree of approximation and guesswork.
Tracking the Trackers grew out of experiments in using machine
learning to detect malware.  This provided the spark to apply this to
privacy issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The malware research clearly demonstrates that network domain names
and code signatures are quite reliable techniques for identifying
malware.  This also applies to tracking, since the majority of
tracking happens via tracking companies&amp;rsquo; SDKs which send data to
specific domain names.  The hard part is that code signatures and
domain names are not easy to reliably extract, and are often easy to
obfuscate when someone is looking to hide what an app is actually
doing.  This is common in malware, and we are also starting to see
obfuscation in the world of tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android gives us a break with its
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/manifest/manifest-intro&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a hard requirement for Android apps so it is always there, it
contains some key declarations that set up how the code is run, and it
is easy to extract and parse.  So we put extra effort in thinking
about the data that is contained in the &lt;em&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the goal of simple scanners for tracking, we are excited by
two new data sources that we found in the &lt;em&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/em&gt; that
are useful signals for automatically detecting tracking in Android
apps: API Key Identifiers and &lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/em&gt; Declarations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-key-identifiers&#34;&gt;API Key Identifiers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking services provide their customers with servers to submit the
data for processing and analytics.  These are usually part of the
service&amp;rsquo;s API.  A common pattern for publicly accessible network APIs
is to require the use of an API Key.  This key grants access to the
service and provides an unique identifier for the customer so that the
submitted data goes to the right place.  In order to submit the key to
the API, the key data must be identified to the server somehow.  That
is the API Key Identifier.  This is generally something that never
changes, since changing it could mean locking out all customers.  For
example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/android/reference/com/google/android/gms/analytics/Tracker&#34;&gt;Google Firebase
Analytics&lt;/a&gt;
has used &lt;code&gt;ga_trackingId&lt;/code&gt; as its API Key Identifier for many years. API
Key Identifiers are a great way to track trackers.  They are tiny and
easy to extract.  Most services require them.  The entire set that we
have found is small enough to fit into a single machine learning
search space.  And it is quite unlikely that an app would include them
by accident or without having set up a tracking service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exodus-Privacy/etip/issues/62#issuecomment-613964965&#34;&gt;some
evidence&lt;/a&gt;
of obfuscated API Key Identifiers, the source has not yet been
identified.  We found many API Key Identifiers that were not the same
but matched a pattern.  This pattern looks like it could be encoding
some information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.APpuz.lHMBA142332.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.BCcyZzWehh.IOfazFfwIH109433.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.CDwo.buYv134822.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.DErSuvPp.bEyhwTQb93737.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.EOoOEpvG.ZuepOuto31966.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.FIKDGlAZIZ.vrlGNzSLEm110206.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;com.GicPdlXU.iXbdAAkA69030.APIKEY&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;API Key Identifiers are now &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exodus-Privacy/etip/issues/62&#34;&gt;included as a data
point&lt;/a&gt; gathered in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/11/%CE%B5xodus-etip-the-canonical-database-for-tracking-trackers/&#34;&gt;Exodus ETIP&lt;/a&gt;.
If you have some clues about any of this, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/wiki/-/issues/6&#34;&gt;let us
know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;broadcastreceiver-declarations&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/em&gt; Declarations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Android, apps and the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/about/versions/11/reference/broadcast-intents-30&#34;&gt;system&lt;/a&gt;
can publicly broadcast events, and any app can listen for these
events.  Some of these events contain detailed information, like the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/wiki/-/issues/5&#34;&gt;complete metadata&lt;/a&gt;
about which song is currently playing.  Charging and battery status
can be used to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/battery-status-readout-as-a-privacy-risk/&#34;&gt;re-identify users&lt;/a&gt;.
These broadcast events are generic Android &lt;code&gt;Intents&lt;/code&gt; which an app
registers a receiver by name in order to get the info when it is sent.
The specific pieces of interest are the
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/BroadcastReceiver&#34;&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/IntentFilter&#34;&gt;IntentFilter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/intents-filters#Building&#34;&gt;Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other bits in the &lt;em&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/em&gt;
Declarations are easy to extract.  Unfortunately, &lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/em&gt;
Declarations are not nearly has definitive when it comes to marking
tracking.  They are still worth including, since they are easy to
extract, and the whole set of unique, extracted names is small enough
to be used as a search space for the machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scope of how apps can receive data via &lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceivers&lt;/em&gt; was
also recently
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/about/versions/oreo/background#broadcasts&#34;&gt;narrowed&lt;/a&gt;
to a large degree by Google, due to privacy concerns.  The upside is
that apps cannot receive system-wide broadcasts unless they are
already running.  The downside is that scanners have to do static code
analysis, and perhaps even dynamic analysis, in order to see which
&lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceiver IntentFilter Action&lt;/em&gt; names an app has declared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage-considerations&#34;&gt;Usage Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The possibility of false positives is still there.  For example, if
someone makes a &amp;ldquo;build flavor&amp;rdquo; that builds without tracker SDKs but
forgets to exclude the API Key Identifiers, then a simple scanner will
flag this as tracking, even though it could not be.  The tracker SDK
is not included, which is the code that gathers and uploads the
tracking data.  In this example, the developer can easily fix it after
a scanner flags the app as a tracker, by moving the API key
configuration out of the &amp;ldquo;build flavor&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trickier case to review is when an app includes opt-in tracking.  We
believe that opt-in tracking and data reporting should not be flagged
as a tracker, especially when the opt-in user experience makes it
clear to the user what data is being gathered, and under what
condition it is being sent.  In that case, the simple scanner will
flag the app, since it contains the API Key Identifier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we think that machine learning is very promising for
tracking apps that track us.  There are many good signals, but none of
them definitely mark an app as a tracker.  They must always be
considered as a group with the whole picture, and given well-labeled
data, machine learning can do this kind of task quite accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-the-hunt&#34;&gt;Join the Hunt!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding API Key Identifiers is work that can be done in bite-sized
pieces, by people in their spare time.  Many if not most tracker SDKs
require API keys in order to use their service, so start by looking
through &lt;a href=&#34;https://etip.exodus-privacy.eu.org/trackers/all&#34;&gt;ETIP&lt;/a&gt; for
entries that are missing &lt;code&gt;Api_key_ids&lt;/code&gt; entries.  Usually, this is
documented in their SDK developer documentation.  There are also many
SDKs which set the API Key via a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exodus-Privacy/etip/issues/62#issuecomment-598272804&#34;&gt;method
call&lt;/a&gt;
rather than a declaration in an XML file.  In that case, the API Key
Identifier might be found by reading the strings out of the JAR
file. We also welcome more information about &lt;em&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/em&gt;
declarations.  We are tracking new data sources and approaches in our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/wiki/-/issues&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any kind of mass scanning to be usable, future work should focus
on expanding the set of easy to extract features, and finding which of
those are useful.  Complicated and resource-intensive extractions like
domain names, code signatures, and source/sink tracing still hold
promise for delivering high accuracy, but would likely remain only
useful when scanning individual or small sets of apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/thema/NGIZeroPET.html&#34;&gt;NGI Zero PET&lt;/a&gt; fund.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Îµxodus ETIP: The Canonical Database for Tracking Trackers</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/11/%CE%B5xodus-etip-the-canonical-database-for-tracking-trackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/12/11/%CE%B5xodus-etip-the-canonical-database-for-tracking-trackers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There is a new story to add to the list of horrors of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surveillance_capitalism&#34;&gt;Surveillance Capitalism&lt;/a&gt;: the United States&amp;rsquo; Military is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgqm5x/us-military-location-data-xmode-locate-x&#34;&gt;purchasing tracking and location data&lt;/a&gt; from companies that track many millions of people.  We believe the best solution starts with making people aware of the problem, with tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt;.  Then they must have real options for stepping out of &amp;ldquo;big tech&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/nov/28/android-apps-third-party-tracker-google-privacy-security-yale-university&#34;&gt;where tracking dominates&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; provides Android apps that are reviewed for tracking and other &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/docs/Anti-Features/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;anti-features&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, and F-Droid is built into mobile platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;https://calyxos.org/&#34;&gt;CalyxOS&lt;/a&gt; that are free of proprietary, big tech software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the most effective method for automatically analyzing
Android APK files is to search for well known strings in the extracted
contents of the APK.  Domain names are one example, like if an app is
sending data to &lt;code&gt;google-analytics.com&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;facebook.com&lt;/code&gt;, then it is
clear that it is doing some kind of tracking.  These lists of well
known strings must be created and managed by people, then gathered and
reviewed.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt; created
their &lt;a href=&#34;https://etip.exodus-privacy.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Exodus Tracker Investigation Platform
(ETIP)&lt;/a&gt; for exactly this purpose.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/YalePrivacyLab/tracker-profiles&#34;&gt;Yale Privacy Lab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jawz101/potentialTrackers&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;jawz101&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Guardian Project, F-Droid, and others have centralized their efforts on Îµxodus ETIP as the canonical database for these strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;searching-the-open-web-for-key-bits-of-info&#34;&gt;Searching the open web for key bits of info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since tracking is mostly done by companies trying to get customers,
they advertise and document their services on the web.  We spent some
time searching for that information to see what we could find.  We
mostly searched using two bits of information: the API Key Identifiers
that we
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/extracted-features/-/blob/master/axml-meta-data-run&#34;&gt;extracted&lt;/a&gt;
and &amp;ldquo;top 10&amp;rdquo; lists of companies that provide tracking and related
services.  From this, we added over 50 new service profiles to the
Îµxodus ETIP database.  We also added upwards of 100 pieces of
additional information to existing entries like SDK identity strings,
links to documentation, privacy policies, and information on the
company&amp;rsquo;s tracking methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that research, we saved some choice promises from selected tracking companies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Glassbox offers customer experience analytics solutions that
doesnâ€™t just tell you what a customer is doing. It tells you why.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Target traffic from all sources, including the 50% from the hidden
web where third-party cookies are blocked, to increase targetable
inventory.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Collect customer and product data in real time, from anywhere&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;PlaytestCloud will capture the whole gameplay experience, turning
you into a spectator with super powers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We record the playersâ€™ screen, their touches and what they have to
say at all times.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We curate geospatial ground truth data sets on a global scale&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take segmentation and analysis from overnight to real-time. Our DMP
works in-session for perfect match rates even on passerby traffic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowdsourcing-the-hunt-for-trackers&#34;&gt;Crowdsourcing the hunt for trackers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking the trackers is the kind of work that fits in very well with
crowdsourcing.  Tracking companies are disappearing and renaming
themselves all the time, in order to avoid too much scrutiny.  But
they still must reach out to developers in order to find customers.
That means we can find them.  Join in the search!  Non-technical
people can also contribute, for example, when you read news about a
tracking company,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://etip.exodus-privacy.eu.org/trackers/all&#34;&gt;search&lt;/a&gt; to see if it
is already in ETIP.  If not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exodus-Privacy/etip/issues&#34;&gt;file an
issue&lt;/a&gt; to request it is
added. Android developers with little bits of spare time can add code
signatures, domain names, and other key technical details to ETIP.  Or
even &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/scripts/-/blob/master/find-ga_trackingId.py&#34;&gt;code up quick scripts&lt;/a&gt;
with new ideas for detecting tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of forums where you can ask for assistance in
getting started.  Hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/en/page/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contributing to Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.f-droid.org&#34;&gt;F-Droid Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/about/#contact&#34;&gt;F-Droid chat rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/&#34;&gt;Guardian Project channels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/thema/NGIZeroPET.html&#34;&gt;NGI Zero PET&lt;/a&gt; fund.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy translation workflows and the risks of translating in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/06/08/easy-translation-workflows-and-the-risks-of-translating-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/06/08/easy-translation-workflows-and-the-risks-of-translating-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Crowdsourced translation has opened up software and websites to whole
new languages, regions, and uses.  Making translating easier has
brought in more contributors, and deploying those languages requires
less work.  A number of providers now offer &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo;, integrated
translation, speeding up the process of delivering translated
websites. On the surface, this looks like a big win.  Unfortunately,
the way such services have been implemented opens up a big can of
worms.  Third parties must be trusted with user data.  The translators
cannot work without being tracked. Displaying the translation requires
JavaScript.  The security profile is more complicated and harder to
defend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For projects with elevated security and privacy requirements, these
are deal breakers.  Translators can get in trouble for working on
publishing software or translating censorship circumvention
documentation.  Minority languages are suppressed in many places
around the world, even publicly working in some languages can get
people into trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been working for many years now to help make software and
website translation easier, more accessible, and more efficient.  We
also balance that with privacy and security concerns.  This post
outlines how to balance all those concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-integrated-translation-systems&#34;&gt;Live, integrated translation systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this new class of translation services means that the
translations are not shipped with the website or app, but instead
dynamically downloaded and delivered.  These translation services
require that third party code is integrated into the website or app to
deliver the translations.  All of the regular
&lt;a href=&#34;https://browserleaks.com/&#34;&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://owasp.org/www-project-top-ten/&#34;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; concerns of dynamic
web services apply here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Transifex Live is based around
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.transifex.com/live/installing-the-JavaScript-snippet&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;,
it uses JavaScript to dynamically load the translated strings from the
Transifex CDN hosted on Amazon AWS.  They also provide an iFrame
option, which has its own &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/9428051&#34;&gt;security
concerns&lt;/a&gt;.  Crowdin provides
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.crowdin.com/in-context-localization/&#34;&gt;in-context
localization&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;
which lets translators see the translations live in the website as
they are working.  This is a huge benefit to the translators, but it
has all the same issues as Transifex Live.  Their code must run in
your site.  They use other providers like Amazon to provide their own
service.  All of these third-parties have to be trusted to provide
security and privacy.  On top of that, Crowdin and Transifex are
monolithic, proprietary offerings, it is not possible run your own
instance.  Like many cloud-based services, it is all-or-nothing:
accept all the tracking, the privacy concerns, and security issues, or
do not use such a service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the data from the translation contributors must be considered.
These live services provide the translators a direct channel to feed
data into the website.  A malicious translator could feed an exploit
to the website using this channel.  Such a setup relies entirely on
any automated checks that the translation platform provides.  These
checks are optional, and often disabled by default.  Also, attackers
regularly find ways around even the best checkers and sanitizers, like
Mozilla &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mozilla/bleach&#34;&gt;Bleach&lt;/a&gt; or Ruby
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flavorjones/loofah&#34;&gt;loofah&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all these reasons, projects like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://weblate.securedrop.org/&#34;&gt;SecureDrop&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.tails.boum.org/&#34;&gt;Tails&lt;/a&gt; self-host Weblate to
provide crowdsourced translation..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;static-sites-with-live-previews&#34;&gt;Static sites with live previews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static sites built with tools like Jekyll and Hugo offer big benefits
in terms of privacy, security, and cost of operation.  But they
generally require more technical skills to operate, and have
restricted possibilities in terms of dynamic interaction.  There is a
lot that still can be done, and things are improving fast.  The dream
of live localization and in-context translation workflows without
privacy and security concerns is within reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live display of translations is not possible with a fully static site.
Live translation requires front end JavaScript or a dynamic backend
server.  The vast majority of web tracking and security
vulnerabilities come from JavaScript, sites that serve high risk
communities should use static sites that work without JavaScript
enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translation updates can be highly &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/23/figuring-out-crowdsourced-translation-of-websites/&#34;&gt;automated&lt;/a&gt; with a static site.  This means new translations can be reviewed
and deployed within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll and Hugo can also provide live previews while editing the
source pages and translations. Unfortunately, using these features
requires base level familiarity with technical things like working in
the terminal.  When Jekyll or Hugo is installed locally on the
translators computer, &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hugo serve&lt;/code&gt; generate the
whole website on the fly, and the browser will automatically refresh
the page with each change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-translation-and-static-sites&#34;&gt;Wordpress, Translation, and Static Sites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress remains a popular option for running websites, especially
for small and non-technical organizations.  It provides intuitive
editing and publishing tools combined with a wide array of attractive
templates to build on.  It is free software that can be self-hosted,
and it can even be used as a static site generator.  Even with the
rise of Jekyll, Hugo, and so many other static site generators,
Wordpress remains a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianshim.com/webtricks/wordpress-static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;good
option&lt;/a&gt;
for small organizations with privacy and security concerns, given that
it is used with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/static-html-output-plugin/&#34;&gt;static HTML output
plugin&lt;/a&gt;.
The one missing piece is crowdsourced translation that fits in with
all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://poedit.net/&#34;&gt;Poedit&lt;/a&gt; provides an alternate approach that is
self-hosted and free software, but is not entirely a typical
crowdsourced translation workflow.  It is an editor app that runs
locally on the translator&amp;rsquo;s own machine.  It supports translating
Wordpress directly via its API.  Then the results are included when
Wordpress generates the static HTML output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using self-hosted Weblate, the full website and translation workflow
can be as private as needed.  The static HTML output can be fed
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.weblate.org/en/latest/formats.html#html-files&#34;&gt;directly to
Weblate&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/23/figuring-out-crowdsourced-translation-of-websites/#translation-setup-with-po4a&#34;&gt;use &lt;em&gt;po4a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to set up an automated workflow that is tailored to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If self-hosting the translation platform is not a requirement, then
Crowdin and Transifex are options for translating the static HTML that
comes from Wordpress.  It is important to consider that both of these
will send data to many different companies, so they cannot be
considered private.  Using Crowdin sends data to Amazon, Google, and
Sentry.  Using Transifex sends data to Amazon, ChurnZero, Google,
jsDelivr, New Relic, Sentry, Stripe, Adobe (Typekit), and VWO.  Both
can potentially also send data to Facebook, GitHub, GitLab, LinkedIn,
and Twitter since those can be used for signing in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two good patterns for setting up the languages are the hosting each
language on a subdomain like how wikipedia does it; or, use path
segments for each language.  With GitHub Pages and GitLab Pages, each
language can be a project, then each language will be deployed to a
sub-directory, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mysite.gitlab.io/en&#34;&gt;https://mysite.gitlab.io/en&lt;/a&gt; comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/mysite/en&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.com/mysite/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the main site is the language chooser, e.g.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mysite.gitlab.io&#34;&gt;https://mysite.gitlab.io&lt;/a&gt; comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/mysite/mysite.gitlab.io&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.com/mysite/mysite.gitlab.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One idea further improve the Wordpress workflow is to combine the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transifex.com/integrations/wordpress-multilingual-plugin/&#34;&gt;Transifex Wordpress Plugin&lt;/a&gt;
with the
[Wordpress Static HTML Output Plugin](&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/static-html-output-plugin/&#34;&gt;https://wordpress.org/plugins/static-html-output-plugin/&lt;/a&gt;
to customize and streamline the whole process.  This could work with
Crowdin, Transifex, and Weblate, since they all provide APIs to
integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the classification of tracking</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/05/20/on-the-classification-of-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/05/20/on-the-classification-of-tracking/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This position paper tries to outline a framework for defining trackers
in smart phones and lists mechanisms for identifying them.  It hopes
to serve as the foundation for the work done in the
Tracking-the-Trackers project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;#section-1-levels-of-unwanted-behaviour&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; we start with
an abstract analysis of levels of unwanted behaviour in the context of
tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, in &lt;a href=&#34;#section-2-an-attacker-s-perspective-and-a-taxonomy&#34;&gt;section
2&lt;/a&gt;, we focus on
an attackerâ€™s perspective, on anonymity and pseudonymity. This
foundation allows us to define terms which are needed throughout the
paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we list proposed mechanisms for identifying trackers - based
on the threat model (attacker) as well as the level of acceptable
tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document talks about trackers in general on mobile devices
(smartphones). However, for the purpose of verification, we
exclusively focus on Android apps. First of all, Android has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idc.com/promo/smartphone-market-share/os&#34;&gt;85%
global market
share&lt;/a&gt;, secondly
Android apps (APKs) are easier to work on.  With iOS apps, monitoring
trackers (or instrumenting running code) is not as easy as on Android
based systems.  Therefore, whenever any claims are made, we refer to
the Android ecosystem. We however believe that very similar behaviours
exist on iOS based systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, this document does not talk about contact tracing (as in
Covid-19 contact tracing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1-levels-of-unwanted-behaviour&#34;&gt;Section 1: Levels of unwanted behaviour&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following section tries to categorize tracking respectively
potential unwanted behaviour in apps by level of severity. This is
done with a perspective for categories (labels) in a machine learning
approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level-0-no-tracking-at-all-no-network-communication&#34;&gt;Level 0: No tracking at all / no network communication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most harmless situation: an app is downloaded or shared in an
anonymous way (Tor, etc.) and only uses offline features and/or uses
unlinkable side channels for updates (for example flash cards).  An
example could be a map application which only displays a map and reads
a phoneâ€™s GPS position to display the userâ€™s location. There is no
network communication at all and it still offers a useful service to
its users. Map updates may be installed via flash cards or other
physical transportation media. The app does not need to request a new
map interactively from any server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level-1-inadvertent-tracking&#34;&gt;Level 1: Inadvertent tracking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category includes tracking but the service provider and the app
never intended to actually use the resulting data / meta-data for the
purpose of tracking individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: to illustrate this category, recall our map app from above. Only
this time, it does request map (base layer) updates from a map server  every 7
days. It also checks every day, if the map viewer app is the latest version.
Based on this information, an attack could theoretically derive weekly IP
address &amp;ldquo;beacons&amp;rdquo; from some user. Since the update check was not personalized,
an attack can not be for sure, if an update request is from the same person or
not.  Hence, a user still has potentially enough anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This and the next category probably (to be verified) constitute the majority of
&amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level-2-unintentional-tracking-by-use-of-chatty-libraries&#34;&gt;Level 2: Unintentional tracking by use of chatty libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category tracks users already quite heavily. The motive is not to increase
ad revenue, build up user profiles to sell them nor to pass on the data to an
aggregator. The unintentional tracking stems more from the fact that the app
developer(s) used libraries which help them in developing the app and/or which
are simply useful for the overall user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: if we revisit our map example, we could imagine that the map app
now also includes a search functionality. Users can type in the initial letters
of a street name and for every letter they type, an AJAX HTTP request is sent
to the map server. In addition, the developers felt that it would be useful to
receive APM (application performance monitoring) logs as well as crash reports
as well as a set of libraries to measure which features of an app the users
actually use the most. These logs are sent periodically to some log collection
server run by the developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that we still do not talk about (Google, Facebook etc) cookies here. We
only talk about watching what users are typing (including backspace and
corrections - an attacker can literally watch their thoughts via the global
click-stream).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level-3-ad-revenue-focused-tracking-of-users-and-or-user-behaviour-pseudonymized&#34;&gt;Level 3: Ad-revenue focused tracking of users and/or user behaviour (pseudonymized)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this category, we are entering the area often described as surveillance
capitalism: users are receiving cookies (if it&amp;rsquo;s a web based app) and or have
unique IDs embedded in the app and these unique identifies (which are not tied
to a person in the first place and hence are a &amp;lsquo;nym of the user) are being sent
for nearly every network interaction. These IDs may (but not necessarily have
to ) serve as authentication / authorization token ( see OAUTH 1,2, OpenID
Connect) or may be purely auto-generated and simply serve for tracking actions
users takes over the course of his day (so that the interest of a user may be
extracted). These tracking IDs may then be forwarded and sold to aggregators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may be acceptable to some users, since the techniques use
pseudonymization, there is an implicit trap hidden in this approach: unique IDs
are usually long enough so that they are unique globally (for example UUID
strings). Thus, they can easily be correlated with real PII data and the
pseudonymization vanishes instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level-4-ad-revenue-focused-tracking-of-users-and-or-user-behaviour-linked-to-person&#34;&gt;Level 4: Ad-revenue focused tracking of users and/or user behaviour (linked to person)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category fits most non-open source commercial apps such as FB messenger,
twitter, etc. (but it can occur as well in open source apps).  The business
model is to fully understand a user, his/her interests, his/her behaviour,
location (-&amp;gt; location tracking),  and very important - his/her circle of
friends (contacts), etc.  The &amp;ldquo;gold&amp;rdquo; in the app gold rush is a users&amp;rsquo; interest
and intent. In order to serve him/her adds better and faster (in the
sub-millisecond range). Again, as in the previous category, these tracking IDs
may then be forwarded and sold to aggregators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assume the vast majority of apps fall into this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level-5-full-scale-stealthy-tracking-surveilling-the-spouse-kids-state-actors-apt-attacks-general-surveillance-etc&#34;&gt;Level 5: Full scale stealthy tracking (surveilling the spouse, kids, state actors, APT attacks, general surveillance, etc.)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category would fit any technique which tries to secretly monitor as many
actions on the whole smartphone (or potentially also via the smart phone on
computers) of a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: kids tracking apps. Or hidden apps which check what your
husband/wife is doing on his/her phone (and forwarding call logs , messages,
etc.). State actors tracking dissidents, journalists or any chosen target also
would use these techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often these apps can be identified by their extended permissions but not
necessarily so. Well written apps in this category may be impossible to detect
without major reverse engineering efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work in the Tracking the Trackers project limits itself to Levels 3 and 4.
We intentionally omit level 5, since this is a cat-and-mouse game with the
attackers. It is rather trivial to change some behaviour for an attacker while
our detection mechanism remains open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;section-2-an-attacker-s-perspective-and-a-taxonomy&#34;&gt;Section 2: an attackerâ€™s perspective and a taxonomy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is nothing as practical as a good theory&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;ndash; Kurt Lewin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section builds upon the work of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dud.inf.tu-dresden.de/literatur/Anon_Terminology_v0.31.pdf&#34;&gt;Pfitzmann and
Hansen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
who did (to the author&amp;rsquo;s knowledge) the first thorough comparison of
terminology in literature with respect to the concepts of anonymity,
linkability, pseudonymity, etc. We believe that their work is a good
framework for thought. It also hints at some connections to Shannon&amp;rsquo;s
information theory and probability. However, the paper does not follow
through on the maths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core insight of their work is that - if you include metadata of
communication flows over the internet, and if you assume an attacker which can
observe the whole network (passively)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, then true anonymity is nearly
impossible to achieve for any regular app or program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we first briefly describe Pfitzmann&amp;rsquo;s and Hansens&amp;rsquo; model and
especially their attacker&amp;rsquo;s model / threat model. We then replicate their
definitions and add some definitions of our own. The next step is to link their
definitions to our categories of tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equipped with these theoretical tools, we can proceed to define what we
consider tracking in Android apps and derive feature sets for an ML based
approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pfitzmann-hansen-threat-model&#34;&gt;The Pfitzmann-Hansen threat model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The threat model assumes a classical sender-receiver (source/sink) information
model where the communication network is usually the internet. They assume an
attacker to be yet another (possibly all-knowing) passive receiver. If messages
pass the communication network, attributes (i.e. meta-data&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; such as time +
time zone when a message was sent, received, the packet size, the protocols
used etc) may be derived by a receiver. These attributes may become another new
message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sender-receiver-model.png&#34; alt=&#34;sender-receiver-model&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we apply  Pfitzmann&amp;rsquo;s and Hansens&amp;rsquo; model to our levels, we arrive at the following insights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 0&lt;/strong&gt;: the app is quiet â†’ no harm, an all-knowing attacker can see the download of a level 0 app in the very best of cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1&lt;/strong&gt;: the passive attack may derive IP addresses (and hence some ideas of a userâ€™s location) and time stamps of when the app was in use. â†’ the passive attacker can already track the user to some extent iff (if and only if) he also has access to the telecomâ€™s IP address assignment database for that particular time window. This is usually only possible for nation state attackers. &lt;strong&gt;â†’&lt;/strong&gt; out of scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2&lt;/strong&gt;: In this scenario, it already depends a lot if the app is sending APMs, crash reports, or other â€œchatty libraryâ€ messages. If unencrypted, a passive attacker may - already in this category gain a lot of information on the user.  &lt;strong&gt;â†’&lt;/strong&gt; we propose to include detection of APMs/crash reporting libraries in future versions of the tracking the trackers project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3&lt;/strong&gt;: While it is nice to notice that the developers tried to pseudonymise tracking in this category, it does not help the user very much. As long as a passive attacker may detect the pseudonymized IDs in messages flowing to a central server, he wins. He can track the user. Countermeasure: a guaranteed rotation of these unique IDs/tokens every x seconds (at fixed intervals).
â†’ we propose to look at this level of tracking in our research in order to identify unique tokens/API keys, unique IDs in apps which are easily detectable in order to guide the F-Droid store developer on how to avoid common pitfalls associated with fixed IDs/API keys etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 4&lt;/strong&gt;: for an attacker, this is the gold mine. Here, nearly every action may be passively observed. This is the case, we assume to be the most prevalent one in most apps (proof: just take a random app and look at the tcpdump stream of data it sends every second). We will aim to detect the most common tracking libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 5&lt;/strong&gt;: here the attacker basically gains an upgrade from a passive attacker to an active attacker should he wish so. Game over for the user â†’ out of scope for our research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified a rough categorization of 5 levels of tracking. We reasoned what
information an attacker may gain at each level and we defined the scope of our
research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/thema/NGIZeroPET.html&#34;&gt;NGI Zero PET&lt;/a&gt; fund.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anonymity, Unlinkability, Undetectability, Unobservability, Pseudonymity, and Identity Management â€“ A Consolidated Proposal for Terminology&amp;rdquo;, 2008, Andreas Pfitzmann (TU Dresden), Marit Hansen (ULD Kiel). &lt;a href=&#34;http://dud.inf.tu-dresden.de/literatur/Anon_Terminology_v0.31.pdf&#34;&gt;http://dud.inf.tu-dresden.de/literatur/Anon_Terminology_v0.31.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;An assumption which is not far fetched - see the Snowden papers.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;Compare with the quote &amp;ldquo;we kill people based on metadata&amp;rdquo; by the former CIA/NSA director Hayden. &lt;a href=&#34;https://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2014/05/ex-nsa-chief-we-kill-people-based-on-metadata&#34;&gt;https://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2014/05/ex-nsa-chief-we-kill-people-based-on-metadata&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Features&#34; for Finding Trackers</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/28/features-for-finding-trackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/28/features-for-finding-trackers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One key component of the Tracking the Trackers project is building a
machine learning (ML) tool to aide humans to find tracking in Android
apps. One of the most important pieces of developing a machine
learning tool is figuring out which &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo; should be fed to the
machine learning algorithms. In this context, features are
constrained data sets derived from the whole data set. In our case,
the whole data set is terabytes of APKs. This post is an outline of
the features that we are focusing on in this current project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;confirmed-features&#34;&gt;Confirmed Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are features that we will definitely used, and already have good
tooling to do the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_extraction&#34;&gt;feature
extraction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;permissions&#34;&gt;Permissions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android apps must request
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/permissions/overview&#34;&gt;permissions&lt;/a&gt;
from the Android OS to access sensitive user data as well as certain
system features. This can naturally give big hints towards tracking
attempts. Basically an app which does not request any permissions will
have a much harder time of tracking its users, while an app aimed
towards tracking will require a myriad of permissions depending on the
properties it desires to track (e.g. location, contacts, phone IDs,
Bluetooth IDs, WiFi IDs, camera/microphone-access, call-logs and many
more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracking-libraries-and-sdks&#34;&gt;Tracking Libraries and SDKs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code re-use plays a big role in any software project, why write your
own tracking functionality when someone else has already implemented a
whole library geared towards tracking users. This functionality is
provided by different SDKs, which are pre-configured bundles of
functionality which in turn (for this use case) are provided by
tracking companies. The app developer often has to choose the desired
functionality. While importing a tracking library is no guarantee for
tracking activities it is certainly a red flag. We compare the
libraries imported by the app with a list of known tracking libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;domain-names&#34;&gt;Domain Names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers leave URLs in form of strings in the code to allow exchange
of information with the world outside of the app. This can be used to
transfer information about the user which in turn can be used for
tracking. The domains often contain a hint about the purpose behind
the data transfer (e.g. &lt;code&gt;https://www.google-analytics.com&lt;/code&gt;). Domain names
are data sinks for collecting data, which gives us a clear point to
focus on analyzing since collecting tracking data does not matter if
it never leaves the local device, while domain names are the point in
the code where data leaves the device and is sent to be collected and
analyzed on a remote server. Combined with other features like
permissions and seeing tracking libraries being imported a human
reviewer could get a pretty good idea of what type of information
could be sent. This human &amp;ldquo;gut feeling&amp;rdquo; of recognizing fishy
combinations of features is something a neural network can often learn
to approximate by being trained on a sufficient amount of training
data. Domain names known to be relevant to tracking are collected and
maintaned by &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/en/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;new-experimental-features&#34;&gt;New Experimental Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are features that show a lot of promise, but there is not
existing tooling to easily work with them.  We are working to make it
easier, and will cover that work in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-key-id&#34;&gt;API Key ID&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exodus-Privacy/etip/issues/62&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;API Key ID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
is a string that identifies bit of authentication data for enabling
access to an online service. Many online services require an &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt;
even if a library or SDK is not required to access it. Even when the
SDK is detected, the presence of an &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt; shows that the tracking
function is actually enabled. For example, the Google Firebase SDK
includes lots of functionality, not only tracking, each of which must
be enabled with an &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt;. So the presence of Firebase is not
enough to confirm tracking. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.epicenter.works/content/analysis-of-the-stopp-corona-app-improvements-through-expert-report&#34;&gt;current
example&lt;/a&gt;
of exactly this is the Austrian Red Cross&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Stopp Corona&lt;/em&gt; app to track
the spread of covid-19 in Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-language-processing-nlp&#34;&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned under the section on domain names, domain names can
already give a clear hint at intent. However since this property is
well known, URLs might be obfuscated to hide this information. This
domain name obfuscation is a well known technique in the world of
malware, there is some evidence of use by tracking companies. In this
case, a language model might learn that any URL that looks like random
letters and numbers might be a sign to consider increasing the
probability of classifying this app as tracking slightly, depending on
other features like requested permissions, and imported tracking
libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast-receivers&#34;&gt;Broadcast Receivers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android provides a system for data to be broadcast to all apps on a
device, this is known as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/broadcasts&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Broadcast
Receiver&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
A wide range of data is available via this mechanism, both from the
Android system as well as apps.  The Android OS broadcasts detailed
information about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/monitoring-device-state/battery-monitoring&#34;&gt;battery level, health, and charging
status&lt;/a&gt;,
including details of &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/os/BatteryManager#BATTERY_PLUGGED_AC&#34;&gt;how its
charging&lt;/a&gt;.
Many music apps will broadcast detailed information about the song
being played, while also &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/wiki/-/issues/5&#34;&gt;collecting those
events&lt;/a&gt; from
the system and other apps.  The full extent of this activity is not
well described, both what data is broadcasted, what apps are doing
with it, and which apps are collecting.  As a feature, &lt;em&gt;Broadcast
Receivers&lt;/em&gt; have a lot of promise since they fit the patterns of useful
features for machine learning: small, globally unique, and easy to
extract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;feature-extraction-process&#34;&gt;Feature Extraction Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are using tabular data to feed to the machine learning processes,
so the process of extracting and pre-processing different features for
classification includes similar steps for every feature. The number of
features that can reasonably be processed this way is limited to
probably tens of thousands of features, or perhaps even hundreds of
thousands. Therefore we have collections of the top-&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; features where
&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; is in the range of thousands: For example, the top thousand
tracking libraries, or all built-in permissions. This way we extract
the features out of the binary APK file, and source code when
available, and loop over our collections of known features. If the
feature was found in the APK/source the tabular data will be a 1, else
a 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/thema/NGIZeroPET.html&#34;&gt;NGI Zero PET&lt;/a&gt; fund.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Promise and Hazards of COVID Contact Tracing Apps</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/09/the-promise-and-hazards-of-covid-contact-tracing-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/09/the-promise-and-hazards-of-covid-contact-tracing-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been increasing interest in the possibilities of tracking
people who are infected with Coronavirus using all of the various
methods that smart phones provide.  There is good reason: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_tracing&#34;&gt;contact
tracing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; has been a
pillar of public health efforts for decades.  It is an effective means
to curtail the spread of infectious disease.  At the same time,
governments, companies, and organizations are acting fast to offer
services to help end this current pandemic.  The problem is that many
of these are taking advantage of these times to introduce more
tracking of people, more data collection, and more control over
people.  We must not let contact tracing be used to reduce privacy
and increase unnecessary data collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy International has been collecting examples of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://privacyinternational.org/examples/tracking-global-response-covid-19&#34;&gt;new data and tracking that are being introduced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there this is the specific issue of contact tracing apps that are
being introduced around the world.  These apps can be made in a way to
fully respect privacy, and to build trust with its users.  Unfortunately the majority of the ones introduced are failing to live up to this promise.  Singapore&amp;rsquo;s TraceTogether was the first to rise to prominence, it is proprietary software with obfuscated operations. (&lt;em&gt;update: the source for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opentrace-community&#34;&gt;reference implementation&lt;/a&gt; has since been released, but TraceTogether is still proprietary&lt;/em&gt;)   A &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@zerotypic/reversing-tracetogether-initial-analysis-edc940e86aa8&#34;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://splira.com/2020-03-28/&#34;&gt;audits&lt;/a&gt; pointed to failings, including potentially sending location data to a third-party analytics service.  There are now many of these apps, and based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://forensic.defensive-lab.agency/covid/&#34;&gt;this analysis&lt;/a&gt;, most of them are sending data to third party tracking companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, these audits took much more effort because the apps
were not open source.  There have been many pledges of making these
apps open source, but the only one that we have found that is actually
open source is &lt;a href=&#34;https://privatekit.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;Private Kit&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://fsfe.org/news/2020/news-20200402-02.en.html&#34;&gt;Free, open
source software is essential&lt;/a&gt;
for software that needs to be widely
trusted.  This is only key design element, the CCC has laid out a
complete list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ccc.de/en/updates/2020/contact-tracing-requirements&#34;&gt;requirements for creating trustworthy contact
tracing apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stand ready to help any of these efforts achieve real privacy and
build public confidence.  People must trust these apps for them to be
effective.  Transparency is essential to building trust.  They must be
secure so they do not leak personal data.  And they must be usable by
the vast majority of the population.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Trackers: using machine learning to aid ethical decisions</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/01/16/tracking-the-trackers-using-machine-learning-to-aid-ethical-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/01/16/tracking-the-trackers-using-machine-learning-to-aid-ethical-decisions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid is a free software community app store that has been working since 2010 to make all forms of tracking and advertising visible to users. It has become the trusted name for privacy in Android, and app developers who sell based on privacy make the extra effort to get their apps included in the F-Droid.org collection. These include &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/com.nextcloud.client&#34;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;, Tor Browser, &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/de.thecode.android.tazreader&#34;&gt;TAZ.de&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/de.tutao.tutanota&#34;&gt;Tutanota&lt;/a&gt;.  Auditing apps for tracking is labor intensive and error prone, yet ever more in demand. F-Droid already has tools to aide contributors in this process, visible in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/fdroiddata/merge_requests&#34;&gt;app submission&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/rfp/issues&#34;&gt;Request For Packaging (RFP)&lt;/a&gt; issue trackers.  We also have functional prototypes of using machine learning to drastically speed up this process by augmenting humans, rather than replacing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the prime motivation of the F-Droid community is ethical software distribution, algorithms will never replace humans in making ethical decisions. We have also explored using machine learning to detect tracking in a more generic way, without manually compiled lists of tracking libraries. With this funding, we will improve the F-Droid tools, and make them generally available for any use case needing to reliably detect trackers in Android apps. This builds upon our &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/2017/12/14/new-collaborations-on-exposing-tracking.html&#34;&gt;collaboration&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/reddr/LibScout&#34;&gt;LibScout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project comes out of some proof of concept work that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lo-res.org/~aaron/&#34;&gt;Aaron Kaplan&lt;/a&gt; and Hans-Christoph Steiner did, working with students in the Vienna Economics University&amp;rsquo;s (WU) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wu.ac.at/en/infobiz/teaching/sbwl-data-science&#34;&gt;Data Science Lab&lt;/a&gt;.  We focused on using machine learning with Android apps, first to detect malware, then second to detect tracking libraries.  It is of course ultimately an outgrowth of the F-Droid community&amp;rsquo;s efforts, and Guardian Project&amp;rsquo;s funded efforts for building systems without any tracking at all.  And special thanks to F-Droid founder &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ciaran_Gultnieks&#34;&gt;Ciaran Gultnieks&lt;/a&gt; for setting the ethical tone that inspired us all, back in &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2010/09/30/no-free-beer.html&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This current 44,500â‚¬ project is funded by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/PET/&#34;&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Trust Enhancing Technologies (PET) Fund&lt;/a&gt;.  F-Droid has received large, dedicated, computing resources from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cfarm.tetaneutral.net/machines/list/&#34;&gt;GCC Compile Farm&lt;/a&gt;, as well as some shared resources from Aaron Kaplan.  The budget will be used entirely to pay for people&amp;rsquo;s time for the research, development, and integration work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software development to get the existing LibScout and Exodus Privacy tools to be fully integrated into the F-Droid stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning research and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community management, to coordinate with F-Droid contributors, app developers, tool developers, academic researchers, etc. as well to promote these tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalize and package up all the useful parts of this project, which also means getting them included in Debian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-efforts&#34;&gt;Related Efforts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general approach that we are taking here has been proven in the context of web pages. The Brave Browser includes &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1805.09155&#34;&gt;machine learning techniques&lt;/a&gt; for blocking ads and trackers in webpages.  It is a very similar idea to what we propose, but that example is embedded into a browser and only applies to web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exodus Privacy has manually compiled an extensive list of tracking libraries and domains for receiving user data.  It then uses this to scan app from Google Play.  Those results are then reported on their website.  Exodus Privacy would directly benefit from this work, since they could use the tools we will create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghostery uses AI techniques to dynamically block ads in web pages. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/ghostery-deploys-ai-in-fight-against-ad-trackers/&#34;&gt;https://www.wired.com/story/ghostery-deploys-ai-in-fight-against-ad-trackers/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid has its own &lt;code&gt;fdroid scanner&lt;/code&gt; for doing checks based on manually prepared regular expressions.  This was combined with Exodus Privacy into F-Droid&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/rfp/issues&#34;&gt;issuebot&lt;/a&gt; which automatically scans apps that users request to be added to F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibScout uses machine learning to detect which versions of which libraries are included in an Android app (APK).  Using the list of libraries from Exodus Privacy, we worked with the LibScout author to create a functional prototype of a tracking library detector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sec.cs.tu-bs.de/pubs/2014-ndss.pdf&#34;&gt;Drebin&lt;/a&gt; clearly demonstrated that machine learning can be used to automatically classify Android apps based on certain aspects of their behavior. Their aim was to find malware.  Working with CERT.at and the WU Data Science Lab, we reproduced the results of the Drebin paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenges&#34;&gt;The challenges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest promise of this project is also the biggest technical challenge: finding a way to take datasets about what includes tracking libraries (e.g. F-Droid manual review, LibScout, Exodus Privacy), and turning that into a more general machine learning approach.  We will have to explore a wide range of possible features to include in the machine learning that are distinct from the tracking libraries themselves.  This general approach will provide tracking detection with more automation and less maintenance work of rerunning the machine learning on updated datasets as new tracking libraries are put into use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical methods for determining whether an app includes trackers are well known and described.  They currently require knowledge of Android development.  Machine learning has been proven to be able to reliably spot trackers in apps, this project will turn working prototypes into production software, integrate it into F-Droid community-driven processes, and make these new tools easily available for anyone else to apply to their specific use cases. Given an Android apps downloaded from anywhere, these new tools will be able to mark which ones have any kind of tracking in them, with a very high degree of certainty.  With the portion of the project that involves applying LibScout, at this point, the idea has been proven with prototypes.  Applying it is a straightforward matter of bringing a proven prototype to production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations relying on proprietary apps that must follow strict data protection requirements, like banks under the GDPR, can use these tools to ensure that apps they rely on do not contain illegal tracking, and to ensure that such tracking is not added in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These techniques are also applicable to other platforms, like Progressive Web Apps and Apple iOS.  Bootstrapping another platform would require a marked training set of apps to feed to the machine learning.  F-Droid already provides this set, and Android is the most popular OS in the world, making Android the ideal platform to start this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;humans-at-the-core&#34;&gt;Humans at the core&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid is a community run free software project very much in the same spirit as Debian.  The community has always aimed to provide 100% verified free software, built from source.  From the beginning, there was also an interest in other ethical considerations as well, these are expressed via F-Droid&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Anti-Features&amp;rdquo;.  These are things tagged with Tracking (contains tracking), Ads (includes advertising), and NonFreeNet (requires a non-free network service).  The process of ensuring that the apps are 100% free software as well as tagging apps with the required Anti-Features is a manual process that many people contribute to, that is aided by quite a bit of automation.  This project fits directly into this existing ecosystem.  It will both quickly provide improvements in contributors&amp;rsquo; workflow based on the existing prototype, as well as experiments towards drastically improving the whole workflow of anyone working to track trackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid fits into the whole Android app ecosytem in a very specific role.   It is the one source that only distributes free software, and has built a well deserved reputation for not compromising on the ethics that guide the community.  This has led it to become the standard &amp;ldquo;clean set&amp;rdquo; in all manner of research into Android malware and tracking.  Many academic papers covering Android malware cite f-droid.org as the source of ground truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, it is important to highlight that it is essential to keep humans always at the center of of these tools.  We are building tooling to augment humans, not replace them. Since the prime motivation of the F-Droid community is to build ethical software distribution, algorithms will never replace humans in making decisions based on ethics.  The tools can automate the technical details, so that contributors do not need to understand them in order to meaningfully help with the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking usage without tracking people</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/06/08/tracking-usage-without-tracking-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 10:58:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/06/08/tracking-usage-without-tracking-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that has become very clear over the past years is that there is a lot of value in data about people. Of course, the most well known examples these days are advertising and spy agencies, but tracking data is useful for many more things. For example, when trying to build software that is intuitive and easy to use, having real data about how people are using the software can make a massive difference when developers and designers are working on improving their software. Even in the case of advertisers, they mostly do not care exactly who you are, they want to know what you are interested in so that they can more effectively promote things to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning Guardian Project has focused on privacy, and worked to practice what we preach in our own software. For example, we have entirely disabled Apache web logs on our website for the past couple of years, so that we would not even have access to that rich data. We felt that we could not even store that data without fear of violating peopleâ€™s privacy, let alone working with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have changed in the past few years, and there are now a number of well tested techniques for tracking how people are using software without actually tracking who they are. It is now possible to keep some usage data while feeling safe that no one who might get that data could use it to identify individuals. One good example of this is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor Projectâ€™s tracking data&lt;/a&gt;. They provide a wide variety of tracking data to follow how Tor is being used, and how well the Tor network is operating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we believe that it is now possible to responsibly track usage without violating anyoneâ€™s privacy. One piece of work along these lines is the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cleaninsights/cleaninsights-android-sdk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clean Insights Android SDK&lt;/a&gt;. Nathan is leading the development of that effort. And this blog post announces another new development that we are starting: tracking usage data from F-Droid app repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry-300x133.png&#34; alt=&#34;tracking by country&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;133&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-13632&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry-300x133.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/bycountry.png 747w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, the Apache web logs for this site will be configured to store, but only information that is not fine-grained enough to identify people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only the date is stored, not the time or time zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referer, IP Addresses, User Agent are never stored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;country is stored by looking up the IP Address in the &lt;em&gt;geoip&lt;/em&gt; database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, a log entries look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;189.4.73.81 testy.at.or.at - [08/Jun/2017:13:55:46 +0200] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;-&#34; &#34;F-Droid&#34;
119.29.81.134 199.119.112.126 - [08/Jun/2017:14:46:48 -0400] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;http://testy.at.or.at/fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar&#34; &#34;Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 9.0; Windows NT 6.1)&#34;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stripped version looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;0.0.0.0 - - [08/Jun/2017:00:00:00 +0000] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;-&#34; &#34;-&#34; AT
0.0.0.0 - - [08/Jun/2017:00:00:00 +0000] &#34;GET /fdroid/repo/index-v1.jar HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 147950 &#34;-&#34; &#34;-&#34; ZH
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the raw data is processed by the webserver, the extra information will be discarded and never written to disk. Only the sanitized usage tracking information is ever stored. This is based on Tor Projectâ€™s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/webstats.git/tree/src/sanitize.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;web tracking&lt;/a&gt;. It is possible to do this with &lt;em&gt;Apache&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;lighttpd&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt;, and probably other webservers. For &lt;em&gt;Apache&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/maxmind/geoip-api-mod_geoip2/blob/master/INSTALL.md#configuration&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;mod_geoip&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; needs to be installed, then only a single line is needed to configure this private logging mode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;LogFormat &#34;0.0.0.0 - %u %{[%d/%b/%Y:00:00:00 %z]}t \&#34;%r\&#34; %&gt;s %b \&#34;%{Referer}i\&#34; \&#34;-\&#34; %{GEOIP_COUNTRY_CODE}e&#34; privacy+geo
CustomLog ${APACHE_LOG_DIR}/access.log privacy+geo
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we hope that we can work towards providing value from tracking data, without violating anyoneâ€™s privacy. Indeed, we are still prioritizing privacy over any value derived from tracking data. So anyone else who also wants to go follow this route needs to be fully aware that any tracking must be very carefully done, since it can easily result in inadvertent leaks. Do not take this as a stamp of approval on any tracking activity!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we learn without watching?</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/01/30/how-can-we-learn-without-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 14:40:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/01/30/how-can-we-learn-without-watching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What kind of measurement, tracking or analytics do you use, and can you sleep at night with your decision?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://berkmankleinassembly.org/&#34;&gt;Berkman-Klein Assembly&lt;/a&gt;Â program at Harvard, I am working with a team to imagineÂ a next-generation mobile and IoT analytics system that has privacy, confidentiality and anonymity at its core. The hope is we can find ways to learn what our users like and understand how our apps are performing without having to rely on proprietary cloud services, logging liability, network vulnerabilities, and invasive app permissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, we want to hear from you, as a developers and users interested in private, free and secure applications and devices, to understand the compromises you are making today. Please answer the questions below, and optionally provide your contact information, so we can get in touch with you for further help developing this new idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(the survey is now closed, thanks!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Â &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ImageÂ By Dave Morice Uploaded by Mkacer at en.wikipedia (Author Â Transferred from en.wikipedia by SreeBot) [CC BY-SA 3.0 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0)&#34;&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0)&lt;/a&gt;], via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
