<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ietf on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/ietf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ietf on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/ietf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF119 Conference Report: Monday March 18, 2024</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/03/18/ietf119-conference-report-monday-march-18-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/03/18/ietf119-conference-report-monday-march-18-2024/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Opening Day of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/119/&#34;&gt;119th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Brisbane Australia.  This post commences a daily rundown of privacy and Internet Freedom activities at this IETF meeting. For the rundown on IETF119 Hackathon, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2024/03/17/ietf119-hackathon-report/&#34;&gt;Hackathon report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dispatch&#34;&gt;Dispatch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IETF meetings don&amp;rsquo;t often kick off with the open dispatch but this time it happened. Dispatch sessions are meant to help specification authors find a home for their work if a home isn&amp;rsquo;t obvious. There are two classes of dispatch request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smaller items that have been spun off from mature work.  A good example is when a specification has a component that needs a formal record-type declaration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New work, possibly not yet well-defined, where the authors themselves haven&amp;rsquo;t a clue where it belongs. This is somewhat rarer because IETF offers several mechanisms for new work to develop interest and work its way into the formal process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got some of both this time. Unfortunately, the one that needs the most work is in the latter category and brought to IETF by a privacy-focused team.  I need to write a separate post with a crisp definition of a better method for achieving success at the IETF because we can&amp;rsquo;t make headway until hyptothetical participants learn from past mistakes (including my own).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cfrg&#34;&gt;CFRG&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has a frightening amount of new cryptography coming into the IETF over the last three to five years, driving by privacy-preserving measurement, quantum computing and the endless search for better performance.  Most of it entires IETF through the Cryptography Forum Research Group. It stikes me that this space is moving very quickly and I&amp;rsquo;m concerned we&amp;rsquo;re baking mistakes into Internet protocols in a way that will be hard to retrieve in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ohttp&#34;&gt;OHTTP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation (OHAI) Working Group has brought its key draft - &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ohai-ohttp/10/&#34;&gt;Oblivious HTTP&lt;/a&gt; to RFC status as of January 25, 2024 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/rfc9458/&#34;&gt;RFC9458&lt;/a&gt;). This was a focused effort, well-managed by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ohai/about/&#34;&gt;Working Group&lt;/a&gt; chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Working Group remains in place to tackle future items that arise from the early deployments. Better handling of large data transactions is the first such item, giving rise to a new specification for &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ohai-chunked-ohttp/&#34;&gt;Chunked Oblivious HTTP Messages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hackathon-demo&#34;&gt;Hackathon Demo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented the results from our interoperability testing on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-httpbis-unprompted-auth/&#34;&gt;The HTTP Signature Authentication Scheme&lt;/a&gt; to the wider IETF attendee audience at the Hackathon Demo event and felt lucky to have six people show interest (the competition being free food nearby).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF119 Conference Report: Hackathon March 17, 2024</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/03/17/ietf119-conference-report-hackathon-march-17-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/03/17/ietf119-conference-report-hackathon-march-17-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hackathon Weekend at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/119/&#34;&gt;119th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Brisbane Australia.  This post commences a daily rundown of privacy and Internet Freedom activities at this IETF meeting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IETF&amp;rsquo;s Hackathon, held at each face-to-face IETF meeting, is designed to encourage interoperability testing of standards under development. See this meeting&amp;rsquo;s wiki page for a description of&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ietf.org/en/meeting/119/hackathon&#34;&gt;this year&amp;rsquo;s twenty-four projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-httpbis-unprompted-auth/&#34;&gt;The HTTP Signature Authentication Scheme&lt;/a&gt; has been winding its way through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/httpbis/charter/&#34;&gt;HTTPbis Working Group&lt;/a&gt; since being adopted as a Working Group draft in July 2022. This work proposes a mechanism by which HTTP servers can offer authenticated resources without telegraphing they do so (thus resisting probing attacks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until very recently, Guardian Project had the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/guardianproject/httpsignatureauthentation/-/tree/main/http-sigauth-java&#34;&gt;only extant implementation&lt;/a&gt; of this specification.  It was originally demonstrated at the IETF113 (March 2022) Hackathon.  That changed in the last month with new implementations by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/quiche/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/francoismichel/http-signature-auth-go&#34;&gt;Université catholique de Louvain&lt;/a&gt;. We were able to pull together an interoperability test among these three for the Hackathon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interoperability proved surprisingly easy, implying that each of the authors had the same understanding of the wording of the specification, at least for this baseline test.  While we were unable to conduct a full pairwise test across the three server implementations and the three client implementations, we did get sufficient coverage to call it an early win. The testing team agreed more exercise will be necessary on the handling of the three supported HTTP versions as well as a variety of key related issues that will arise with the specification &amp;ldquo;in practice&amp;rdquo;. Still this effort seems technically solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potentially the most significant issue going forward is defining an approach to integrating this work into the prominent protocol stacks. Since HTTP and TLS have been in the field for more than a quarter century, their programming libraries have ossified (and narrowed) around conventional practices which does not support layer interaction in the manner necessary to support this work.  In particular, this work uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openssl.org/docs/man1.1.1/man3/SSL_export_keying_material.html&#34;&gt;keying materials exporter&lt;/a&gt; available at the TLS layer but not currently available in most HTTP layers where this spec needs the keying materials to create the proper HTTP authentication header.  Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEfO - Developing ECH for OpenSSL (round two)</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/11/09/defo-developing-ech-for-openssl-round-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/11/09/defo-developing-ech-for-openssl-round-two/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Encrypted ClientHello (ECH) plugs a privacy-hole in TLS, hiding previously visible details from network observers. The most important being the name of the web-site the client wishes to visit (the Server Name Indication or SNI).  This can be a major privacy leak, like when accessing a dissident news source hosted on a Content Delivery Network (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_delivery_network&#34;&gt;CDN&lt;/a&gt;). A visible domain name also provides a straightforward method for censors to block websites and internet services. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tolerantnetworks.com/about-us.html&#34;&gt;Tolerant Networks Limited&lt;/a&gt; and the Guardian Project successfully ran the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opentech.fund/&#34;&gt;OTF&lt;/a&gt;-funded &lt;a href=&#34;https://defo.ie/&#34;&gt;DEfO&lt;/a&gt; project that &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2021/11/30/implementing-tls-encrypted-client-hello/&#34;&gt;developed interoperable implementations&lt;/a&gt; of ECH for OpenSSL, Conscrypt and, via those libraries, a range of ECH-enabled web servers and clients.  This second funded project, DEfO-2, is a timely continuation of that project from the same the team.  As needed for disambiguation, we use DEfO-1 to refer the completed project and DEfO-2 for this current project. When there’s no ambiguity, we use the DEfO acronym to cover both past and future work related to ECH for OpenSSL, related applications and other TLS stacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the IETF standard for ECH completes, our key objectives are to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upstream DEfO code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate ECH into more clients and servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain and document operational experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit key code for red team audits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish open-source ECH provisioning tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key challenges we expect to face in meeting those objectives are: firstly, dealing with the OpenSSL and other upstream code bases (e.g. nginx, Apache HTTP Server) - satisfying upstream developers when dealing with complex code changes, as are involved here, has proven to be quite time and effort consuming. Secondly, it is a challenge to arrange the trials we have envisaged for DEfO-2 but doing so should help to demonstrate that web sites can easily and safely enable ECH without putting themselves at risk of interoperability failures or adverse attention from censors and without further centralising the web. Lastly, there are some remaining technical challenges not addressed in DEfO-1 (proprietary TLS ClientHello extension handling, interactions between TLS Hello Retry Request and ECH, and privacy analyses of split-mode ECH deployments) that we plan to address in DEfO-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key challenges we aim to mitigate for users is the ease with which user activity can be tracked and blocked based on clear text SNI. Secondarily, our focus on web-server integrations and provisioning mechanisms for ECH addresses Internet centralisation (which itself poses potential risks for censorship) by ensuring this technology can be easily deployed without having to depend on entities such as global-scale CDNs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary gaps addressed by DEfO are: the privacy-leak that is clear text SNI in TLS and secondly that nobody else has been developing an ECH implementation for OpenSSL, which is one of the most widely used TLS stacks, particularly for web servers. That situation has not changed since DEfO-1 started. Arguably filling that gap has become more pressing as some browsers now ship with ECH support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH is designed to contribute to the safety of users by removing one the the main remaining aspects of the web that allows network observers to easily monitor and censor web traffic based on either client DNS queries (browsers typically only use ECH when DoH has been used) and the Server Name Indication (SNI) in the TLS handshake, which is encrypted via ECH. The eventual goal is that use of ECH becomes near ubiquitous, and that goal is very achievable for web sites that make use of a CDN. DEfO however also has a focus on ECH support in various web servers and proxies (Apache, nginx, lighttpd, HAProxy) so that users of deployments that don’t use a commercial CDN can also benefit from ECH. The result of using ECH should be that neither the DNS query nor the TLS exchange leak the name of the web server with which the browser is establishing contact, thus taking away a still-easy opportunity for monitoring and censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Censors however, especially at the nation-state level, might choose to block all uses of ECH, which is something that is to be expected. The main mitigation for that envisaged is that browsers, even while not using ECH, will emit “fake” (or GREASEd) ECH values, thus increasing the costs if a censor decides to block all use of ECH. The extent to which GREASEing will be an effective mitigation for blocking all ECH will essentially
end up as a political/commercial decision for censors, browser makers, and web sites, but what we can say is that for now at least, browser makers and the larger CDNs do seem committed to making use of ECH. So we can have some hope that even the most capable censors might have to think hard before blocking all ECH. In DEfO-2 we are also planning some significant-scale trials that, if successful, should go a long way towards helping other significant web sites overcome fears related to enabling ECH. Overcoming a fear that one’s web site may be blocked if one deploys ECH will be a valuable result of DEfO-2 should our trials come to fruition as we hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do see a number of usability issues for those deploying web servers that need to be addressed, and that we plan to address in DEfO-2. Our approach is to aim for the same level of usability for web server administrators as has been achieved by &lt;a href=&#34;https://certbot.eff.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;certbot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as it interacts with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt or other CAs. Making it easy to enable ECH, especially for &amp;ldquo;smaller&amp;rdquo; web properties is high priority for DEfO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcome for which we hope is the upstreaming of ECH into important code bases, and to have demonstrated that one can deploy ECH easily at either small or large scale. The impact we expect is that we continue to significantly contribute to the use of ECH becoming near ubiquitous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;timeliness&#34;&gt;Timeliness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time is now ripe for DEfO-2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/faq-encrypted-client-hello&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; now supports ECH by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome supports ECH in &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/a/chromium.org/g/blink-dev/c/KrPqrd-pO2M/m/_8Lfd5xcAwAJ&#34;&gt;10% of stable releases&lt;/a&gt; as of August 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brave now also supports ECH, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brave/brave-browser/issues/1851#issuecomment-1763176335&#34;&gt;behind the same flags&lt;/a&gt; as Chromium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These browser developments, plus the server code developed by DEfO-1, now enable us to plan real-world experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloudflare has &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/ssl/edge-certificates/ech/&#34;&gt;beta support&lt;/a&gt; for enabling ECH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the run-time of DEfO-2 we expect to be in a position to run trials with significant players that could significantly assist with the goal of making use of ECH common for large web sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The DEfO-2 project timeline should also cover the finalisation of the IETF specification for ECH, significant progress on ancillary specifications (e.g. for provisioning) and provide sufficient time for upstreaming of DEfO code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEfO-2 benefits from the same team as DEfO-1 – Tolerant Networks and the Guardian Project having co-operated successfully on DEfO-1 are looking forward to continuing that collaboration and to extending the team for DEfO-2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HPKE, a core part of ECH, but with broader applicability, is now RFC9180 and the OpenSSL maintainers merged our DEfO code for HPKE in November 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-development-projects&#34;&gt;Our development projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DEfO project implemented Encrypted ClientHello (ECH) support for OpenSSL and Conscrypt, carried out interoperability testing of those implementations, and also used those libraries to ECH-enable various web servers and clients. We deployed services using these web servers and the DNS infrastructure required to support automated key upated for the HTTPS RRs associated with those services. Here we provide a short overview of that work in order to help with larger scale experiments and with further development of the ECH specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;libraries&#34;&gt;Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the DEfO project, we ECH-enabled two important TLS libraries:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.conscrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Conscrypt&lt;/a&gt; is a Java Security Provide (a library) that provides a Java &amp;ldquo;wrapper&amp;rdquo; for the C++ language boringssl library. Conscrypt is commonly used as the TLS provider for applications running on Android devices and is thus an attractive target to allow many clients to be ECH-enabled. (We do not target browser clients in DEfO as work on ECH-enabling those is being done by browser-makers.) The authors of boringssl (Google) have added ECH support to a version of their code, and we used that to enhance Conscrypt to call the new borinssl APIs required to use ECH and to provide mechanisms for applications to default to, or signal use of, ECH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSSL is a long-lived library providing cryptographic and TLS services that is used by many applications, including many web servers and hence is an attractive target for ECH-enabling, especially for server-side functionality. Our ECH-enabled fork of OpenSSL is here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have and will continue to work with the developers of other TLS libraries (e.g. wolfSSL) to assist in ECH-enabling their code, mostly via interoperability testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;clients&#34;&gt;Clients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ECH-enabled implemented the following TLS client applications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSSL &lt;code&gt;s_client&lt;/code&gt; - this client application comes as part of the OpenSSL build but is commonly used for testing and as an extremely simple scriptable TLS client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;curl&lt;/em&gt; is a widely-used command line web client that can use OpenSSL for TLS support, so we &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/curl/blob/ECH-experimental/docs/ECH.md&#34;&gt;ECH-enabled that&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F-Droid is an Android client application that provides an installable catalogue of FOSS applications and that uses Conscrypt. We made an ECH-enabled build called &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/ie.defo.ech_apps/&#34;&gt;DEfO ECH Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;servers&#34;&gt;Servers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ECH-enabled implemented the following web servers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Apache HTTP Server is one of the two most commonly used web servers today, you can try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/httpd&#34;&gt;ECH-enabled fork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt; is the other web server in the &amp;ldquo;top two.&amp;rdquo;, you can try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/nginx&#34;&gt;ECH-enabled fork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lighttpd is a web server that is commonly used on smaller devices such as home routers, you can try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/lighttpd1.4&#34;&gt;ECH-enabled fork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HAProxy is widely used as an HTTP ingress proxy and so is a good target for exploring ECH split-mode, you can try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/haproxy&#34;&gt;ECH-enabled fork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSSL &lt;code&gt;s_server&lt;/code&gt; - this example server application is part of the OpenSSL build and is commonly used for testing and experimentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;test-tools&#34;&gt;Test tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst the test tooling we developed are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive OpenSSL make test targets for HPKE and ECH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/defo-project/EchInteropTest&#34;&gt;ECHInteropTest&lt;/a&gt; is a Java client for interoperability testing on Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/echdnsfuzz&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;echdnsfuzz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a catalogue of &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; ECHConfigList values that could cause issues for clients combined with a service to randomly select one of those for publication in the public DNS every 30 minutes. This is a useful part of fuzz-testing an ECH-enabled client application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;issues-arising&#34;&gt;Issues Arising&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw the following issues that could benefit from further work to ease deployment of ECH:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For HAProxy, since DEfO-1 we have achieved support for HelloRetryRequest in ECH split-mode but have further work to do on ECH key rotation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There can sometimes be a lack of clarity as to which software component should be responsible for choosing to attempt real (i.e. non-GREASEd) ECH, and hence to be responsible for the additional DNS queries required to acquire an ECHConfig. For libraries like OpenSSL and boringssl it clearly only makes sense for that decision (and hence any new DNS handling code) to be outside the library. For a browser, it as clearly makes sense for that code to be in the browser application layer. With &amp;ldquo;middleware&amp;rdquo; though, such as OkHTTP or Conscrypt it can be hard to know which is the correct decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new DNS code required for handling HTTPS RRs is not too complex but the full generality of SVCB is extremely complex. Adding such complexity (and associated caching) is a major change for clients like curl that have to date only had to have a very simple model for DNS - essentially only querying A/AAAA and having almost trivial caching in the application itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The client implementation of ECH is relatively complex in that it &amp;ldquo;touches&amp;rdquo; the TLS state machine in many ways, and hence requires changes in a lot of places. As well as increasing the cost of implementing this also increases the costs associated with testing and upstreaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieving the same level of usability as &lt;code&gt;certbot&lt;/code&gt; for web server administrators may be challenging, but is an important goal to make it easy for web server administrators to be able to easily deploy ECH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH is demonstrably implementable and can be deployed. We don&amp;rsquo;t yet know if new issues will become apparent as larger-scale experiments are carried out, but we should find out during the run-time of DEfO-2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF116 Conference Report: Friday March 31, 2023</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/04/04/ietf116-conference-report-friday-march-31-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/04/04/ietf116-conference-report-friday-march-31-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Five of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/116/&#34;&gt;116th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Yokohama Japan.  For the rundown on Day Four, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2023/03/30/ietf116-conference-report-thursday-march-30-2023/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a lot of focus on privacy with respect to Internet protocols, novel new cryptography schemes are an important requirement for new protocol designs.  For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement&lt;/a&gt; is relying on new cryptography to support distributed aggregation of a wide range of measurements in the advertising domain as well as application telemetry.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass&lt;/a&gt; is relying on new cryptography to allow web browsing across the broad Internet after a single, lightweight authentication to an authority.  IETF Working Groups are encouraged to work with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://irtf.org/cfrg&#34;&gt;Crypto Forum Research Group&lt;/a&gt; of the Internet Research Task Force (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/about/groups/irtf/&#34;&gt;IRTF&lt;/a&gt;) to develop, test and refine new cryptography techniques that meet defined security/privacy goals and can scale for Internet-wide use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One area receiving a lot of attention is &lt;em&gt;signature blinding&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blind_signature&#34;&gt;Blinding&lt;/a&gt; is used when a message&amp;rsquo;s signing party is different from the message originator (digital cash, electronic voting are examples).  There are many types of blind signature, used for different purposes.  IETF&amp;rsquo;s interest is in how these algorithms work at Internet scale (Privacy Pass potentially being the most high-volume example).  No fewer than three results [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-cfrg-key-blinding-for-signature-schemes&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-cfrg-the-bbs-signature-scheme&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-cfrg-rsa-blind-signatures-with-public-metadata&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] were presented on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2023/130&#34;&gt;Verifiable Distributed Aggregation Functions&lt;/a&gt; are a key set of &lt;em&gt;multi-party computing&lt;/em&gt; techniques for improving the privacy of Internet measurement - split the counting across a group of non-colluding hosts and reassemble it in a manner only the requester (and not the individual aggregators) can see. While there is consensus around the approach, there is work to be done on the algorithm details, specifically around performance and elimination of attack vectors. &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-cfrg-plasma&#34;&gt;PLASMA&lt;/a&gt; - a new proposal for distributed aggregation - was presented along with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-cfrg-vdaf&#34;&gt;deeper analysis&lt;/a&gt; of two other proposals (PRIO and POPLAR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also worry about the forthcoming era of &lt;em&gt;quantum computing&lt;/em&gt; and its &lt;a href=&#34;https://scienceexchange.caltech.edu/topics/quantum-science-explained/quantum-cryptography&#34;&gt;impact on the cryptographic tools used today&lt;/a&gt;.  The search is on for cryptographic methods that are safe &lt;em&gt;post-quantum&lt;/em&gt; and, along with them, ways to migrate currently-encrypted data into the post-quantum era. Currently being discussed are &lt;em&gt;hybrid&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;composite&lt;/em&gt; schemes that layer the old techniques and the new techniques.  For me, the math goes off into fairy land pretty quickly, but if &lt;em&gt;Composite Key Encapsulation Mechanisms&lt;/em&gt; turns you on, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty happening at IETF nowadays [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ounsworth-pq-composite-kem-00&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-tls-hybrid-design&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-wussler-openpgp-pqc/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-tjhai-ipsecme-hybrid-qske-ikev2/00/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, it&amp;rsquo;s not just me whose eyes glaze over at the mathematics involved in much of this work.  IETF has found that IRTF&amp;rsquo;s research in this area should recognize that a presentation acceptable to other mathematicians might not be too useful for protocol implementers.  With this in mind, the Crypto Forum is pulling together &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-cfrg-guidelines-for-writing-cryptography-specifications&#34;&gt;a set of guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for writing cryptographic specifications within the IETF context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF116 Conference Report: Thursday March 30, 2023</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/30/ietf116-conference-report-thursday-march-30-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/30/ietf116-conference-report-thursday-march-30-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Four of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/116/&#34;&gt;116th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Yokohama Japan.  For the rundown on Day Three, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2023/03/30/ietf116-conference-report-wednesday-march-29-2023/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IETF is getting serious about interoperability among messaging services (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2022/04/eu-digital-markets-acts-interoperability-rule-addresses-important-need-raises&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; might have had something to do with it).  The charter for the Messaging Layer Security Working Group (MLS) specifically &lt;em&gt;excluded&lt;/em&gt; interoperability, though the group organized a draft that addressed the basic concepts that would allow MLS-compatible systems to federate. In early 2023, a new Working Group - More Instant Messaging Interoperability (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/group/mimi/about/&#34;&gt;MIMI&lt;/a&gt;) - was chartered to expand on the MLS federation work.  Given IETF&amp;rsquo;s relatively long and somewhat checkered history with messaging, the Working Group&amp;rsquo;s charter included this reminder to itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Numerous prior attempts have been made to address messaging interoperability, including the IETF&#39;s extensive prior work on XMPP, SIP/SIMPLE, and their related messaging formats. The MIMI working group will draw lessons from these prior attempts, seek to avoid re-hashing old debates, and will focus on the minimal standards suite necessary to facilitate interoperability given the feature set of modern messaging applications.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, its remit had some strict limits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The More Instant Messaging Interoperability (MIMI) working group will specify the minimal set of mechanisms required to make modern Internet messaging services interoperable. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;minimum&lt;/em&gt; being the operative word. So, what&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;in scope&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;messaging interoperability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;user discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;messaging content format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(an appropriate) MLS profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;message delivery service and transport mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establishment of end-to-end cryptographic identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifier naming conventions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically &lt;em&gt;out of scope&lt;/em&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;metadata processing to manage spam and abuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interoperable mechanisms for group administration or moderation across systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extensions to the MLS protocol (if needed, requirements will be referred to the MLS working group or other relevant working groups in the security area)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definition of completely new identity formats or protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extensions to SIP, SDP, MSRP, or WebRTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;development of anti-spam or anti-abuse algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;oracle&lt;/em&gt; or look-up services that reveal the list of messaging services associated with a given user identity without the user&amp;rsquo;s permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This being the first formal meeting after group charter, discussions are still at the stage where defining what &lt;em&gt;in scope&lt;/em&gt; means is still open, as are the most basic tenets of the technical mechanisms to implement the required features.  Grab your popcorn!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF116 Conference Report: Wednesday March 29, 2023</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/30/ietf116-conference-report-wednesday-march-29-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/30/ietf116-conference-report-wednesday-march-29-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Three of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/116/&#34;&gt;116th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Yokohama Japan.  For the rundown on Day Two, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2023/03/29/ietf116-conference-report-tuesday-march-29-2023/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long-running work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/masque/about/&#34;&gt;MASQUE&lt;/a&gt; - proxying all network-layer datatypes over QUIC (HTTP/3) - is nearing completion, with the specification for &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-masque-connect-ip/&#34;&gt;Proxying IP in HTTP&lt;/a&gt; in IESG review.  With these components in place, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-schinazi-masque-proxy/&#34;&gt;original MASQUE concept&lt;/a&gt; - a non-probable relay for client traffic providing privacy guarantees - has been revived, now defined within the new framework and leveraging &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-httpbis-unprompted-auth-02.html&#34;&gt;HTTP Unprompted Authentication&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy-preserving measurement is much on the minds of IETF attendees as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement Working Group&lt;/a&gt; continues to make progress.  Two new concepts were debuted in the Privacy Enhancements and Assessments Research Group &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/rg/pearg/about/&#34;&gt;PEARG&lt;/a&gt; meeting: &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-pearg-secure-partitioning-protocols&#34;&gt;Secure Partitioning Protocols&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-pearg-ipa&#34;&gt;Interoperable Private Attribution&lt;/a&gt;. Partitioning is new work looking at how multi-party statistical aggregation can be efficiently accomplished with improved privacy guarantees and is applicable to the on-going work on the Distributed Aggregation Protocol &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ppm-dap/&#34;&gt;DAP&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-pearg-ipa&#34;&gt;Private attribution&lt;/a&gt; measures events that occur in different contexts to the same person (shown an ad, then bought the product, for example).  As a sort of counterpoint, PEARG attendees also heard about the design decisions made in the development of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-pearg-dp3t-deploying-decentralized-privacy-preserving-contact-tracing&#34;&gt;privacy-preserving contact tracing application&lt;/a&gt; rolled out during the recent COVID-19 pandemic. Perhaps the defining characteristic of the design of this app was &lt;em&gt;purpose limitation&lt;/em&gt; - building out features that specifically &lt;em&gt;can not&lt;/em&gt; be used for any other purpose (such is the wide-spread fear of these applications being used as the infrastructure of a much more broader system of social control).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF116 Conference Report: Tuesday March 28, 2023</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/29/ietf116-conference-report-tuesday-march-28-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/29/ietf116-conference-report-tuesday-march-28-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Two of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/116/&#34;&gt;116th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Yokohama Japan.  For the rundown on Day One, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2023/03/28/ietf116-conference-report-monday-march-28-2023/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ohai/about/&#34;&gt;OHAI Working Group&lt;/a&gt; has submitted the core draft of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ohai-ohttp/&#34;&gt;Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation&lt;/a&gt; to the RFC Editor for editorial finalization and publication. OHAI is designed to support &lt;em&gt;transational&lt;/em&gt; uses of the HTTP protocol that seek IP address privacy (by means of a relay pair, one associated with the client and one associated with the target resource). The target resource is, thus, said to be &lt;em&gt;oblivious&lt;/em&gt; to the requester&amp;rsquo;s IP address.  While the initially-imagined use case for OHAI was access to the DNS service (with some in the IETF feeling DNS-over-HTTP did not go far enough to protect user privacy), the dominant  use case imagined today is &lt;em&gt;telemetry&lt;/em&gt; - monitoring vendor-, application- or operating system-defined usage parameters on centralized systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fair to ask how OHAI-capable services are to be discovered.  The OHAI Working Group is proposing to use DNS &lt;em&gt;Service Binding Records&lt;/em&gt; (SVCB, defined &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-dnsop-svcb-https/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and well-described &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-01/dns-svcb-https/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). TLS 1.3 Encrypted Client Hello is among the other IETF standards leveraging SVCB.  SVCB records, similar to the (also new) HTTPS records, allow a host of define multiple ways to make connection with parameterization using just the DNS lookup (as opposed to the multiple round-trip mechanism of HTTP&amp;rsquo;s Alt-Svc header).  The draft - &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ohai-svcb-config/&#34;&gt;Discovery of Oblivious Services via Service Binding Records&lt;/a&gt; has been under Working Group discussion since IETF113 and is close to submission for last call (technical completion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/rfc8446/&#34;&gt;TLS 1.3&lt;/a&gt; and Service Binding Records, Encrypted Client Hello &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-tls-esni-14.html&#34;&gt;ECH&lt;/a&gt; was, in fact, the reason SVCB records were defined. DNS lookup is the only point at which certain cryptographic information can be made available before all the connection encryption starts to happen.  Unfortunately, the SVCB draft is stuck in the RFC Editor work queue behind ECH, even though there is language in ECH that references SVCB.  The Working Group is therefore required to remove all the SVCB language from the ECH draft so that it may proceed.  This procedural detail - and accompanying delay - has important consequences: the major open source software package that requires modification before ECH can expect wide adoption (OpenSSL) is waiting for ECH to become a full-fledged RFC before the submitted pull requests will be granted.  Meanwhile there is plenty of experimentation with ECH happening on the live Internet with Mozilla/Firefox and Cloudflare running experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out there&amp;rsquo;s an alternative (or perhaps &lt;em&gt;parallel&lt;/em&gt;) proposal for TLS 1.3 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-tls-ctls/&#34;&gt;CompactTLS&lt;/a&gt; - an effort begun in 2019 and now in it&amp;rsquo;s eighth revision.  cTLS proposes to &lt;code&gt;save bandwidth by trimming obsolete material, tighter encoding, a template-based specialization technique, and alternative cryptographic techniques. cTLS is not directly interoperable with TLS 1.3 or DTLS 1.3 since the over-the-wire framing is different.&lt;/code&gt;  cTLS is undergoing formal analysis and implementation work proceeds, though no results are currently available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/httpbis/charter/&#34;&gt;HTTPbis Working Group&lt;/a&gt; formally adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-httpbis-unprompted-auth/&#34;&gt;HTTP Unprompted Authentication&lt;/a&gt; specification in the month before IETF116.  As a reminder, Unprompted Authentication allows a server to offer authenticated services without advertising that it does so (meaning the authenticated resources can not be actively probed). A number of semantic elements are under discussion, mostly to understand how this new feature is unique among existing HTTP features (and can, or can not, be aligned with &lt;em&gt;adjacent&lt;/em&gt; capabilities). An action item for IETF117 is a formal analysis of the cryptography used, with several alternatives being proposed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF116 Conference Report: Monday March 27, 2023</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/28/ietf116-conference-report-monday-march-27-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2023/03/28/ietf116-conference-report-monday-march-27-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post begins a daily blog, live from the 116th meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/116/&#34;&gt;Internet Engineering Task Force&lt;/a&gt; in Yokohama, Japan, March 25-31, 2023.  We&amp;rsquo;re focusing on standards activities of importance to the Internet Freedom community.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since IETF114 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2022/07/28/ietf114-conference-report-thursday-july-28-2022/&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;), the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement Working Group&lt;/a&gt; has been deliberating over two distinct proposals offering very different technical methodologies for undertaking measurement activities while respecting user privacy. &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-dss-star&#34;&gt;STAR&lt;/a&gt; offers an approach called &lt;em&gt;k-anonymity&lt;/em&gt; - reporting a measurement value only if &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; or more parties are also reporting the same value. This approach theoretically prevents rare values being used to single-out individuals.  Distributed Aggregation Protocol, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ppm-dap/&#34;&gt;DAP&lt;/a&gt;, uses an approach that distributes individual measures across a set of aggregators, none of which gets to see all the granular measurement data - the fully-aggregated total only seen by the third-party who requested it (who, in turn, gets to see none of the granular measurements).  At IETF116 we&amp;rsquo;re learning about the operational experience with these technologies, with multiple implementations of both running in different testbeds.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/116/materials/slides-116-ppm-poplarstar-measurements&#34;&gt;Performance analysis&lt;/a&gt; has also been undertaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it&amp;rsquo;s very early days, it&amp;rsquo;s becoming clear that both approaches have had to make operational modifications (based on privacy vulnerabilities or performance or security) that seem to &lt;em&gt;decrease&lt;/em&gt; their uniqueness and call into question the need to have two approaches.  Both approaches, for example, are considering adding &lt;em&gt;differential privacy&lt;/em&gt; features.  Operationally, STAR performs best when &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; is within the range 10-100 and it is being argued that such a range is insufficient for Internet-scale use cases.  Operationally, DAP can benefit from a more distributed computation model (using &lt;em&gt;helpers&lt;/em&gt;) but this is offset by performance loss due to the volume of network traffic generated.  DAP is already at a performance deficit compared to STAR, partially because it handles the negative impact of malicious clients (those that purposely submit erroneous values).  Will we see a unified approach in the future?  I sense there&amp;rsquo;s a long way to go here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;em&gt;web filtering&lt;/em&gt; - raised initially at IETF115 - was again discussed in a side meeting hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iwf.org.uk&#34;&gt;Internet Watch Foundation&lt;/a&gt; who are focused on combating child abuse, trafficking and exploitation, a problem they say is exacerbated by the distribution of specific types of content on the Internet. IWF is raising this problem within the IETF in hope of a technical solution to finding and removing the types of content that encourage, they say, these behaviors.  This problem area strikes at the heart of the design of the Internet which, at its core, is &lt;em&gt;content-neutral&lt;/em&gt;.  Perhaps more importantly, there is significant concern that tools developed to suit this particular use case could be easily adapted to induce censorship of less well-defined content and for less-altruistic purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF114 Conference Report: Friday July 29, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/29/ietf114-conference-report-friday-july-29-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/29/ietf114-conference-report-friday-july-29-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Five of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/114/&#34;&gt;114th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia USA. For the rundown on Day Four, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2022/07/28/ietf114-conference-report-thursday-july-28-2022/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quiet day today with only the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/mls/charter/&#34;&gt;Messaging Layer Security&lt;/a&gt; Working Group holding its session. Draft 16 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-mls-protocol/&#34;&gt;MLS protocol&lt;/a&gt; completed last-call in mid-July and has been submitted for review after significant technical and editorial feedback from the working group. Are we getting close (again)?  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-mls-architecture/&#34;&gt;MLS Architecture&lt;/a&gt; document was lightly revised and version 8 submitted for review.  Two new drafts were presented: &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-mahy-mls-content-neg/&#34;&gt;MLS Content Negotiation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-robert-mls-extensions/&#34;&gt;MLS Extensions&lt;/a&gt;. The former has yet to be adopted as a Working Group item, but the latter was adopted during IETF114 (before the MLS session, over the mailing list).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federation (between messaging systems supporting MLS) was upgraded to BoF (Birds of a Feather) status at IETF114, with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/bofreq-mahy-mimi-more-im-interop/&#34;&gt;formal announcement&lt;/a&gt; that the activity would, if agreed by BoF participants, be seeking Working Group status.  The implication here is that the current MLS Working Group might &lt;em&gt;fold the tent&lt;/em&gt; after completion of the architecture and protocol work (a MLSbis Working Group would conceivably follow to handle protocol extensions and updates).  The existing draft on &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-mls-federation&#34;&gt;MLS Federation&lt;/a&gt; would then be picked up by this new Working Group as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF114 Conference Report: Thursday July 28, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/28/ietf114-conference-report-thursday-july-28-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/28/ietf114-conference-report-thursday-july-28-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Four of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/114/&#34;&gt;114th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia USA. For the rundown on Day Three, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2022/07/27/ietf114-conference-report-wednesday-july-27-2022/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At IETF112 (online) a formal Birds of a Feather (BoF) session was held on the concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/112/materials/slides-112-priv-chair-slides-agenda-01&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement&lt;/a&gt;.  A Working Group was &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;chartered&lt;/a&gt; and, at IETF113 in Vienna, we were treated to an incredibly detailed presentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2021/576.pdf&#34;&gt;Prio&lt;/a&gt;, an academic concept for supporting privacy in the context of Internet-scale measurement. Quickly following that presentation was an IETF proposal for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ppm-dap/&#34;&gt;defined protocol&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;distributed aggregation&lt;/em&gt; of measurement data, based on Prio&amp;rsquo;s core concepts and using a range of cryptographic and system architecture techniques to separate measurements from the identities of the human users being measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at IETF114, an alternative proposal was brought forward by &lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/about/&#34;&gt;Brave Software&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-dss-star&#34;&gt;STAR&lt;/a&gt;.  STAR uses techniques (specifically, distributed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/shamirs-secret-sharing-algorithm-cryptography/&#34;&gt;Shamir Secret Sharing&lt;/a&gt;) which make the system simpler to build and presents a smaller attack surface for adversaries.  Brave reported that STAR is in production use for some telemetry in the current &lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/download/&#34;&gt;Brave browser&lt;/a&gt;.  Several enhancements are planned, among them use of Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/id/draft-ietf-ohai-ohttp-02.html&#34;&gt;OHAI&lt;/a&gt;) to reduce exposure of Brave users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses when they share telemetry data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what is certainly a milestone in the IETF&amp;rsquo;s efforts to have positive impact on user privacy, Apple presented its experience with deploying its &lt;em&gt;private label&lt;/em&gt; version of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass protocol&lt;/a&gt; called Private Access Tokens - defined &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-private-access-tokens-01.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=huqjyh7k&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Private Access Tokens is a service fully compliant with Type 2 (Publicly Verifiable Basic Tokens) of the Privacy Pas specification, using the Split Origin/Attester/Issuer model and supporting origin-bound or cross-origin tokens.  Apple has also made developer tools available so applications (and not just browsers) can make use of the technology. Importantly, two open source implementations of the Type 2 spec are also available, and several CDN vendors are cooperating in providing test points. See more &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/114/materials/slides-114-privacypass-deployment-experience-00&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant progress has been made on the protocol&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/114/materials/slides-114-privacypass-base-drafts-update-00&#34;&gt;three base drafts&lt;/a&gt;. The success of these drafts might, however, be overtaken by the need to support an important use case - rate limiting.  Rate limiting can be used to subjugate DDoS type attacks and it can also be used to enforce &lt;em&gt;paywall&lt;/em&gt; type subscription services.  The challenge? Rate limiting necessarily weakens the privacy guarantees that form the basis for Privacy Pass. The Working Group &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/114/materials/slides-114-privacypass-rate-limited-tokens-slides-v2-00&#34;&gt;is debating&lt;/a&gt; what sort of damage limitation needs to be applied to this degradation in order to keep the value of the idea strong enough to justify the expense of maintaining it while also encouraging trust in the service by users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the HTTP protocol &lt;a href=&#34;https://httpwg.org/specs/&#34;&gt;long defined&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/httpbis/charter/&#34;&gt;HTTPbis Working Group&lt;/a&gt; is chartered to maintain and develop the core specifications as well as extensions to the protocol agreed to be generally useful.  To that end, the Working Group heard four new proposals for extension. Important for privacy are &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-pauly-httpbis-geoip-hint/&#34;&gt;GeoIP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth/&#34;&gt;HTTP Transport Authentication&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GeoIP attempts to address the problem of sharing personal location data, but in a manner that doesn&amp;rsquo;t induce harm or threaten privacy.  The author&amp;rsquo;s idea is to support a location &lt;em&gt;hint&lt;/em&gt;, as an option, on HTTP transactions. They were quickly reminded that IETF has tried to address location privacy for over a decade with nothing to show for it. In the end, however, most participants agreed it was important for IETF to address this area, even if the specific proposal was (tragically?) flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth/&#34;&gt;HTTP Transport Authentication&lt;/a&gt; has been revived after a long period of dormancy caused by the work on proxying over HTTP/3 (now almost complete).  Impacted by that proxying work as well as many of the new concepts being developed around &lt;em&gt;oblivious&lt;/em&gt; services (those that don&amp;rsquo;t leak the user&amp;rsquo;s IP address), this proposal has moved away from it&amp;rsquo;s focus on CONNECT tunnel authentication to a proxy server in favor of a general authentication scheme to suit situations in which servers do not want to expose the fact they are hosting authenticated services (&lt;em&gt;silent&lt;/em&gt; or non-probe-able authentication). The Working Group found the concept useful but asked for a number of editorial changes before they would vote to accept it as a work item.  A technical flaw will need to be addressed as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF114 Conference Report: Wednesday July 27, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/27/ietf114-conference-report-wednesday-july-27-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/27/ietf114-conference-report-wednesday-july-27-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*Day Three of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/114/&#34;&gt;114th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia USA. For the rundown on Day Two, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2022/07/26/ietf114-conference-report-tuesday-july-26-2022/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest is starting to consolidate on the need for additional definition for serving media over the QUIC transport layer, particularly for streaming and conferencing applications.  Following an informal gathering at IETF113 in March 2022, a formal Birds of Feather session met today with a draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/114/materials/slides-114-moq-moq-charter-proposal-00&#34;&gt;charter proposal&lt;/a&gt; and two draft documents describing the intended &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/id/draft-gruessing-moq-requirements-02.html&#34;&gt;use cases&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/id/draft-jennings-moq-quicr-proto-01.html&#34;&gt;protocol&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/114/materials/slides-114-moq-if-time-permits-quicr-01&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; a more visual overview.  There was broad concensus (at this well-attended session) as to the need for this work, but a split between one camp that sought a much narrower set of use cases (not wanting to &lt;em&gt;boil the Internet&lt;/em&gt; as it were) and another who wanted to &lt;em&gt;solve this problem once&lt;/em&gt;. This will be addressed as the BoF leaders work towards a vote on chartering the effort.  Either way, this is substantial work ahead.  I mention this here not so much in the realm of privacy as to look towards a future where QUIC&amp;rsquo;s efficiency and scalability benefits might make media-rich services available to those of lesser economic means or with mediocre connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly related to our interests in privacy and a free and open Internet, the MASQUE Working Group presented the status of what will be the last of its core specifications, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-kuehlewind-masque-connect-ip-01.html&#34;&gt;CONNECT-IP&lt;/a&gt;.  With implementations ready for interoperability testing, the protocol definition is being scrubbed for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ietf-wg-masque/draft-ietf-masque-connect-ip/issues&#34;&gt;burning issues&lt;/a&gt;. Of these, some headway was made at the meeting, though all are still officially under discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recall the challenges with actual interoperability testing with CONNECT-IP at the Hackathon last weekend (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2022/07/24/ietf114-hackathon-report-sunday-july-24-2022/&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;)?  With spec definition work almost complete, the Working Group&amp;rsquo;s mission will also be complete and, officially, put the group in a position to disband.  But those interoperability challenges provide the next raison d&amp;rsquo;être for continuation and, with five proposals already before the group, concensus was that the group leaders should move forward with re-chartering with a new mission which - at least by concensus of those present - will focus on assuring MASQUE is deployable in real-world scenarios. With CONNECT-IP lowest in the protocol stack individual vendors and implementors face vastly different integration scenarios and, in many cases, with quite different teams who have (historically) faced divergent requirements. That said, the demand for proxying IP over QUIC is already huge, with both major mobile device vendors lining up extensive services for their platforms using the MASQUE model.  IETF&amp;rsquo;s implementation-checks-definition model is well-suited to this sort of aggressive development, thankfully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF114 Conference Report: Tuesday July 26, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/26/ietf114-conference-report-tuesday-july-26-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/26/ietf114-conference-report-tuesday-july-26-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day Two of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/114/&#34;&gt;114th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia USA. For the rundown on Day One, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2022/07/25/ietf114-conference-report-monday-july-25-2022/&#34;&gt;daily report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucas Pardue, of Cloudflare and co-chair of the QUIC Working Group, gave a not-so-tongue-in-cheek &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/114/materials/slides-114-anrw-sessa-keynote-00&#34;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; about the breakdown of the OSI layering model of the Internet. His focus was on the &lt;em&gt;top&lt;/em&gt; of the stack, illustrating handsomely what QUIC and HTTP/3 have done (unknowingly to most) to our perception of layers.  A key challenge: tools for HTTP/1 are widely available and the protocol and its impacts are widely understood.  HTTP/2 and HTTP/3? Not so much (both are binary, not text-based, protocols).  Yet, here in mid-2022, the world of the Internet is predominantly (91%!) HTTP/2 and HTTP/3 traffic.  Similarly, TLS/1.3 and QUIC represent 87% of traffic. And many of the now-being-standardized protocols for privacy insert several layers of proxy into every transaction. From a &lt;em&gt;sound knowledge&lt;/em&gt; perspective, we seem to have taken a rather quick, and rather deep, step backwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ohai/about/&#34;&gt;OHAI Working Group&lt;/a&gt; has brought the core draft of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-ohai-ohttp/&#34;&gt;Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation&lt;/a&gt; nearly to Working Group Last Call (technical finalization). With multiple interoperable implementations said to exist, this bodes well for rapid completion and standardization. The twistingly-worded name engenders confusion (or distain) but the goal is laudable: make the requester&amp;rsquo;s IP address private in any &lt;em&gt;transactional&lt;/em&gt; HTTP-based protocol. Transactional protocols include DNS and Online Certification Status Protocol. But the dominant imagined use case is &lt;em&gt;telemetry&lt;/em&gt; - monitoring vendor-, application- or operating system-define usage parameters on centralized systems. A few holes remain, however, for services that do not want (or need) to be tightly-coupled (systems that are not, for example, an operating system&amp;rsquo;s fault reporting service).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF114 Conference Report: Monday July 25, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/25/ietf114-conference-report-monday-july-25-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/25/ietf114-conference-report-monday-july-25-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day One of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/114/&#34;&gt;114th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia USA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With privacy a key consideration in new protocol design, cryptography has become a major focus of IETF activities.  The Internet Research Task Force (IRTF) has the &lt;a href=&#34;https://irtf.org/cfrg&#34;&gt;Crypto Forum Research Group&lt;/a&gt; where new cryptography schemes are brought forward and vetted for use in IETF protocols.  Well, &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; is a misnomer. Much of the mathematics has long been defined, at least at its core, and the work is rather being brought into the IETF context where important engineering considerations apply: use of memory (at rest or in flight), processing required, round-trips required, etc.. Of significance at this meeting, mechanisms for &lt;em&gt;blinding&lt;/em&gt; a digitial signature are in high demand given the prevalence of multi-tiered approaches to privacy (that is, approaches that insert one or more proxies between entities in a transaction).  Something similar is in the works for cryptographic keys. A number of IETF protocol specifications, still in development, are in line to receive these mathematical gems including &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/group/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-private-access-tokens/&#34;&gt;Private Access Tokens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ohai/charter/&#34;&gt;Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation&lt;/a&gt; and others.  An excellent summary of the National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) &lt;a href=&#34;https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/nistir/8413/final&#34;&gt;Post-Quantum Cryptography &lt;em&gt;contest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was also provided. The topic itself, let alone the solutions chosen, is not for the weak-kneed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among IETF&amp;rsquo;s most difficult challenges - for those of us interested in privacy - is the massive amount of surveillance that Internet users endure in everyday life.  One problem is simply defining what &lt;em&gt;surveillance&lt;/em&gt; means, in the commercial rather than law enforcement sense. Toward that end, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/rg/pearg/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Enhancements and Assessments Research Group&lt;/a&gt; hosted an excellent &lt;em&gt;first principles&lt;/em&gt; presentation teasing out ideas around &lt;em&gt;decoupling&lt;/em&gt; who we are versus what we do, and specifically architectures and design principles to increase decoupling for the purpose of preserving privacy. IETF has a new Working Group looking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement&lt;/a&gt; where some of the decoupling ideas are key.  While one approach to privacy preserving measurement has been presented to IETF in the past, PEARG hosted a well-considered survey presentation that looked at a number of techniques in this field at different stages of development. Not considered here: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleaninsights.org&#34;&gt;Clean Insights&lt;/a&gt; project, with which Guardian Project is associated and which was perhaps the first to take a user-consent approach, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opendp.org&#34;&gt;Open Differential Privacy Project&lt;/a&gt; which seeks to make its tools explicitly transparent for public scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF114 Hackathon Report: Sunday July 24, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/24/ietf114-hackathon-report-sunday-july-24-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/07/24/ietf114-hackathon-report-sunday-july-24-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post begins a daily blog, live from the 114th meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/114/&#34;&gt;Internet Engineering Task Force&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelpha Pennsylvania USA, July 23-29, 2022 (in-person meetings having restarted in March 2022 after the COVID pandemic abated). We&amp;rsquo;re focusing on standards activities of importance to the Internet Freedom community.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/runningcode/hackathons/114-hackathon/&#34;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; event kicks off each IETF event, with projects that run the gamut from early implementations of just-emerging specifications to full multi-vendor interoperability testing of nearly-mature protocols. At this event, I sat in on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/masque/about/&#34;&gt;MASQUE&lt;/a&gt; team&amp;rsquo;s effort to commence work on the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-masque-connect-ip/&#34;&gt;CONNECT-IP&lt;/a&gt; specification. With the recent completion of two key specifications -  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-masque-connect-udp/&#34;&gt;CONNECT-UDP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-masque-h3-datagram/&#34;&gt;H3 Datagrams&lt;/a&gt; - MASQUE has become IETF&amp;rsquo;s solution for proxying all types of network traffic over QUIC and HTTP/3, including VPN and other privacy-focused scenarios. CONNECT-IP will complete the trio.  But this initial effort didn&amp;rsquo;t go well.  Google and Ericcson (co-authors on the spec) had brought teams who, indeed, implemented the key protocol elements of CONNECT-IP live and in-the-moment but were both stymied setting up testbeds that could deliver raw IP packets for routing by this new code. Wait, you might say, aren&amp;rsquo;t these network engineers?  True, but it was mostly the practicalities that got in the way - only laptops as test machines, working from the open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/quiche&#34;&gt;QUICHE&lt;/a&gt; repository on a machine that also hosts an environment for building production code, even deciding what sort of packets could be used for testing and where to route them. These are the frustrations of a first-ever effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other teams had much better luck even if they are not specifically focused on privacy.  Fourteen vendors worked together on the first interoperabiltiy test of &lt;em&gt;Low Loss Low Latency Scalable Throughput&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-tsvwg-l4s-arch-12.html&#34;&gt;L4S&lt;/a&gt;, an ambitious effort that was ultimately successful (that is, both at functioning at all and producing excellent results). Another team working on the Drone Remote ID Protocol &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/drip/about/&#34;&gt;DRIP&lt;/a&gt; were also successful - despite the lack of hackable drones or access to the key server software this protocol will eventually have to interoperate with &amp;ndash; and produced the first working demonstration of DRIP&amp;rsquo;s session registration protocol (which, it happens, involves almost all aspects of the proposed standard).  These two projects will surely be the hits of the upcoming Hackdemo Happy Hour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Hackathon complete, IETF turns to the serious business of creating new specifications.  This week&amp;rsquo;s meeting will see working sessions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/group/ohai/about/&#34;&gt;Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/mls/charter/&#34;&gt;Messaging Layer Security&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement&lt;/a&gt; in addition to emerging ideas from the Internet Research Task Force&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/charter-irtf-pearg/&#34;&gt;Privacy Enhancements and Assessments Research Group&lt;/a&gt;.  And MASQUE, where we&amp;rsquo;ll have some explaining to do about our Hackathon gaff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF113 Conference Report: Friday March 25, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/28/ietf113-conference-report-friday-march-25-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/28/ietf113-conference-report-friday-march-25-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Final day of the 113th IETF meeting, in Vienna Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IETF is looking to make a clear contribution to the problem of hyper-aggressive measurement of user activities on the Internet and the many misuses thereof.  To do so, the IETF recognizes that some measurement is important but that many desirable measurements require data most people consider sensitive.  It also recognizes that aggregated measurements often provide the most value, rather than individual ones.  Yet, today, parties interested in measurement need to collect and store individual records in order to aggregate them, exposing themselves to potential violations of their privacy agreements with users (or governments) and to theft of that data by outsiders.  Instead, IETF is looking at ways this aggregation can be managed in ways that protect user privacy while still providing much of the statistical power needed.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/group/ppm/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement Working Group&lt;/a&gt; has formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IETF&amp;rsquo;s effort centers around new cryptographic techniques that allow an intermediary aggregation service to aggregate measurements in a variety of ways &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; learning the individual values themselves, then passing that aggregated information along to &lt;em&gt;collectors&lt;/em&gt; (organizations that use the measurements).  The protocol design will include mechanisms for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safe submission of individual measurements by the client (potentially including proof of validity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verification of such validity proofs at the &lt;em&gt;aggregator&lt;/em&gt; when provided by the client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computation of aggregates at the &lt;em&gt;aggregator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting of results to the &lt;em&gt;collector&lt;/em&gt; without leaking the individual measurements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Working Group is chartered to deliver one or more protocols that can accommodate multiple privacy-preserving algorithms as necessary.  Two such algorithms are already under consideration - one based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://educatedguesswork.org/posts/ppm-prio/&#34;&gt;Prio&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-gpew-priv-ppm/&#34;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;), the other based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/staging/draft-dss-star-00.html&#34;&gt;STAR&lt;/a&gt;. The protocol(s) will be designed to limit abuse by both clients and servers (aggregation servers, collector servers), including exposure of individual user measurements and denial of service attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this work has the character of &lt;em&gt;seeming&lt;/em&gt; appropriate and necessary, there are many aspects to consider - just in the protocol design, let alone the social and policy implications - that caused attendees to say, to the effect, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m leaving here more confused than when I entered&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.  The unique trust model implied, the increased centralization implied, the completeness of the approach (that is, how much measurement it subsumes), the alignment with laws and agreements already in place, the pragmatics around what organizations can run such a service - these are questions yet unaddressed.  But at least now IETF has a solid stake in the ground from which to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF113 Conference Report: Thursday March 24, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/27/ietf113-conference-report-thursday-march-24-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/27/ietf113-conference-report-thursday-march-24-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day four of the 113th IETF meeting, in Vienna Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/group/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass&lt;/a&gt; - originating at Cloudflare in 2017 as a solution to user frustration with CAPTCHA - has been in full swing as an IETF activity since mid-2020.  Privacy Pass allows a client to solve some form of validity check (a CAPTCHA, a puzzle, a user-pass authentication) to then receive some number of tokens to be used at websites accepting Privacy Pass, thus eliminating the need to do a CAPTCHA at each site.  Sites hosted on large CDNs like Cloudflare benefit (Cloudflare provides the service for them) and users get a more convenient experience.  Users accessing the Internet through Tor are even more positively affected since they are most prone to CAPTCHA.  Privacy Pass is now in Version 3 and working to support a multi-issuer environment to provide another uplift to the user experience (tokens can be validated across issuers).  Just prior to this IETF meeting, a standardized mechanism for exchanging Privacy Pass tokens was adopted by the Working Group - &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-privacypass-auth-scheme/&#34;&gt;The Privacy Pass HTTP Authentication Scheme&lt;/a&gt;. Both request and response mechanisms are provided so that use of (or demand for) the token can be either server- or client-initiated. Going forward, it will be interesting to see if Privacy Pass benefits mostly the web browsing environment or finds its way into applications using HTTP as a substrate for richer styles of interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to point out that Privacy Pass, in practice, requires relatively-centralized infrastructure (issuers, who grant and redeem tokens).  In fact, the mathematics behind the multi-issuer capability in Version 3 requires that the number of issuers is limited to avoid users being de-anonymized too easily.  A more complete discussion of centralization and Privacy Pass is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-mcfadden-pp-centralization-problem-01&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  IETF members have, for some years now, expressed concern about increasing centralization - not only of Internet hardware (which the work of IETF can not in practice impact) but also of the  protocol designs themselves. The Internet Architecture Board has, during its recent Open Meetings, taken on the weight of this discussion, providing a forum for both studies of, and individual views on, the topic.  A formal statement from the group, though, has been harder to achieve.  As an alternative, individual voices have been encouraged, the most recent being former IAB member &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/person/Mark%20Nottingham&#34;&gt;Mark Nottingham&lt;/a&gt; who has produced &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-nottingham-avoiding-internet-centralization/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Centralization and Internet Standards&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that tries to define the problem in ways that can eventually be addressed within the IETF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it seems like very early days here, I&amp;rsquo;m encouraged both that discussions are vocal and pubic, and that more &lt;em&gt;human-centric&lt;/em&gt; voices are now present at IETF who have been working &lt;em&gt;within the system&lt;/em&gt; to provide tools and guidelines that can inform protocol design in ways that maybe, just maybe, will pull us back from the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF113 Conference Report: Wednesday March 23, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/26/ietf113-conference-report-wednesday-march-23-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/26/ietf113-conference-report-wednesday-march-23-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day three of the 113th IETF meeting, in Vienna Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messaging Layer Security (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/mls/about/&#34;&gt;MLS&lt;/a&gt;) is (finally) closing in on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/about/glossary/?query=wglc&#34;&gt;Last Call&lt;/a&gt; at protocol Draft 14 and architecture Draft 7 (which will be taken forward together). Sometimes referred to as the &lt;em&gt;TLS for messaging systems&lt;/em&gt;, Messaging Layer Security creates a uniform secure group discussion protocol, scalable to very large groups and providing similarly uniform security guarantees across providers. The near completion of the architecture and protocol drafts, and commencement of interoperability testing has prompted the Working Group to dust off the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-mls-federation&#34;&gt;Federation draft&lt;/a&gt; as the next object of their affection.  Will I be able to connect my &lt;a href=&#34;https://wire.com/en/&#34;&gt;Wire&lt;/a&gt; client to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.messenger.com/&#34;&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/a&gt; server? Don&amp;rsquo;t hold your breath, but in the meantime you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to enjoy the manifest benefits of secure group chat (with security guarantees as high as the industry knows how to produce) on your own network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ohai/charter/&#34;&gt;OHAI&lt;/a&gt;) is another in the suite of new designs aimed at reducing misuse of the client&amp;rsquo;s IP address.  OHAI is complementary to &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/masque/about/&#34;&gt;MASQUE&lt;/a&gt; - the former focused on &lt;em&gt;transactional&lt;/em&gt; service protocols like DNS and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/rfc8954/&#34;&gt;OCSP&lt;/a&gt; queries, the latter on fully bi-directional interactive exchanges.  Like MASQUE, proxies are involved (between requester and request destination) and in both cases the client (user) has to trust the proxy.  However, in the case of bad-actor clients, it is imagined that the proxy will want to communicate on a side channel with its counterpart to stop things like reply attacks or other mischief via &lt;em&gt;shadow banning&lt;/em&gt;.  This, however, raises the spectre of collusion among the intermediaries - something OHAI was initially defined to avoid.  There seems to be significant effort remaining on this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the prior post, the Human Rights Protocol Considerations(&lt;a href=&#34;https://sandbox-ng.ietf.org/group/hrpc/documents/&#34;&gt;HRPC&lt;/a&gt;) Research Group considered a new Individual Contribution on &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-giuliano-blocking-considerations/&#34;&gt;Regional Internet Blocking Considerations&lt;/a&gt;. While the current geopolitical environment was the impetus for this work, the content isn&amp;rsquo;t specific to a particular event. Rather, it catalogs - for policy makers - the technical mechanisms available to &lt;em&gt;withdraw&lt;/em&gt; geographic areas from connection to the global network, effectively &lt;em&gt;de-mystifying&lt;/em&gt; the concept.  Also via HRPC, the IETF got its first look at the idea of &lt;em&gt;content provenance&lt;/em&gt; in the work of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://c2pa.org&#34;&gt;Coalition for Content Provenance and Authenticity&lt;/a&gt; and their efforts to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://c2pa.org/specifications/specifications/1.0/specs/C2PA_Specification.html&#34;&gt;specifications&lt;/a&gt; around this idea.  Guardian Project&amp;rsquo;s pioneering &lt;a href=&#34;https://proofmode.org/about&#34;&gt;ProofMode&lt;/a&gt; work got a shout out!  Of special importance here, and perhaps more significance to IETF than the &lt;em&gt;data at rest&lt;/em&gt; work of the specification itself, are its generally-applicable definitions in the area of &lt;em&gt;Harms Modelling&lt;/em&gt;, readapted from work by &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture/guide/responsible-innovation/harms-modeling/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. This concept is core to HRPC&amp;rsquo;s research mission as defined in &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc8280&#34;&gt;rfc8280&lt;/a&gt; and this is the most rigor I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in defining the concept in ways that can have protocol impact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF113 Conference Report: Tuesday March 22, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/24/ietf113-conference-report-tuesday-march-22-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/24/ietf113-conference-report-tuesday-march-22-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day two of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/113/&#34;&gt;113th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt;, in Vienna Austria.  The crisis in Ukraine is on everyone&amp;rsquo;s mind, lending immediacy to the work of the Global Access to the Internet for All (GAIA) Research Group. While past and continuing work has focused on Internet access for the world&amp;rsquo;s population (especially those disadvantaged by economics, distance, mobility, and social constraints) the situation in Ukraine resulting from military activities give cause for both concern and hope.  While communications access points have been obviously targeted, the inherently decentralized topology of the Internet infrastructure in Ukraine has afforded surprising resiliency, increased by the willingness of nominal competitors to patch the communication systems back together for the good of all.  Few will remember that this resiliency from military attack was the raison d&amp;rsquo;être for ARPANet, predecessor to the Internet.  Perhaps, in this era of increasing centralization (hardware and software), the crisis in Ukraine will give us the impetus to consider changes to the trajectory of consolidation we&amp;rsquo;ve allowed to occur. We&amp;rsquo;ll follow up on this topic tomorrow after the Human Rights Protocol Considerations (HRPC) Research Group who will take up the topic of Regional Internet Blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important consideration from today&amp;rsquo;s GAIA presentations: the environmental impact of decisions we make about the architecture of the Internet.  While it&amp;rsquo;s easy to trash cryptocurrency for its unfathomable consumption of electricity (live dashboard &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccaf.io/cbeci/index&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), it&amp;rsquo;s almost certainly necessary to think about these same considerations in the work of the IETF, impacting as it does, billions of people on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF113 Conference Report: Monday March 21, 2022</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/21/ietf113-conference-report-monday-march-21-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/21/ietf113-conference-report-monday-march-21-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s opening day at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/meetings/113/&#34;&gt;113th IETF meeting&lt;/a&gt;, the first in-person meeting in two years due to the COVID pandemic and being held in Vienna Austria. We&amp;rsquo;re focusing on standards activities of importance to the Internet Freedom community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New work is brought to the IETF via Birds-of-a-Feature sessions and also each technical area&amp;rsquo;s Dispatch Working Group.  The Application area often sees the most unique and interesting ideas and this meeting was no exception.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://openethics.ai/&#34;&gt;Open Ethics Initiative&lt;/a&gt; introduced its idea for an &lt;em&gt;ethics disclosure&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://openethics.ai/oetp/&#34;&gt;transparency protocol&lt;/a&gt; to help promote trust among users and service providers in a way similar to nutrition labelling on foods.  Two &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-mahy-dispatch-immi-content-00.html&#34;&gt;new&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-mahy-dispatch-immi-mls-mime-00.html&#34;&gt;drafts&lt;/a&gt; have been written related to the format of data exchange among messaging services. I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking: &amp;ldquo;but messaging services don&amp;rsquo;t interoperate&amp;rdquo;.  Exactly. These drafts are a push to get that to happen, initially in the context of the Messaging Layer Security (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/mls/about/&#34;&gt;MLS&lt;/a&gt;) effort.  Along the same lines, a plea was made to liberate messaging from the confines of the encapsulating (and in some cases proprietary) protocols, to be used as first-class network transactions on their own via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-spinella-event-streaming-open-network/&#34;&gt;Event Streaming Open Network&lt;/a&gt;. And, the team doing Encrypted Client Hello (&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/id/draft-ietf-tls-esni-13.html&#34;&gt;ECH&lt;/a&gt;) introduced an idea to &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-farrell-tls-wkesni/&#34;&gt;liberate ECH&amp;rsquo;s host configuration information from the DNS&lt;/a&gt; to which some folks believe it is inextricably bound.  Well, they didn&amp;rsquo;t present it &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; that way, but&amp;hellip; Liberation was the theme of the event, it seems!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Privacy Enhancements and Assessments Research Group (&lt;a href=&#34;https://pearg.org&#34;&gt;PEARG&lt;/a&gt;) had a detailed presentation on the EU&amp;rsquo;s General Data Protection Regulation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gdpr.eu&#34;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;) as it relates to network privacy. It&amp;rsquo;s much richer than I imagined, indicating there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more there in terms of enforcement in the future. The long-incubating &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-irtf-pearg-censorship/&#34;&gt;A Survey of Worldwide Censorship Techniques&lt;/a&gt; seems to be near &lt;em&gt;last call&lt;/em&gt; in its Version 5.  The difficulty of getting it published has as much to do with hesitancy around the term &lt;em&gt;censorship&lt;/em&gt; as with the actual content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major news today, however, is that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/masque/documents/&#34;&gt;MASQUE Working Group&lt;/a&gt;, whose charter is to develop mechanisms that allow configuring and concurrently running multiple proxied stream- and datagram-based flows inside an HTTPS connection, is coming to closure on &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-masque-connect-udp&#34;&gt;CONNECT_UDP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/id/draft-ietf-masque-h3-datagram-06.html&#34;&gt;HTTP Datagrams&lt;/a&gt; while &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-masque-connect-ip/&#34;&gt;CONNECT_IP&lt;/a&gt; has a few more issues to sort out.  Though QUIC and HTTP/3 are the focus of this work, these changes are being defined for HTTP/2 and HTTP/1.1 as well, implying the medium-term availability of robust proxying options in the Internet&amp;rsquo;s service hubs.  As we mentioned in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth-05.html&#34;&gt;HTTP Transport Authentication&lt;/a&gt; is an idea for privately authenticating these flows.  We hope this work gets picked up again upon completion of these three initial efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF113 Hackathon Project</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/20/ietf113-hackathon-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2022/03/20/ietf113-hackathon-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post begins a daily blog, live from IETF113 in Vienna Austria, March 19-25, 2022 (first in-person meeting after six remote-only meetings during the COVID pandemic).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/how/runningcode/hackathons/113-hackathon/&#34;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; event kicks off IETF and, at this meeting,  we picked up work originally done by one of our teammates implementing version 5 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth-05.html&#34;&gt;Internet Draft HTTP Transport Authentication&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;HTTP Transport Authentication&lt;/em&gt; is designed to authenticate such protocol flows in a manner that does not reveal any information to an attacker during failure cases.  Therefore, applications using &lt;em&gt;HTTP Transport Authentication&lt;/em&gt; are resistant to active probing by network adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got the original code running in Google Conscrypt (TLS for Java/Android), verified its function (as defined in the Internet Draft) and created a public open source repository with a demonstration capability. We presented the work to Hackathon attendees (~50 people) and discussed the work with the specification’s author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the specification for HTTP Transport Authentication &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth-05.html&#34;&gt;Internet Draft&lt;/a&gt;.  Here’s our  implementation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/HTTPTransportAuthentication&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF: Year End Review 2021</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/12/23/ietf-year-end-review-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/12/23/ietf-year-end-review-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In terms of potential impact on Internet Freedom, it’s been a banner year at the Internet Engineering Task Force &lt;a href=&#34;https://ietf.org/&#34;&gt;(IETF)&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/rfc9000/&#34;&gt;QUIC&lt;/a&gt; (featuring the improved privacy and security of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc8446&#34;&gt;TLS1.3&lt;/a&gt;) reached Proposed Standard status, with implementations and rollouts from every major vendor on both server and client, and with multiple &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QUIC#Source_Code&#34;&gt;open source toolkit options&lt;/a&gt; for developers.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-tls-esni/&#34;&gt;Encrypted Client Hello&lt;/a&gt; for TLS1.3 gained traction via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://defo.ie&#34;&gt;DEfO project&lt;/a&gt; that, through pull requests, makes a huge privacy enhancement easily available to the major security library (OpenSSL) underpinning the Internet’s most important service engines (nginx, apache, lighttpd, haproxy on the server, even curl on the client).  IP address privacy got new attention with a working group formed around Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/charter-ietf-ohai/&#34;&gt;OHAI&lt;/a&gt;), as did Privacy-Preserving Measurement (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/bofreq-privacy-preserving-measurement/&#34;&gt;PPM&lt;/a&gt;) which seeks to drastically reduce the amount of personal information swept up in the pervasive monitoring of all public Internet activity.  Meanwhile, the Internet Research Task Force (&lt;a href=&#34;https://irtf.org&#34;&gt;IRTF&lt;/a&gt;) has focused on developing new cryptographic techniques to serve these rapidly-evolving privacy-focused activities. IRTF also fosters work on truly-global Internet access and, in a sense, serves as the IETF’s conscience through it’s work on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/rg/hrpc/about/&#34;&gt;human rights implications of protocol design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s valid to ask: will the Internet be more free when/if these proposals become widely-deployed standards? While there’s sound reason for hope, I see two major concerns that could significantly reduce the positive impact of this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first concern is extreme pushback from the major state actors who want more control over how their citizens use the Internet.  While QUIC, TLS1.3 and ECH appear to be headed for full adoption in regions where the Internet is already nominally free, they amount to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.poker.org/poker-hands-ranking-chart/&#34;&gt;royal flush&lt;/a&gt; for the good guys in the regions where it is not. The reaction? Stop playing the game (the major state actors have already blocked QUIC).  What’s going to be the reaction when ECH makes ubiquitous domain-fronting possible?  Will that just increase the number of states participating in blocking QUIC?  It’s important to remember, state actors &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huawei.com/us/technology-insights/industry-insights/innovation/new-ip&#34;&gt;have options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second concern is centralization.  The Internet has gotten more centralized over time, both in the way the breadth of its content is hosted and in the number of services users visit to view that content.  Further, national gateways have seen massive consolidation in the last five years as most states reduce exposure in the name of terrorism prevention and reducing the flow of disinformation.  This centralization has worsened the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/rfc7258/&#34;&gt;pervasive monitoring&lt;/a&gt; all users suffer under and has made it difficult (at best) to trust service providers with even the most benign-seeming of our personal data. Yet, the privacy solutions under development at IETF - OHAI and PPM, along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass&lt;/a&gt; and others - all rely on layers of new infrastructure operated by these same providers, seeming to require us to put even more trust in them.  Directionally, is that sustainable?  It’s important to remember, we users also &lt;a href=&#34;https://permission.io/blog/web-3-0/&#34;&gt;have options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2022, I’ll be looking more critically at how IETF addresses these concerns. IETF continues to be the most open and responsive standards organization determining the Internet’s future.  It feels like we’re reaching a point where Internet Freedom isn’t any longer a niche interest, but rather the central focus of progress for mankind in terms of our intercommunication as citizens of the planet. The best option would seem to be an IETF at the forefront of that progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing TLS Encrypted Client Hello</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/11/30/implementing-tls-encrypted-client-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/11/30/implementing-tls-encrypted-client-hello/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://defo.ie/&#34;&gt;DEfO&lt;/a&gt; project, we have been working on
accelerating the development &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-tls-esni-13.html&#34;&gt;Encrypted Client Hello
(ECH)&lt;/a&gt; as
standardized by the IETF.  ECH is the next step in improving Transport Layer
Security (TLS).  TLS is one of the basic building blocks of the internet, it is
what puts the S in HTTPS.  The ECH standard is nearing completion.  That is
exciting because ECH can encrypt the last plaintext TLS metadata that it is
possible to encrypt.  So ECH will bring some real improvements in privacy and
censorship resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH is built on top of TLSv1.3 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/handshake-encryption-endgame-an-ech-update/&#34;&gt;completes unfinished
work&lt;/a&gt;
from the TLSv1.3 effort, now that private DNS is a thing. ECH is now in draft-13
and there are many implementations that are interoperating. ECH is working for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/openssl&#34;&gt;OpenSSL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/boringssl/issues/detail?id=275&#34;&gt;BoringSSL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/nginx&#34;&gt;nginx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/httpd&#34;&gt;Apache HTTPD&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/lighttpd1.4&#34;&gt;lighttpd&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sftcd/haproxy/commits/ECH-experimental&#34;&gt;HAProxy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/conscrypt/tree/2.6.alpha1638179154.job1828169525&#34;&gt;Conscrypt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niallor/curl&#34;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt;, and more. There is work underway in &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1725938&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=1091403&#34;&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt;. It has been sketched out for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/square/okhttp/issues/6539&#34;&gt;OkHTTP&lt;/a&gt;. Draft versions of ESNI
and ECH have been deployed in Firefox releases and some production web services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main downside of ECH is that it is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://defo.ie/report.html#issuesarising&#34;&gt;complex&lt;/a&gt;, and most of that is
unavoidable.  Large scale websites have complicated server-side setups, and ECH
has to work in those setups.  That is where ECH&amp;rsquo;s complexity comes from.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-dnsop-svcb-https-07.html&#34;&gt;DNS
SVCB and HTTPS RR
Types&lt;/a&gt; is a
related standard to encapsulate the complexity of large scale websites a single
DNS lookup.  It adds additional complexity since it might include the TCP port
number for the service, while TLS implementations mostly assume that the port
number is known before doing a DNS lookup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH was formerly known as Encrypted SNI (ESNI), which it replaces.  So do not
expect updates to ESNI unless ECH proves too complicated for implementers. ECH
is more complex to implement in the TLS library than ESNI.  Once it is
implemented in the TLS library, then implementing the next level of managing the
keys and hostnames is quite similar between ESNI and ECH.  The rest of this post
will be diving into details about that complexity and what it takes to implement
ECH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;do-not-stick-out.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Do Not Stick Out&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-stick-out&#34;&gt;Do Not Stick Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH implementers must also work to ensure that their implementation does not
create packets that look &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-tls-esni-13.html#name-do-not-stick-out&#34;&gt;look
different&lt;/a&gt;
than other implementations.  How ECH is implemented will affect
fingerprintability.  Right now, BoringSSL, OpenSSL, and Firefox all put the ECH
extension in different places, so it is easy for a network observer to tell
which of them is serving as the client in a TLS session.  Ideally, all
implementations would create network packages that look identical to the network
observer.  To get an idea of this problem in the real world, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/anti-censorship/pluggable-transports/snowflake/-/issues/40014&#34;&gt;this detailed
technical
discussion&lt;/a&gt;
of metadata ordering in DTLS as used in WebRTC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-keys&#34;&gt;Getting the keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH encrypts the first stage of the negotiation between the client and server,
the &lt;em&gt;ClientHello&lt;/em&gt; packet using a new type of key and related configuration.
This is known as an &amp;ldquo;ECH Config&amp;rdquo;.  This negotiation is what sets up the
encrypted TLS connection, so to encrypt the negotiation, so the keys can not be
derived from the certificates and negotiation itself.  ECH also needs new
methods distributing this ECH Config.  HTTPS/SVCB therefore includes ECH Config Lists,
and DNS is the recommended way to get ECH Config Lists.  Other distribution
methods are also possible, and ECH implementation should provide a method to
directly supply ECH Config Lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using ECH in conjunction with HTTPS/SVCB, the DNS needs to be handled differently
than the common, decades old practices that most TLS stacks are built on.  The
ECH Config List must match the IP address so that multi-CDN setups still work.
That ensures the server gets the ECH Config that matches its ECH private keys,
not the one for a separate server.  If the A/AAAA lookup is done separately from
the HTTPS/SVCB lookup, they might not match since the results could come from
different caches, etc.  It is not yet clear where the right place to handle that
DNS is, but it is clear that clients that implement HTTPS/SVCB and ECH will need to
consider that DNS will touch different parts of the stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which part of the stack will handle the HTTPS/SVCB look up depends on whether
the code is acting as a library or more as the client itself.  For example,
libraries like OkHTTP or Conscrypt can both act as a TLS library, providing the
blocks for implementing TLS in an app.  They can also act as the TLS client
itself, the app just needs to open the hostname and port to get a connection.
This is especially true for OkHTTP, which can also handle DNS itself with its
own DNS-over-HTTPS implementation.  Most apps will expect to just open a URL and
have it work without providing anything else.  In the case of HTTP libraries
like OkHTTP or Volley, Conscrypt becomes the provider of TLS functions rather
than the client.  OkHTTP&amp;rsquo;s default setup will probably want to treat Conscrypt
like the client and do zero config.  But there are use cases where apps want to
handle DNS in OkHTTP, in that case Conscrypt is a library.  Another way this
could be broken down would be to have Conscrypt only be the TLS library, then
leave the DNS to the HTTP stacks.  Then each HTTP library would have to have
their own ECH and HTTPS/SVCB handling (In Android, that would mean
&lt;tt&gt;HttpURLConnection&lt;/tt&gt;, OkHTTP, Volley, Apache HTTP Client, etc).  Python
provides another example with HTTP libraries like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/psf/requests/issues/5972&#34;&gt;Requests&lt;/a&gt; working in
combination with the core &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.python.org/issue45567&#34;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that is clear here: whichever piece initiates the HTTPS/SVCB DNS query
should also handle the ECH Config, and setting up the lower levels.  On top of
this, ECH has GREASE and &amp;ldquo;Retry Configs&amp;rdquo;.  GREASE is a key part of ensuring that
ECH connections do not stick out.  GREASE makes the network observer see TLS
packets that look the same as connections that successfully used an ECH Config
to encrypt.  Retry Configs are sent by the server if it cannot decrypt what the
client sent.  Whichever piece of the code handles the ECH Config List should
then also handle GREASE and the Retry Configs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/encrypted-client-hello/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tls-ech-negotiation.png&#34; alt=&#34;TLS ECH Negotiation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outer-and-inner-clienthello&#34;&gt;Outer and Inner &lt;em&gt;ClientHello&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post began by saying that ECH was complex.  Most of that complexity stems
from the concept of &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloOuter&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloInner&lt;/em&gt;.  They are sort of
parallel versions of the TLS &lt;em&gt;ClientHello&lt;/em&gt;, with &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloOuter&lt;/em&gt; being
plaintext and &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloInner&lt;/em&gt; being encrypted.  Many of the same bits of
metadata can be set in either &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloOuter&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloInner&lt;/em&gt;, or even
in both.  And the outer and inner values can be different.  For example, the
outer plaintext SNI could be set to a generic domain name, while the inner could
be set to a different domain name that the client wants to protect.  Whenever
the client needs to manage what is set in &amp;ldquo;inner&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;outer&amp;rdquo;, etc., then extra
complexity is exposed all the way up to the app using the ECH client.  Also, so
many possible configuration options also means so many ways that the negotiation
might fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BoringSSL&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;SSL_set1_ech_config_list()&lt;/code&gt; provides a good example of this complexity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a supported ECHConfig is found, &lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; will encrypt the true
ClientHello parameters. If the server cannot decrypt it, e.g. due to a key
mismatch, ECH has a recovery flow. &lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; will handshake using the
cleartext parameters, including a public name in the ECHConfig. If using
&lt;tt&gt;SSL_CTX_set_custom_verify&lt;/tt&gt;, callers should use
&lt;tt&gt;SSL_get0_ech_name_override&lt;/tt&gt; to verify the certificate with the public
name. If using the built-in verifier, the &lt;tt&gt;X509_STORE_CTX&lt;/tt&gt; will be
configured automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no other errors are found in this handshake, it will fail with
&lt;tt&gt;SSL_R_ECH_REJECTED&lt;/tt&gt;. Since it didn&amp;rsquo;t use the true parameters, the
connection cannot be used for application data. Instead, callers should handle
this error by calling &lt;tt&gt;SSL_get0_ech_retry_configs&lt;/tt&gt; and retrying the
connection with updated ECH parameters. If the retry also fails with
&lt;tt&gt;SSL_R_ECH_REJECTED&lt;/tt&gt;, the caller should report a connection failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-walk-through-which-pieces-needs-to-do-what&#34;&gt;A walk through which pieces needs to do what&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us return to the Python example to go through the pieces needed to implement
ECH there.  Starting at the lowest level, the Python &lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; is built on
top of OpenSSL, so the new ECH functions in OpenSSL need to be included and
exposed in &lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt;&amp;rsquo;s API.  Unlike with a plain TLSv1.3 connection,
&lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; would not set up an ECH connection without additional configuration
as long as &lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; does not include the additional DNS requirements needed
to fetch the ECH Config.  The DNS could instead be implemented in the HTTP
library.  Requests is built on top of urllib3, so urllib3 could implement
HTTPS/SVCB handling.  Then Requests would automatically get ECH connections.
Since it can be necessary to handle the ECH Config outside of DNS, urllib3 and
Requests could provide methods for the app to submit the ECH Config.  This would
mean overriding any HTTPS/SVCB handling in Requests and urllib3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this outline, these are the pieces that need to be implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTPS/SVCB DNS queries for getting ECH Config Lists, IP, and other config.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A way to provide ECH Config Lists as bytes directly to the &lt;tt&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A method to ensure encrypted DNS is used so all metadata is encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A method to enable and disable GREASE, ideally with GREASE default on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A callback that gets called whenever ECH negotiation fails and the server
offers a &amp;ldquo;Retry Config&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially also controls of what to send in the &lt;em&gt;ClientHelloOuter&lt;/em&gt; versus the
&lt;em&gt;ClientHelloInner&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the point of view of the client implementation, there is a big difference
between TLS before and after ECH.  This new complexity may look scary but this
is a clear path to providing strong privacy protections with TLS that can be as
widely deployed as TLSv1.3 is now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IETF112 - Meeting Update (November 2021)</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/11/24/ietf112-meeting-update-november-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/11/24/ietf112-meeting-update-november-2021/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The 112th meeting of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) took place November 8-12, 2021 - as a virtual event for the sixth time in succession due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Here’s a summary of the work I found important to the Internet Freedom community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-preserving-measurement&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we often (rightly) focus on unwanted surveillance of targeted individuals by nation-states and other bad actors, the Internet’s surveillance economy presents a major threat to personal privacy and freedom for all users of the Internet, as Mozilla so aptly describes on &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/State_Of_The_Internet/Surveillance_Economy&#34;&gt;this wiki page&lt;/a&gt;. Since IETF significantly boosted its focus on privacy at IETF105 (July 2019, where privacy was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/105/materials/slides-105-ietf-sesse-privacy-modern-concerns-steven-m-bellovin-00&#34;&gt;plenary topic&lt;/a&gt;), participants at both research and engineering levels have begun to address this problem - initially with research studies and statements of requirements, and then with proposals.  Later we’ll discuss proposals that try to offer more anonymity in the way users access the Internet. But new at this conference was a Birds of a Feather session formed around the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/bofreq-privacy-preserving-measurement/&#34;&gt;Privacy Preserving Measurement&lt;/a&gt; (PPM) and led by Mozilla’s Eric Rescorla who has collected significant thoughts and technical ideas &lt;a href=&#34;https://educatedguesswork.org/tags/privacy%20preserving%20measurement/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  This thinking would insert a layer of protection between end users and the data collection infrastructure in a way that would significantly impact the bad (for privacy) practices of current-term measurement tools - over-collection, under-protection and deep-interlinking.  An architecture for PPM was proposed and, as there was significant interest from IETF attendees, a Working Group is being established to undertake the technical effort.  There is a future work effort here to understand how this work overlaps or dove-tails with &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleaninsights.org&#34;&gt;CleanInsights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oh-hi-oblivious-http-application-intermediation&#34;&gt;Oh, Hi! (Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representative of over-collection, under-protection and deep-interlinking is the common practice of linking together sequences of interactions within or across services.  Particularly pernicious are interactions with the DNS (the centralized monitor that can easily catalog all the sites a user visits when name resolution is requested) but the problem generalizes to other core services as well as simple browsing.  While services like Tor work to make the practice of linkage difficult, this approach shares a fingerprint with bots and attackers, inducing providers to, at minimum, make the anonymous user experience difficult.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/ohai/about/&#34;&gt;Oblivious HTTP Application Intermediation&lt;/a&gt; (OHAI) is a new Working Group addressing the problem of request linking in a manner that reduces the negative experience for users while keeping the bots at bay.   The Working Group’s initial focus will not be safe browsing, however.  It will instead focus on generalizing the earlier work on DNS over HTTPS (&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/id/draft-ietf-doh-dns-over-https-10.html&#34;&gt;DoH&lt;/a&gt;) and an earlier &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-pauly-dprive-oblivious-doh/&#34;&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; specific to DNS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ip-address-privacy&#34;&gt;IP Address Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The network addressing mechanism used by the Internet Protocol was among the most innovative concepts of the early Internet.  But the Internet’s pioneers did not anticipate that, over time, the IP address would become an enforcement mechanism for censors and state prosecutors as well as the most attractive tracking token for the surveillance economy.  IETF has &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ip-address-privacy-considerations/&#34;&gt;begun an investigation&lt;/a&gt; into this problem.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.broadband-forum.org&#34;&gt;Broadband Forum&lt;/a&gt; - whose manufacturers provide the majority of WiFi access points to the Internet - has undertaken its own study, to be published in 2022.  Both studies catalog the abuses themselves and the technically-sound and unsound ways in which the IP address is currently put to use in managing networks.  Separately, CDN provider Cloudflare has been researching &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/addressing-agility/&#34;&gt;Addressing Agility&lt;/a&gt; (decoupling IP addresses from DNS domain names, at Internet scale, on the server side).  This latter effort points the way to at least one approach for curbing IP address abuse, though no concrete proposals have yet been brought to IETF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;masque-multiplexed-application-substrate-over-quic-encryption&#34;&gt;MASQUE (Multiplexed Application Substrate over QUIC Encryption)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QUIC (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/quic/about/&#34;&gt;the protocol&lt;/a&gt;) and MASQUE (a &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/masque/documents/&#34;&gt;set of activities&lt;/a&gt; to formalize the legitimate ways in which network traffic can be proxied using QUIC’s enhanced performance, security and privacy) are now mainstay IETF activities.  Of importance at IETF112, this question: Do QUIC and MASQUE, taken together, represent a mechanism that creates an overlay atop the heritage Internet?  And if so, what does that (or will that) mean?  An oversimplified pessimistic view is that these tools can be used to eliminate the (public) Internet in favor of an oligopoly of private networks that will, among themselves, define the rules for how they interconnect and how users connect to them.  An oversimplified optimistic view is that the same tools can be used to prevent such an oligopoly and enhance the public Internet (in fact, University of California Berkeley-affiliated researchers presented some work promoting &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccronline.sigcomm.org/2021/revitalizing-the-public-internet-by-making-it-extensible/&#34;&gt;a similar plan&lt;/a&gt;).  Is this where the &lt;em&gt;long Internet&lt;/em&gt; battle is going to be fought?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-thoughts&#34;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m ten conferences into my participation at IETF, and there are certainly patterns forming. Focusing solely on Internet Freedom, one can fairly ask if the kinds of solutions we see proposed at IETF are the right ones.  Is IETF the right forum for making decisions about planet-wide human freedom of communication and interaction? Or is IETF too compromised by its constituent organizations?  Or, rather, does that make IETF the perfect place to address the key technical questions in our increasingly-technical world?  The only certainty would seem to be that participation in this forum is the best way to understand how the situation is evolving and what avenues are available to have a voice in that evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IETF and Internet Freedom</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/10/18/the-ietf-and-internet-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/10/18/the-ietf-and-internet-freedom/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems useful to clarify the relationship between the near-term work of keeping the Internet open on a daily basis - work that dominates the efforts of the Internet Freedom community - and the long term work of the industry on crafting operational standards for the same network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those involved in Internet Freedom are typically focused on the “problems of today”, creating solutions using existing technologies offering immediate effect.  Often, it’s hard to tell if Internet standards are helping, hurting, or just in the way.  However, looking back at the (roughly) 15-year history of Internet Freedom work, it’s useful to recognize the many times we’ve said to ourselves “*Gosh, I would have done that differently if I’d had a chance to think about it*”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standards bodies offer one mechanism for broad deliberation on what it means to have the opportunity of a universally-accessible Internet.  There’s a lot of time to “*think about it*”, there’s input from many stakeholders and broad involvement in getting the final document &amp;ndash; the standard &amp;ndash; written.   For several years now, members of the Internet Freedom community have been asking themselves if such a process is useful in their context.  It’s easy to imagine, for example, that if the community had spent even a small effort over fifteen years voicing its concerns over, and hopes for, Internet Freedom to the right standards bodies, there might be more … Internet freedom.   We’re testing that theory now, taking part in the activities of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org&#34;&gt;Internet Engineering Task Force&lt;/a&gt; (IETF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-ietf&#34;&gt;What is the IETF?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1993 the IETF has operated as the standards-development body of the Internet under the auspices of the Internet Society, an international membership-based non-profit organization.  The IETF is the formal successor to similar (but smaller) bodies - based in the United States - that participated in orchestrating and managing the deployment of the Internet after 1981, when the original research project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARPANET&#34;&gt;ARPANet&lt;/a&gt;) was expanded into the global scientific community.   The Internet became a fully public entity in the mid-1990s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IETF is organized into informal topic-based discussion groups (“birds of a feather”, BoFs) and formal “working groups”. Membership in these groups is open to the public, both for in-person and mailing-list participation.  International participation is encouraged.  The IETF operates, formally, in an inclusive manner and maintains a strict code-of-conduct for its activities that encourages “small voices” to participate.  The IETF operates in a bottom-up manner for idea development and task-creation, largely driven by these groups.  The Internet Architecture Board (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Architecture_Board&#34;&gt;IAB&lt;/a&gt;) plays a modest role in defining vision and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rough_consensus&#34;&gt;Rough consensus&lt;/a&gt; is the primary basis for decision making. There are no formal voting procedures. An important part of rough consensus is demonstrated interoperability among independently-developed implementations of proposed standards.  Generally speaking, as work moves from “idea” toward “standard”, the act of clarifying the idea is informed by the act of implementing it.  In the early years of the IETF, this approach was unique among standards bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the details of IETF operations have changed considerably over time, the basic mechanism remains: (1) publication of a proposed specification, (2) development of software based on the proposal, (3) review and independent testing by participants, and (4) republication as a revised proposal, a draft standard, and possible, eventually as an Internet standard. Two types of working document are available: the Internet Draft (generally speaking, the idea) and the Request for Comment (generally speaking, the standard).  It is perhaps a credit to the spirit of iterative improvement through constant testing and discussion that IETF’s completed documents are not titled “Internet Standard”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An allied organization within IETF is the Internet Research Task Force (&lt;a href=&#34;https://irtf.org/&#34;&gt;IRTF&lt;/a&gt;) that promotes longer-term research on the evolution of the Internet.  Made up largely of academic researchers, IRTF operates in a manner that brings cutting edge research into the decision-making processes of IETF activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-s-who-at-ietf&#34;&gt;Who’s Who at IETF?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern IETF is composed of technical representatives from commercial vendors, academic researchers, researchers and advocates from non-profit entities and independent “concerned citizens”.   While the IETF’s modern code of conduct makes it possible for anyone to attend a meeting or mailing list and have a voice in the conversation, the IETF remains an “implementation-centric” forum.  That is, “talk is cheap” and ideas have to be implementable - or have impact on implementations - to be considered for standardization.  Thus, individuals and organizations who are successful within IETF are able to both espouse their ideas and “code them up” (or, at minimum, understand the process of coding them and the hard problems that arise from coding them).   Experience shows, however, that these criteria still allow for a broad range of meaningful participation and impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IETF now has the Human Rights Protocol Considerations (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/rg/hrpc/about/&#34;&gt;HRPC&lt;/a&gt;) research group (chartered in 2017) monitoring and informing IETF working groups.  HRPC draws its mission directly from RFC 1958 (“Architectural Principles of the Internet”, 1996).  Key participants include both technical people and rights advocates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Architecture Board (IAB) has, as of 2019, given considerable attention to the problem of privacy (as distinct from the IETF’s successful, long-duration work on security).  The Privacy Enhancements and Assessment Research Group (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/rg/pearg/about/&#34;&gt;PEARG&lt;/a&gt;) brings important research activities on privacy to the IETF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-some-memorable-ietf-standards&#34;&gt;What are some memorable IETF standards?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specifications for Internet Protocol (IP, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc791&#34;&gt;RFC 791&lt;/a&gt; in 1981), Transmission Control Protocol (TCP, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc793&#34;&gt;RFC 793&lt;/a&gt; in 1981) and Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc1945&#34;&gt;RFC 1945&lt;/a&gt; in 1996) are the foundation of the modern Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most significant update to the foundational protocols is Quick UDP Internet Connections (QUIC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc9000&#34;&gt;RFC 9000&lt;/a&gt; in 2016), a new “hybrid” transport protocol informed by the evolved use cases impacting TCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most significant technical update, in terms of the Internet Freedom community’s interest, was Transport Layer Security Version 1.0 (TLS, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc2246&#34;&gt;RFC 2246&lt;/a&gt; in 1999) and its improved form, Version 1.1 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc4346&#34;&gt;RFC 4346&lt;/a&gt; in 2006).  Two important “Best Current Practice” pieces impacting Internet Freedom are &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc7258&#34;&gt;RFC 7258&lt;/a&gt; “Pervasive Monitoring Is An Attack” and &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-irtf-hrpc-guidelines/&#34;&gt;draft-irtf-hrpc-guidelines-10&lt;/a&gt; “Guidelines for Human Rights Protocol and Architecture Considerations”.  These works have stimulated a significant portion of IETF&amp;rsquo;s activity on privacy and Internet accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;among-the-current-work-of-ietf-what-is-most-important-to-the-internet-freedom-community&#34;&gt;Among the current work of IETF, what is most important to the Internet Freedom community?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS 1.3 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc8446&#34;&gt;RFC 8446&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) was designed for long-lived connections between clients and servers.  HTTP broke that in a big way and Transport Layer Security (TLS) magnified the problem further, with the two biggest challenges being the lengthy setup (or “handshake”) phase and the negotiation of cryptographic modes and strategies, many of which quickly went out of date.  TLS 1.3 is an effort to mitigate these challenges with so-called Zero-RTT.   More importantly, TLS 1.3 fixes a few security flaws created by wrong assumptions made in earlier designs.  See below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-tls-esni/&#34;&gt;ECH / eSNI&lt;/a&gt; (draft)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encrypted Client Hello (ECH/ECHo) is successor work to the earlier Encrypted Server Name Identifier (eSNI) effort.  Security requirements evolve as bad actors get smarter.  While the designers of TLS thought they’d made the transport layer “secure” (thus, the name), several omissions were quickly spotted.  Among these was the public visibility of the requested server name (the SNI).  A plan was put forward to encrypt the SNI, but quickly that too became insufficient and a plan was advanced to encrypt the entire “client hello” message - that is, all the data that exists about the attempted connection before the actual encrypted session begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECH/eSNI has its opponents, of course.  TLS 1.3 is already blocked in specific geographies because of this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS Security (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc7858&#34;&gt;DoT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc8484&#34;&gt;DoH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/dnssec/charter/&#34;&gt;DNSSEC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-pauly-dprive-oblivious-doh-04.html&#34;&gt;Oblivious DNS&lt;/a&gt;, Private DNS, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key benefit of the Internet over pre-existing networking techniques was the ability to address servers using human-readable names.  Old-schoolers recognize this was, in fact, a late-arriving component of the Internet protocols and, in some minds, handled in an ill-considered manner.  That skepticism has been borne out in numerous failures of the Domain Name Service (DNS) and, in more recent times, the way in which DNS has been co-opted by national authorities in certain geographies - malicious operators of the DNS can know all the servers/services you visit based solely on the server names you want resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many schemes being advanced to improve this situation.  Private DNS abrogates the architected “hierarchy of authority” built into the original DNS (which is the part that’s been broken by malicious providers) and implies “trust Google” or “trust Cloudflare”.  DNSSEC is a collection of small, but meaningful, improvements to the DNS implementation aimed at sealing off the (many) leaks of metadata found in the original DNS design.  DNS-over-HTTP (DoH) and DNS-over-TLS (DoT) provide ways for an individual user’s web browser to select a trustworthy DNS provider (like the Private DNS providers) and ask them to do their lookups over a secure link.  ObliviousDNS could (in theory) remove even the need to have a trusted provider (though it adds the idea of a “trusted proxy”.  A further advantage with ObliviousDNS (and the other “Oblivious” proposals, and the reason for the term) is that the user’s IP address is not leaked either (the bugaboo of most other privacy schemes being proposed in standards bodies).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/privacypass/about/&#34;&gt;Privacy Pass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bots, it seems, have taken over the Internet.  Automated programs submit billions of requests to websites, probing in most cases for weaknesses or purposely attempting to flood the system.  With provision of most web content now in the hands of a tiny number of content delivery networks, those networks put up defenses in the form of “roadblocks” that only humans can cross.  This has become overbearing on some services, to the frustration of users.  One attempted solution is Privacy Pass.  The idea is to provide valid users (who’ve successfully crossed the roadblock once) with a token that can be presented on many future accesses so the roadblock is not in their way again.  A key criteria for this token, however, is that it can not be used to identify and track an individual (human) across their access to many sites served by the content delivery network.  If implemented properly, Privacy Pass could be a big win for users who don’t want their access tracked and monitored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messaging Layer Security (&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/mls/about/&#34;&gt;MLS&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, while secure messaging systems exist, the mechanisms by which they implement security for “group messaging” (greater than 2 parties) are typically divergent from standards, layered in a proprietary way on top of standards, or do not scale to large conversations.  MLS is an activity designed to improve this situation by applying the lessons (good and bad) learned with TLS.  MLS also hopes to achieve what has now been defined as a modern level of security and privacy (thanks to the Signal team who raised the bar quite high).  MLS defines both an architecture and protocol that would standardize the way privacy and security are provided, with room for future upgrade, without denying the individuality of each service and that application-level feature demands of the different user groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-limits-to-ietf-s-effectiveness&#34;&gt;What are the limits to IETF’s effectiveness?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should reject the idea that “the standards process is too slow”.  IETF’s method of working dramatically speeds up the standards process while still allowing for as much disagreement and clarification as required for a standard to be considered “deliberative”.  Further, the end result of IETF standardization is not only a descriptive document, but multiple interoperable implementations of that document’s standard.  Again, that’s another big difference between IETF and the strictly “declarative” standards bodies.  With few exceptions, IETF has avoided the problems of too-early standardization based on a fad or a reaction, while still being responsive to perceived needs - be they technical or social/cultural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is, however, the Hammer/Nail analogy: when you’re a hammer, everything looks like a nail.  The IETF solves problems using the Internet infrastructure, even when certain problems might be better solved elsewhere, or in ways that are not infrastructural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-most-important-problem-to-internet-freedom-facing-ietf-today&#34;&gt;What is the most important problem (to Internet Freedom) facing IETF today?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There appears to be broad agreement that the most important problem facing the IETF is “The Problem of Centralization”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centralization initially arose in the hardware sense as the mesh of routers that connect the Internet fell into fewer and fewer hands.  This happened “innocently”, over time, and in the name of cost efficiency.  But this slow change violated one of the fundamental design strengths of the Internet’s original core architecture: resilience.  In recent times, there has been a strong tendency for nation-states to acquire tight control over the gateway routers that allow traffic into and out of their geographic area, further decreasing the resiliency of the Internet and serving as a vehicle for censorship and mass surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem has been further complicated and accelerated by the development of data centers of unimagined scale and worldwide presence whose internal operations are largely opaque and filled with “middle boxes” performing specialized tasks.  Unfortunately, the presence of these “middle boxes” can slow the pace of technological change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, and mostly unimagined at the dawn of the Internet, a small set of application software service providers has come to dominate Internet traffic and exercise an oversized amount of influence on the way users perceive the Internet or are allowed access to its resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem of centralization is magnified at IETF due to the organization’s inherent nature of “defining the Internet”.  Its solutions are “large scale” and large scale solutions by definition fall into the hands of the largest organizations.  Thus, it can sometimes seem that the IETF has moved far from the founding principles of decentralized, decoupled, cooperative, associative solutions that characterized the original Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, sometimes it takes a pendulum-swing of the magnitude we now see to drive people to action.  And, by nature, IETF has a constantly-evolving but actively-engaged community.  The “big names” of thirty years ago have significantly less presence today.  There is hope, thus, that a new community of people who care about the problem of centralization will rise up to make their voices heard.  Indeed, there are signs this is already happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formally, the IRTF’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/rg/dinrg/history/&#34;&gt;Decentralized Internet Infrastructure Research Group&lt;/a&gt; was chartered in September 2017 to address the interest of infrastructure centralization.  Parallel (and in a way orthogonal) advancements in blockchain technology, distributed hash tables and decentralized cryptographic authority are creating what is effectively an “overlay network” on top of the Internet as defined by the IETF.  Colloquially, it’s being called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2020/01/06/what-is-web-3-0/?sh=4002a4bc58df&#34;&gt;Web 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.  These activities have forced IETF to take notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-next-in-our-ietf-participation&#34;&gt;What’s next in our IETF participation?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring IETF activities - bringing that knowledge to the teams doing current-term Internet Freedom work - and presenting the current-term work of the Internet Freedom community to the IETF - has begun to bear fruit in terms of synergy between the two approaches to keeping the Internet open.  Discussion, however, will probably not be enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important way the community might participate is active (and early) involvement in the implementation of important IETF proposals.  Doing so would give the Internet Freedom community a “seat at the table” where core problems and concerns arise and where key decisions are made.   The Internet Freedom community brings extensive expertise in open source software development, a counterpoint to the mostly closed-source implementations undertaken by the IETF’s vendor organizations.  The benefits of transparency and loosely-coupled cooperation - so key to the most successful software projects that built the Internet - are difficult to overstate in this context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain of these efforts are already underway - ECH, and specifically the &lt;a href=&#34;https://defo.ie&#34;&gt;DEfO&lt;/a&gt; project, is an example - and the impact this is having on key pieces of “infrastructural” open source software (the Apache web server, the OpenSSL security layer, for example) is important.  Keeping open source software current and “in tune” with developing standards may be the best way to “square the circle” of Internet freedom work &amp;ndash; assuring that solutions to the problems and challenges of today lead to the creation of a better Internet for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Insights: February 2021 Update on Privacy-Preserving Measurement</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/10/clean-insights-february-2021-update-on-privacy-preserving-measurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2021/02/10/clean-insights-february-2021-update-on-privacy-preserving-measurement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings, all. I hope this finds you healthy and well, finding ways to enjoy the season (whichever it may be). While everyday still provides new challenges in the life of our team at Guardian Project, we continue to strive to be productive as productive as we can be in our professional and personal lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just posted an updated presentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleaninsights.org&#34;&gt;Clean Insights&lt;/a&gt;, reflecting on the symposium in May, and the work we have done since then. You can see and share it from here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vo6FI-WDLG0&#34;&gt;Watch update on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also listen to this update on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/podcast/2021/clean-insights-update.html&#34;&gt;Guardian Project Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://die.netzarchitekten.com/&#34;&gt;Benjamin Erhart&lt;/a&gt;, our lead developer on Clean Insights, we&amp;rsquo;ve made substantial progress over the last few months on delivering our new software development kits. If you visit our Gitlab project page, you will find design documents and SDKs for Android, iOS, Javascript (both for desktop and web) and soon Python (Thanks, to &lt;a href=&#34;https://irl.xyz&#34;&gt;Iain Learmonth&lt;/a&gt; for this contribution). While this work is ongoing, the code is stable, and we feel it is ready to start getting it into all of your hands, so that you can start asking all the questions we have yet to consider.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights&#34;&gt;Clean Insights on Gitlab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of how easy it is to implement a measurement of a specific event or a visit to certain view in your app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-android-sdk/-/blob/master/app/src/main/java/org/cleaninsights/example/Main2Activity.java#L48&#34;&gt;Sample code for Android integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still relying on Matomo as our backend aggregator, analysis tool and dashboard, and it continues to work well enough for our 1.0 solution. That said, to enhance the privacy of Clean Insight-enabled clients, we&amp;rsquo;ve design and implemented a proxy service, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-matomo-proxy&#34;&gt;Clean Insights Matomo Proxy&lt;/a&gt;. The CIMP reduces the amount of metadata and logging that Matomo can do, since it is only communicate to directly by the no-logging proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/cleaninsights/clean-insights-matomo-proxy&#34;&gt;Clean Insights Matomo Proxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this software is available for you to implement and deploy on your own. We also have a public testbed and hosted service available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.cleaninsights.org&#34;&gt;https://metrics.cleaninsights.org&lt;/a&gt; that we can make available for anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t able to run and maintain their own instance. We can also assist you with considering the insights you want to gain, threat modeling the risks it poses to your users, and implementing the SDK into your software, be it a mobile app, web app, desktop app, back-end service or operating system. Our deisgn partners at Okthanks also have a variety of concepts and soon sample projects and code for implementing effective and ethical Consent UX to achieve the right kind of &amp;ldquo;opt-in&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please reach out if you have interest in using Clean Insights. We have weekly scrum meetings, email lists and a public discussion room on the Matrix
network. More info on these on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleaninsights.org/dev&#34;&gt;Developer Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASQUE Review</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/02/25/masque-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/02/25/masque-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/masque/about/&#34;&gt;MASQUE&lt;/a&gt; is set of related IETF drafts for specifying flexible proxying built into a standard webserver.  It is meant to be deployed on a server that is serving public websites, then this connection can be reused for proxying generic connections.  It is very much a work in progress, so any of this can change.  It is currently built on top of the QUIC+HTTP/3 and HTTP/2+TLS+TCP protocols.  The website and proxy packets look the same, and all connections to the webserver will be shared and reused, regardless of whether its a web page request or proxy traffic.  Each new proxy/website request will reuse any existing connection, providing a key reduction in metadata that makes all the packets blend together from the point of view of the network observer.  For example, to prevent the network observer from corrolating requests to proxy with the outbound request to the destination, a client could first connect to the website, then some time later, connect to the proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QUIC is an Internet protocol on the verge of being standardized by the IETF, initially developed by Google.  Approximately 50% of traffic from Chrome browsers to Google sites currently use QUIC, so it already has some large scale adoption.  MASQUE is very similar to Meek and Encrypted &lt;em&gt;ClientHello&lt;/em&gt; (aka ECH or Encrypted SNI) domain fronting in how it functions, and all of them &amp;ldquo;hide in plain site&amp;rdquo; by making circumvention traffic look the same as traffic that censors are unwilling to block.  Like ESNI, MASQUE could be totally blocked in countries that deem QUIC too large a risk, e.g. China already blocks Google, so blocking the QUIC protocol right now would have very low cost to them.  So it must be rolled out and gain broad adoption before it can be an effective circumvention tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One use case is individuals enabling MASQUE on their personal websites, or organizations on their websites.  Another use case is to provide travelling employees with VPN access even with local networks are blocking VPNs based on the protocols (e.g. DPI to identify OpenVPN or Wireguard traffic).  Hosting providers and CDNs are not likely to to deploy MASQUE behind their main TLS certificate, as they are not willing to take the risk of getting blocked, just like with domain fronting.  MASQUE/QUIC does not change the domain fronting formula, instead, it just provides a different mechanism to leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key feature of MASQUE is a means of requiring authentication to the proxy before it gives any information back at all, including even if it exists.  It does this with a custom authentication method where the replies are defined only as &lt;code&gt;200 OK&lt;/code&gt; for successful authentication or &lt;code&gt;404 Not Found&lt;/code&gt; for everything else.  This is an idea that could also be used in Pluggable Transports in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;relation-to-pluggable-transports&#34;&gt;Relation to Pluggable Transports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MASQUE Obsfuscation and HTTP Transport Authentication pieces of MASQUE are directly relevant to Pluggable Transports (PT), and could be included as part of the suite of standards for implementing complete PT solutions.  The non-discoverable authentication method is useful for any PT that already requires some kind of key and is served via an public network socket.   Standardizing the proxy setup and configuration makes sense to do both for MASQUE as much as PT.  Right now, there are a wide variety of proxy configurations for PT with circumvention and VPN service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;masque-as-onion-routing-and-tor-components&#34;&gt;MASQUE as Onion Routing and Tor Components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some efforts to expand the scope of MASQUE into a Tor replacement based on QUIC and HTTP CONNECT proxies.  This is a nice idea, but it should not distract from the core MASQUE pieces which will provide real value now.  This area of work is now represented by three drafts: HTTP Transport Authentication, MASQUE Obfuscation, and MASQUE.  Without a drastically expanded scope, MASQUE cannot replace Tor.  It can provide one key but small building block: the base mechanism for onion routing based on HTTP CONNECT and QUIC.  This could potentially allow Tor middle relay services to be implemented with a standard webserver like nginx with only a small custom plugin.  This would not change the requirement for all of the various Tor network management services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-quic-tls-27&#34;&gt;https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-quic-tls-27&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2018-March/013026.html&#34;&gt;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2018-March/013026.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidschinazi.github.io/masque-drafts/draft-schinazi-masque.html&#34;&gt;https://davidschinazi.github.io/masque-drafts/draft-schinazi-masque.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidschinazi.github.io/masque-drafts/draft-schinazi-masque-obfuscation.html&#34;&gt;https://davidschinazi.github.io/masque-drafts/draft-schinazi-masque-obfuscation.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidschinazi.github.io/masque-drafts/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth.html&#34;&gt;https://davidschinazi.github.io/masque-drafts/draft-schinazi-httpbis-transport-auth.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/masque/Cxh1phx6vFgn19jyANmt2YwLDqQ/&#34;&gt;https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/masque/Cxh1phx6vFgn19jyANmt2YwLDqQ/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/104/materials/slides-104-secdispatch-the-masque-protocol-draft-schinazi-masque-00&#34;&gt;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/104/materials/slides-104-secdispatch-the-masque-protocol-draft-schinazi-masque-00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2019/04/16/exploring-possibilities-of-pluggable-transports-on-android/&#34;&gt;https://guardianproject.info/2019/04/16/exploring-possibilities-of-pluggable-transports-on-android/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
