<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Safety on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Safety on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 06:00:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Partnership with Circle of 6 mobile safety app</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/01/19/new-partnership-with-circle-of-6-mobile-safety-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 06:00:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/01/19/new-partnership-with-circle-of-6-mobile-safety-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circle of 6 Focuses on Security with Guardian Project Partnership&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Safety App Will Get End-to-End Encryption and More To Support High-Risk Communities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York, NY:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Two innovative organizations have partnered to bring increased digital security and privacy capabilities to users interested in improved safety for their mobile devices. Tech 4 Good, the developer of Circle of 6, a highly regarded mobile safety app developed to promote safety and health through networks of trust, has partnered with Guardian Project, a leader in mobile security and privacy technologies. The two organizations will work to upgrade the capabilities of the Circle of 6 app to provide users with secure messaging, private identities and improved physical security of device data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-13488 size-large&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Co6-Screens-1024x921.png&#34; width=&#34;945&#34; height=&#34;850&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Co6-Screens-1024x921.png 1024w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Co6-Screens-300x270.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Co6-Screens-768x691.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 945px) 100vw, 945px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Circle of 6 is coordinating with a number of organizations interested in expanding the focus of the app beyond general safety and defense against sexual violence, to include other high risk communities. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;“Circle of 6 is excited to forge this partnership with Guardian Project to bring increased privacy and security to our existing users and to new communities. We’ve received much interest globally in expanding the ways that Circle of 6 and its safety and connectivity features can be used in multiple contexts. This a thrilling step forward.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;– Nancy Schwartzman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Guardian Project will integrate its free and open-source software libraries to provide support for &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2016/01/12/panickit-making-your-whole-phone-respond-to-a-panic-button/&#34;&gt;multiple emergency hardware triggers&lt;/a&gt;, more &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/code/netcipher&#34;&gt;secure network communication&lt;/a&gt;, and defense against surveillance and censorship.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Updated and new versions of the app will be available by May 1, 2017. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Circle of 6:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Circle of 6 is a survivor-led and queer-led initiative, that takes a public health and harm-reduction approach to personal safety. Drawing from the experience of sexual assault survivors, youth health experts and LGBTQ users, Circle of 6 is designed to foster communities of support, encourage bystander intervention and provide inclusive and comprehensive resources. Circle of 6 was the winner of Vice President Biden’s “Apps Against Abuse” technology challenge and has 350,000 users in 36 countries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Guardian Project:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Guardian Project creates easy to use secure apps, open-source software libraries, and customized mobile dev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;ices&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;that can be used around the world by any person looking to protect their communications and personal data from unjust intrusion, interception and monitoring. With over 10 million users of its applications, and 100 million of its software libraries, Guardian Project has made a significant impact in improving the security and privacy of mobile users worldwide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
