<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jobs on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jobs on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Ruby/Jekyll contractors to start ASAP</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/12/06/seeking-ruby/jekyll-contractors-to-start-asap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/12/06/seeking-ruby/jekyll-contractors-to-start-asap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardian Project is seeking Ruby/Jekyll contractors for mobile/free software and privacy work!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for self-motivated, free software hackers to work with Guardian Project on privacy and internet freedom for mobile devices. Our work is 100% free software and we have a steady stream of projects that tie into F-Droid, Debian, Android, Fastlane, Mobifree and other exciting projects. We work to support people and communities around the world. This is a flexible, remote position but we also like to work in person when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-you&#34;&gt;About you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have at least a few years of experience with Ruby/Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demonstrated the ability to work collaboratively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understand public, free software workflows&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are proactive and self-directed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fluent in Git.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-points-for&#34;&gt;Bonus points for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debian (and derivatives)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experience with GitLab CI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and bash skills&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding privacy implications of metadata&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life experiences that are underrepresented in tech work&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fluency in more than one language&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;User research and UX design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blogging and writing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for projects managed by Hans-Christoph Steiner. We are centered in Vienna, Austria so ideally you work in a similar time zone, but that is not a requirement. We work in English but our team members speak many languages. This work is tied to specific projects and will be contracted per project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please reply to jobs@guardianproject.info or find us in any of the regular channels!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking part-time Grant Administrator</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/08/05/seeking-part-time-grant-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/08/05/seeking-part-time-grant-administrator/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Location: Fully remote (African/European time zone) or Vienna, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type: Part-time contractor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guardian Project is a small organization working to make a big impact in data privacy and secure communications. From the average person looking to use the internet and their mobile device more securely, to journalists needing to safely communicate with sources, to activists looking for secure communication channels, Guardian Project creates solutions that focus on privacy so you have true freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we started this work back in 2008, our team has grown significantly and our impact reach has as well. To help us scale our project even further, we are looking for a dynamic and skilled Grand Administrator to join our team. This role is crucial for the smooth operation of our contractor administration and the effective management of our grants and funding opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team is rooted in Vienna, Austria with a number of contractors around the world. We work mainly in English, our team members speak many languages. Work is contract-based but with the possibility to shift into full-time employment in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-ll-do&#34;&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ll do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;support-our-contractors&#34;&gt;Support our Contractors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team consists primarily of independent contractors, passionate about creating meaningful change through technological solutions. Our freelancers need your support in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drafting and executing working contracts for new and existing team members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding new team members and making them feel welcome, introducing them to our internal communication platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up email accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting monthly check-ins with team members to confirm the contract status and update records as necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process contractor invoices and liaise with our tax accountant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event planning and organizing our annual team retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;grant-management&#34;&gt;Grant Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our organization&amp;rsquo;s funding is partially dependent on grants, we are looking for someone to support us in all things grant management, including the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research and identify new upcoming grant and private funding opportunities relevant for our organization´s mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inform and liaise with the team to assess suitability and requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare grant applications together with team support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build and sustain relationships with grant funders and partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage reporting requirements for various grants, ensuring all reporting is accurate and submitted on time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;networking-and-relationship-management&#34;&gt;Networking and Relationship Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay up to date on industry events and networking opportunities to enhance visibility and outreach opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend industry conventions and gatherings to represent Guardian Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage leads for private funding opportunities and maintain relationships with existing and potential grant partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liaise with other impactful technology and human rights organizations around the world and stakeholders at different levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enhance-our-outreach-and-engagement&#34;&gt;Enhance our Outreach and Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor our blog and social media accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curate relevant content on our online channels to engage our community and enhance our impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-you-are&#34;&gt;Who You Are&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong organizational skills with the ability to manage multiple tasks and deadlines effectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results oriented and willing to expand your current skill set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal, with a knack for relationship building and stakeholder management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comfortable working independently in a small team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficient in using office and financial software, including MS Office and cloud-based document management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detail-oriented with a high level of accuracy in handling administrative and financial duties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-s-a-bonus-if-you&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bonus if you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a Bachelor’s degree in Business Administration or Non-profit Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have experience in grant writing and administration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have experience working in an international, multicultural team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are based in Vienna, Austria and can speak German&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What We Offer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A supportive and dynamic work environment where your work directly contributes to Guardian Project´s mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible working hours and vacation time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully or mostly remote work environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great deal of autonomy and responsibility, with a huge impact on our organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A competitive hourly rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-person team retreats and meet-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunities for professional development and growth within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ready-to-apply&#34;&gt;Ready to Apply?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send your resume and a cover letter explaining why you are a good fit for this position to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jobs@guardianproject.info&#34;&gt;jobs@guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;.  We aim to fill this position in September 2024.
Join us in our mission to create a safer, more secure internet and mobile experience! We look forward to receiving your application!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Slightly Paranoid Android Developers for Hire and Internships</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/11/10/seeking-slightly-paranoid-android-developers-for-hire-and-internships/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2010/11/10/seeking-slightly-paranoid-android-developers-for-hire-and-internships/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Guardian Project is kicking off a three month project focused on finishing up our secure chat app, codenamed &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/gibber&#34;&gt;Gibber&lt;/a&gt; but also known as “OtRChat”. We are looking for developers of all levels to join us in this work. We have already implemented the primary  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cypherpunks.ca/otr/&#34;&gt;“Off the Record” messaging&lt;/a&gt; functionality, and achieved interoperability with desktop clients such as Pidgin and AdiumX. From here, there is work to be done on implementing some unique features, cleaning up the user experience, and ensuring that the implementation is as secure as possible, providing all the necessary features for verifying and managing secure identities and sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a few contract positions available, but are also looking for interns and students interested in getting real-world production development under their belt. &lt;em&gt;All in all, you should be keenly interested in work that strives to find the right balance of usability and security on mobile devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/contact/join/&#34;&gt;get in touch with us&lt;/a&gt;, and we will go from there. We are looking for individuals or small teams. For the paid positions, we would expect you have at least one Android app released in public on the Android Market, and would prefer you have experience with open-source projects, as well. There is much more work to do beyond this specific app, but this is a good place to start. Work can be done anywhere, anytime, assuming your are familiar with the tools and culture of open-source+agile development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some screenshots of the work so far. You can learn more and check out the source on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/gibber&#34;&gt;Gibber app page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/account.jpg&#34; title=&#34;account&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;account&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/account-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;account&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;dt style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;dt style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;dt style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;dt style=&#34;display: inline !important;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;contacts&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/contacts.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;contacts&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/contacts-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;contacts&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;dt style=&#34;display: inline !important;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;secured&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/secured.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;secured&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/secured-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;secured&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
