<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Witness on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/witness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Witness on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 12:07:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/witness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Knight News funding of SecureSmartCam = a #WIN for open-source mobile security</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/03/29/knight-news-funding-of-securesmartcam-a-#win-for-open-source-mobile-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 12:07:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/03/29/knight-news-funding-of-securesmartcam-a-#win-for-open-source-mobile-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Along with our partner &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.witness.org&#34;&gt;WITNESS&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve entered our &lt;a href=&#34;http://newschallenge.tumblr.com/post/19436756887/securesmartcam-protecting-the-privacy-and-data-of&#34;&gt;SecureSmartCam project&lt;/a&gt; into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://newschallenge.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;Knight News Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, and we need your support to get to the next round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bit more about the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knight News Challenge, an international media innovation contest, is evolving – and will be offered three times, with three different topics. The first challenge will be centered on networks, and will accept applications Feb. 27 – March 17. The Networks challenge round seeks projects that use the best of existing software and platforms – those already integrated into people’s lives – to find new ways to convey news and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the merits of SecureSmartCam itself, specifically the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/ObscuraCam&#34;&gt;ObscuraCam&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/InformaCam&#34;&gt;InformaCam&lt;/a&gt; sub-projects, our research and development over the last two years on this project have extended to support an entire range of completely open-source mobile technology for Android developments, the benefits of which extend far beyond our own project itself. There are already many other organizations, projects, and apps (both commercial and non) that have incorporated our technology into their own solutions, not to mention the hundreds of thousands of users out there who depend on our core apps like &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/orbot&#34;&gt;Orbot (Tor for Android)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/gibber&#34;&gt;Gibberbot (Secure Chat)&lt;/a&gt; to safeguard their day to day communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work so far was largely funded by a generous private non-governmental donor, and if you look at the list of projects below, we have put that funding to great use. If we receive this funding from Knight (a similarly generous private donor), we will continue our work in this modular, open manner, ensuring that the money will benefit projects and causes far beyond our own personal vision and endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SecureSmartCam-supported Open-Source Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/gnupg-for-android&#34;&gt;GnuPG for Android&lt;/a&gt;: OpenPGP Public/Private Key Infrastructure for Encryption and Verification of Communications and Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqlcipher/android-database-sqlcipher&#34;&gt;SQLCipher for Android&lt;/a&gt;: AES-256 Symmetric Encryption Layer for SQLite Mobile Database. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zetetic.net/sqlcipher&#34;&gt;SQLCipher&lt;/a&gt; is also available for many other platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/iocipher&#34;&gt;IOCipher for Android&lt;/a&gt; (or any mobile platform): Encrypted filesystem built upon SQLCipher that works for any application without requiring root or custom device modification. This is an extension of our port of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/LUKS&#34;&gt;LUKS for Android&lt;/a&gt;, encrypted disk partition system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/android-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;FFMPEG for Android&lt;/a&gt; (with Video Redaction Filter): a build system and patches for compiling FFMPEG for Android, with support for custom features to enable video privacy controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/asenior/Jpeg-Redaction-Library&#34;&gt;Jpeg Redaction Library&lt;/a&gt;: a generic library for redacting visual and metadata information from JPEG images without needing to decode them. Very important for limited memory mobile devices!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/notepadbot&#34;&gt;NoteCipher for Android&lt;/a&gt;: Simple secure text, photo and video storage app for Android, built upon SQLCipher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/sscxfer/&#34;&gt;SSCXfer for Android&lt;/a&gt;: Anonymous, Proxied, Secure Video (or any file) Uploader (based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vidiom.mobi/&#34;&gt;Vidiom&lt;/a&gt; open-source project) over Tor to YouTube, VideoBin.org and other sites. By extension, this project also supports our core work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/info/apps/orbot&#34;&gt;Orbot, the Tor for Android&lt;/a&gt; application with hundreds of thousands of users worldwide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the approximately $300,000 of grant support we are seeking, is nothing compared to the millions of dollars in funding poured into closed-source mobile startups, who not only by a large majority fail, but also rarely share the components of their work in a way that moves everyone forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we need you to do is, go to our &lt;a href=&#34;http://newschallenge.tumblr.com/post/19436756887/securesmartcam-protecting-the-privacy-and-data-of&#34;&gt;SecureSmartCam Proposal on the Knight News Challenge Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, and “like”, comment, reblog or otherwise show your support for it, in as a public and visible a manner as possible. If you have concerns or questions, please post them to the Tumblr, and our team will reply to you there. This is open-source research after all, and don’t claim to have all the answers, but we do need your support to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing InformaCam</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/01/20/introducing-informacam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 13:58:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2012/01/20/introducing-informacam/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;These are interesting times, if you go by Times Magazine as an indicator. The magazine’s person of the year for 2011 was The Protester, preceded in 2010 by Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg. Both entities partners with equal stake in freely sharing the digital content that shows the world what’s going on in it, at any time, from behind any pair of eyes.&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1471&#34; alt=&#34;The Protester: Person of the Year&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/poy_cover-225x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/poy_cover-225x300.jpg 225w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/poy_cover.jpg 474w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px&#34; /&gt; Also casting in their lot with the others is Time Magazine’s 2006 person of the year, You: the You that puts the “you” in “user-generated content;” the You whose miasma of bits, bytes, and the powerful images they express are becoming increasingly problematic. Problematic and exciting. As governments, police forces, and other power players here and abroad crack down on voices of dissent, it is only You, The Protester, armed not with a press pass, but with a smartphone and a Twitter account, who brings the rest of the world its news. You do it mainly without either the support or permission of those in power, and this makes you a very important person in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smartphone’s role in the defense of human rights has thus become ever-more clear. How can we make it clearer? Our latest project, InformaCam, tackles this issue head-on. In collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.witness.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Witness.ORG&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;www.ibanet.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;International Bar Association&lt;/a&gt;, we’re building a powerful tool to create iron-clad digital images and video that could, should the occasion arise, be used in courts of law to bring justice. This is no small feat– with this project we are helping create the first evidentiary standards for digital media in the social networking age. So, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/node/21542748&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;there’s been a lot of excitement&lt;/a&gt; these past few weeks about InformaCam, as well as a lot of mystery. It’s time to give the project a proper unveiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InformaCam is a plugin for ObscuraCam that allows the user, without much intervention on their own part, to inflate image and video with extra points of data, or metadata. The metadata includes information like the user’s current GPS coordinates, altitude, compass bearing, light meter readings, the signatures of neighboring devices, cell towers, and wifi networks; and serves to shed light on the exact circumstances and contexts under which the digital image was taken. Some users will already be familiar with ObscuraCam, which allows for capturing and digitally manipulating media. With InformaCam included, the app starts to behave almost like Adobe Photoshop or GIMP, supporting non-destructive, layer-based edits to media. This means that a version of an image can be created with any sensitive image data and metadata preserved and encrypted to trusted entities, along with a redacted version that has its metadata stripped which can be easily shared to Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, or any public service the user wishes to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-informacam-works&#34;&gt;How InformaCam Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-1459&#34; alt=&#34;InformaCam (1)&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.18.27-PM.png&#34; width=&#34;205&#34; height=&#34;341&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.18.27-PM.png 205w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.18.27-PM-180x300.png 180w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 205px) 100vw, 205px&#34; /&gt; The workflow is similar to that of ObscuraCam, but with a few key differences. Notice that on start-up, the app triggers the on-board sensors. (Notifications in the top right corner clearly indicate the GPS and Bluetooth modules have been turned on.) This allows the app to register sensory and atmospheric data throughout the session. These “bundles” of data contain the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current timestamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device’s identification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User’s public (PGP) key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image Regions created in the image/video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current latitude &amp;amp; longitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current cell ID (if available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Altitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass bearing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether the user is taking a picture, or editing an existing piece of media, the app registers the goings-on, and signs each bundle of data with the user’s private key. This mean that all actions taken on a piece of media (from capture to editing) are attributed to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with ObscuraCam, the user can perform image filtering and obfuscation on image regions. InformaCam also adds the “Identify” filter, which prompts the user for the subject’s name (or pseudonym) and to fill in whether or not the subject has given his or her consent to be filmed. This checklist of subject permissions can be further developed to match the needs of any organization to provide further protection to the people in front of the camera. Notice again the sensor notifications: the context surrounding each edit to the image is recorded and will be inserted into the media as metadata once the media is saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the user saves the image or video, a dialog appears prompting her to choose one or more “trusted destinations.” This could be an organization, a news outlet, or any friend whose PGP key is known to you. A copy of the unredacted, data-rich image will be created and encrypted to those parties. At the same time, a redacted and data-stripped version is made available to share with anyone, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&#34;201&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1461&#34; alt=&#34;InformaCam (2)&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.21.07-PM.png&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;332&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.21.07-PM.png 201w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.21.07-PM-181x300.png 181w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td width=&#34;197&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1462&#34; alt=&#34;InformaCam (3)&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.21.21-PM.png&#34; width=&#34;197&#34; height=&#34;330&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.21.21-PM.png 197w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-20-at-1.21.21-PM-179x300.png 179w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;i&gt;Using the InformaCam “Identify” filter.&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;i&gt;Select a Trusted Destination for your encrypted media.&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-informa-metadata-schematic&#34;&gt;The Informa Metadata Schematic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metadata is organized in four categories: intent, consent, geneaology, and data. Here’s a rundown of what these categories mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;intent&#34;&gt;Intent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This expresses information about the media’s creator, and the rules governing how this particular media object can be shared, and to whom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;consent&#34;&gt;Consent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bucket of information regards the subjects contained in the image. Each subject is identified (by a name or pseudonym selected by the user) along with their stated preferences regarding treatment of their likeness. For example, if Bobby insists that he wants his face to be fully redacted (rather than blurred) this preference should be registered in metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;genealogy&#34;&gt;Genealogy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information regards chain-of-custody, and represents how the media was acquired, and if a particular image or video is a duplicate of another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category includes all standard metadata (timestamp, acquired sensory data, location and movement data) that have been collected during the lifetime of the image, from the moment it was opened to the instant it was saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sample metadata bundle for an image taken with InformaCam looks like this in JSON notation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;device&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;bluetoothInformation&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;selfOrNeighbor&amp;quot;:-1,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;deviceBTAddress&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;00:25:36:79:EC:6C&amp;quot;,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;deviceBTName&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;nexxxie&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;imei&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;363289131048142&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;sourceType&amp;quot;:101,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;imageRegions&amp;quot;:[&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;regionDimensions&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:256,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:256.00006103515625&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;regionCoordinates&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;:527.705078125,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;:196.15255737304688&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;obfuscationType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Identify&amp;quot;,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;location&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;locationType&amp;quot;:11,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;locationData&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;gpsCoords&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;[40.7085011,-73.9668647]&amp;quot;,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;cellId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;36789325&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
}&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;captureTimestamp&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;timestamp&amp;quot;:1326216508313,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;timestampType&amp;quot;:7&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;subject&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;consentGiven&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;general_consent&amp;quot;,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;informedConsentGiven&amp;quot;:true,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;subjectName&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Harlo!&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;unredactedRegion&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;I@4070cf30&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
}&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
],&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;imageHash&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;f18e7510faaad0d942db68b5c75f219a&amp;quot;,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;geneaology&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;dateAcquired&amp;quot;:0,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;localMediaPath&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\/mnt\/sdcard\/DCIM\/Camera\/1326216520426.jpg&amp;quot;,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;dateCreated&amp;quot;:1326216527629&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;intent&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;owner&amp;quot;:{&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;ownershipType&amp;quot;:25,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;ownerKey&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;MY-IDENTITY-IS-HERE&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
},&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;securityLevel&amp;quot;:1,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;intendedDestination&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;[\&amp;quot;&amp;amp;#x68;ar&amp;amp;#x6c;&amp;amp;#x6f;.h&amp;amp;#x6f;&amp;amp;#x6c;me&amp;amp;#x73;@g&amp;amp;#x6d;&amp;amp;#x61;il&amp;amp;#x2e;&amp;amp;#x63;om\&amp;quot;]&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
}&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-help&#34;&gt;Your Help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InformaCam is a work-in-process, and we’d love help from the community in fleshing out our metadata specification, especially in adding new items to the consent checklist. Feel free to contact us with any suggestions/comments, or just leave some helpful tips in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress on Mobile Video Privacy Tools</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2011/09/10/progress-on-mobile-video-privacy-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2011 04:36:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2011/09/10/progress-on-mobile-video-privacy-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are  a developer you may just want to skip all the prose below, and just jump over to Github to find our new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/android-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;FFMPEG on Android project&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p} and build system. You can also check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/SSCVideoProto&#34;&gt;SSCVideoProto Project&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p} to understand how we are using it to redact faces and other identifying areas of HD video right on the Android phone itself. For more context, read on…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last October at the Open Video Conference 2010, the idea of a camera application that could be designed to understand the needs and requirements of the human rights community was born. During a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.witness.org/2010/10/ovc2010-opensubtitles/&#34;&gt;hackday hosted with WITNESS&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}, we proved that is was possible to take a feature like “Face Detection” which is built into the Android operating system, and turn it into a capability that could be used to protect people, by blurring, pixelating or removing faces that unintentionally appeared in a video filmed on a mobile phone. In the last year, through our partnership with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.witness.org/cameras-everywhere/witness-labs&#34;&gt;WITNESS Labs&lt;/a&gt;, we have built on that concept, designing, developing and releasing apps and source code which move the state of the art in mobile video privacy and anonymity capabilities forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a short video of &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.witness.org/2010/10/ovc2010-opensubtitles/&#34;&gt;where we were a year ago&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was that using a combination of approaches, we might be able to take the human rights video workflow, and ideas of consent and intent, that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.witness.org/training&#34;&gt;WITNESS has developed for over twenty years&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}, and encode that into best practices and features in a software application. This was the catalyst for the launch of our joint &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/securesmartcam/wiki&#34;&gt;Secure Smart Cam Project&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}, which just a three months ago resulted in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2011/06/23/announcing-obscuracam-v1-enhance-your-visual-privacy/&#34;&gt;launch of our first public app&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}, &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2011/06/23/announcing-obscuracam-v1-enhance-your-visual-privacy/&#34;&gt;ObscuraCam v1&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}. Available in the Android Market, this app allows a user to quickly process a still photo taken on an Android smartphone, empowering them to remove unwanted identifying visual elements (faces, logos, signs, places) and remove unwanted digital metadata attached to the photo (GPS data, camera make and model, timestamps, etc). The app assists the user in this process by using Android’s built-in face detection technology to automatically identify and pixelize faces found in photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2011/06/23/announcing-obscuracam-v1-enhance-your-visual-privacy/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/02_autodetect.png&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;336&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continue to develop ObscuraCam in order to add new features, filters and privacy-enhancing capabilities. In addition, we exploring the “Informa” mode of this application, which uses the same technologies developed to assist in removing information, and instead uses them to add layers of extra verification, subject consent and intent tracking, and full media encryption. The idea is that in many cases people want to use visual media as evidence, or at least as reliable sources for journalistic use, and the more data that can be securely and safely captured and associated with a mediafile, the better. This is still in the research and design phase, but we expect to have some concepts of this ready for public play in the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While ObscuraCam is exciting, it only supports photos at this time. This is a fundamental issue, because WITNESS is a human-rights video organization, and the type of compelling content people are creating on their mobile phones are moving pictures not still. A year out from when the idea was first prototyped, I am happy to say that we have addresses the major challenges necessary to achieve mobile video processing of high-resolution video on the Android phone itself. The prototype last year was faking it in a sense, as it couldn’t actual record anything, and just showed the idea that you could detect faces. Our new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/sscvideoproto&#34;&gt;SSCVideoProto project&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}, utilizes the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/android-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;FFMPEG video processing library&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}, to redact regions from recorded video files. Below is a short video that demonstrates the current state of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, this means we can now remove, pixelize or otherwise modify any identifying content in a high-resolution video recorded on a mobile phone, before that video is uploaded to YouTube, Facebook or elsewhere. Faces can be removed, screens blacked out or any other element that shouldn’t be shown, as it would increase some risk to the subjects of the video. Beyond redaction, we can now process any video, using open-source software, on an Android phone, including trimming, splitting, adjusting color, balance, brightness or any other common ffmpeg feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Shawn, Andrew and Hans for the collective work on getting us to this milestone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/android-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;FFMPEG on Android project&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/SSCVideoProto&#34;&gt;SSCVideoProto Project&lt;/a&gt;{.vt-p}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ObscuraCam v1 – Enhance Your Visual Privacy!</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2011/06/23/announcing-obscuracam-v1-enhance-your-visual-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:28:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2011/06/23/announcing-obscuracam-v1-enhance-your-visual-privacy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We’re very happy to announce the beta release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/securecam/&#34;&gt;ObscuraCam&lt;/a&gt; for Android. This is the first release from the SecureSmartCam project, a partnership with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.witness.org/&#34;&gt;WITNESS&lt;/a&gt;, a leading human rights video advocacy and training organization. This is the result of an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/SecureSmartCam/tree/obscurav1&#34;&gt;open-source development cycle&lt;/a&gt;, comprised of multiple sprints (and branches), that took place over the last five months. This “v1” release is just the first step towards the complete vision of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the SecureSmartCam project to to design and develop a new type of smartphone camera app that makes it simple for the user to respect the visual privacy, anonymity and consent of the subjects they photograph or record, while also enhancing their own ability to control the personally identifiable data stored inside that photo or video. Also, we think an app that allows you to pixelize your friends, disguise their faces and otherwise defend their privacy just a little bit, is a lot of fun and helps raise awareness about an important issue. In this first release we have focused on ‘obscura’ by optimizing the workflow of identity obfuscation in still images. Future releases will look at ‘informa,’ the process of properly gaining and recording informed consent from subjects, while also moving to video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/teamdinner.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1199 alignnone&#34; title=&#34;teamdinner&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/teamdinner.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;337&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/teamdinner.jpg 640w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/teamdinner-300x225.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;quick-download-links&#34;&gt;Quick Download Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://market.android.com/details?id=org.witness.sscphase1&amp;amp;feature=search_result&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;margin: 3px;&#34; title=&#34;obscura_market_qr&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/obscura_market_qr.jpg&#34; width=&#34;130&#34; height=&#34;130&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;For those of you who just want to get to it, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://market.android.com/details?id=org.witness.sscphase1&amp;amp;feature=search_result&#34;&gt;Android Market&lt;/a&gt; to grab the latest version of the app. You can also scan the QR code to the left, and it will take you in that direction.&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/obscura_market_qr.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those without access to the Android Market, you can get the ObscuraCam.APK file from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/builds/Obscura/&#34;&gt;public builds folder&lt;/a&gt;. The official signed release binary is also available &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/downloads/ObscuraCam-1.0.4.2-20110624.apk&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For these options, be sure to check back for updates, because the app will not auto-update itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-cameras-everywhere-initiative&#34;&gt;The “Cameras Everywhere” Initiative&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January, WITNESS launched their &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.witness.org/2011/01/cameraseverywhere/&#34;&gt;Cameras Everywhere&lt;/a&gt; initiative, in which they ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As more and more people film people speaking out and taking a stand against human rights crises, how can we protect victims and witnesses and ensure informed consent as much as possible?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;As more and more footage circulates from human rights crises around the world, how does powerful footage reach audiences in comprehensible ways that move people to action?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;And how do we know how to trust that footage?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Critical issues to address in this realm include safety and security in the use of video; ethical questions raised by the widespread capacity to shoot and circulate human rights video; challenges around the authenticity of video and the preservation of evidence; and the need for effective documentation around the use of video in advocacy.&lt;br /&gt;
_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our collaboration, WITNESS has decided to move beyond just awareness, training and advocacy, and instead help design a next generation of Camera app software that is not just intended to share and capture more, but is meant to allow its operator to stop, think and be empowered to control the media they are capturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-primer-on-visual-privacy-and-anonymity&#34;&gt;A Primer on Visual Privacy and Anonymity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_privacy&#34;&gt;Visual Privacy&lt;/a&gt; is the relationship between collection and dissemination of visual information, the public expectation of privacy, and the legal issues surrounding them. It relates particularly to the increasing presence of large-scale still- and video-camera networks in everyday life. This not only includes those surveillance-oriented networks under the control of corporations and governments, but also applies to the vast new network of citizen-controlled media capture devices such as smartphones and handheld cameras that has created a peer-to-peer, social-networking based surveillance. At the same time that these networks have exploded in size, face detection and recognition technologies have also improved considerably while policy regarding the privacy and fair use of such systems and content, as well as the rights of those imaged by such networks, are topics that are not resolved. What results is a situation in which massive amounts of media are being captured every day with little to no protection of individual rights to privacy or anonymity – something that is especially detrimental to human rights efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Sam Gregory of WITNESS &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.witness.org/2011/02/human-rights-video-privacy-and-visual-anonymity-in-the-facebook-age/&#34;&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;, most contemporary discussions around anonymous communication on the Internet focus on the data protection side – for instance options for data encryption or censorship circumvention. In the case of media content, a largely unaddressed question arises: what about the rights to anonymity and privacy for those people who appear, intentionally or not, in visual recordings? Visual privacy and anonymity may sound like a contradiction in terms, but people often wish to speak out and to ‘be seen’ while at the same time concealing their face and identifying surroundings. As human rights documentation and organizing increasingly involves media capture, how are people enabled to make purposeful choices about when they speak out and what degrees of anonymity they hold onto for themselves? Conversely, people caught in the background of a video or still may be unaware that they are even being filmed in that moment and have no option to protect themselves – particularly true in mass protest settings where the wave of group solidarity may overwhelm any sense of personal privacy. For those speaking out from marginalized positions, personal safety is a very real risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples where visual privacy and anonymity is being diluted in the name of features or security:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timesonline.co.uk/tol/news/uk/article6913273.ece&#34;&gt;persecution&lt;/a&gt; later faced by bystanders and people who stepped in to film or assist Neda Agha-Soltan as she lay dying during the 2009 Iranian election protests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.facebook.com/blog.php?post=467145887130&#34;&gt;opt-out feature&lt;/a&gt; for auto-detection and tagging of faces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;British Columbia’s privacy watchdog &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metronews.ca/vancouver/local/article/897762--province-s-privacy-watchdog-oks-facial-recognition-to-identify-rioters&#34;&gt;OKs the use of facial recognition technology&lt;/a&gt; to identify rioters from video and still images of Vancouver’s 2011 hockey riots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viewdle.com/products/mobile/index.html&#34;&gt;Viewdle’s Social Camera&lt;/a&gt; automatically tags your friends in photos based on the social networking profile pictures they have published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some of these examples might seem harmless, or even a useful feature for law enforcement, the main issue is that the subjects of these photos and videos are never asked if they wish to participate in them, not to mention whether they want their photo published online in the first place. The permanence of media on the Web means that any uploaded content can be poured over again and again to identify individuals – either by old-fashioned investigative techniques, but crowd-sourcing, or by face detection /recognition software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-obscuracam-helps&#34;&gt;How ObscuraCam Helps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/01_home.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;margin: 3px;&#34; title=&#34;01_home&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/01_home-180x300.png&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Part of the problem currently surrounding visual privacy and anonymity is the fact that many of the tools and applications that people use on an everyday basis do not have features built in to protect privacy. As a result, everyone with a smartphone, tablet or laptop – not to mention an actual video camera! – captures raw, unedited content that exposes the identities of participants and bystanders present at sensitive events or activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/securecam/&#34;&gt;ObscuraCam&lt;/a&gt; is a mobile application for Android that makes it easy for anyone to protect the identity of individuals or groups represented in their photos by building obfuscation and redaction directly into the app. It can be used on photos taken directly from the app itself, or on any photo that your mobile device has access to, including local memory card images or linked Picasa albums. By moving a usually cumbersome post-production process into the daily workflow of those capturing sensitive images, it’s our hope that visual privacy will be respected when it really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;using-obscuracam&#34;&gt;Using ObscuraCam&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ObscuraCam features a simple, touch-based user interface for easy manipulation and redaction of images, as well as an automated removal of identifying metadata stored in the photo itself. The following steps walk through the process of capturing and sharing an obscured photo using ObscuraCam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the application home page, choose to either capture a new image or choose an existing image from your existing collections. These options just launch your standard Camera and Gallery application. When the photo is imported, identifying EXIF metadata stored in the file itself, such as GPS location, camera make and model or timestamp, will be removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you capture or open an image with ObscuraCam, it is automatically scanned to detect faces. Any faces detected are marked as tagged regions in an image, and the user is able to create as many additional tagged regions as they wish – either via the menu or by long-pressing the desired region. By default, tagged regions are set to be obscured via pixelation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once a tagged region has been created, the user can interact with that region by simply touching it to bring up a contextual menu.&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/02_autodetect.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1171&#34; title=&#34;02_autodetect&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/02_autodetect-300x180.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/02_autodetect-300x180.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/02_autodetect.png 800w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Options available from the contextual tagging menu include:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit – select to scale and move tagged regions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redact – select to fully redact tagged region and replace with black space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pixelate – select to selectively obfuscate identities of persons or situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bgPixelate – select to easily obfuscate everything BUT the tagged region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mask – select to pin a set of ‘groucho marks’ glasses on the tagged region – not only a bit of fun, but useful for quickly defeating facial recognition schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete – delete the current tagged region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you’re done selecting and obfuscating tagged regions, you can use the options from the main application menu to see a preview of the finished image, save it to your local memory, or share the picture with any application on your handset that is configured to accept images. This includes applications like Facebook, Twitter, or the default Messaging app. &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/09_processed.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1172&#34; title=&#34;09_processed&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/09_processed-180x300.png&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/09_processed-180x300.png 180w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/09_processed.png 480w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 180px) 100vw, 180px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;share-with-us-and-save-your-face&#34;&gt;Share With Us and “Save Your Face”!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As impediments of visual privacy continue to expand, help us get the word out that we can take back control over our online identities with ObscuraCam! We’ve set up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/ObscuraCam-Saving-Your-Social-Face/110765659013081&#34;&gt;Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; where you can share your creations with us, and with eachother!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;source-code-issue-reporting&#34;&gt;Source Code &amp;amp; Issue Reporting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re big fans of open source and living in public. As consistent with all our projects, source code for the SecureSmartCam project, along with the ObscuraCam release, is available online at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/SecureSmartCam&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also use GitHub to manage our development milestones and active bugs / issues. If you encounter any bugs or issues when testing out this beta build, please report them directly to us in the comments below or by filing directly on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/SecureSmartCam/issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
