<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nfc on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/nfc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nfc on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:30:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/nfc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Question: central server, federated, or p2p? Answer: all!</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/09/18/question-central-server-federated-or-p2p-answer-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:30:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/09/18/question-central-server-federated-or-p2p-answer-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many ideas of core architectures for providing digital services, each with their own advantages and disadvantages. I break it down along the lines of central servers, federated servers, and peer-to-peer, serverless systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12631&#34; style=&#34;width: 210px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/200px-Server-based-network.svg_.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12631&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/200px-Server-based-network.svg_.png&#34; alt=&#34;a central service with clients connecting to it&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;207&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-12631&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/200px-Server-based-network.svg_.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/200px-Server-based-network.svg_-100x103.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/200px-Server-based-network.svg_-150x155.png 150w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12631&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    a central service with clients connecting to it
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most big internet companies operate in effect as a central server (even though they are implemented differently). There is only facebook.com, there are no other services that can inter-operate with facebook.com. Have a single, central repo makes problems of finding the service and finding people within the service a lot easier. Once you are in Facebook, you just need to know the name of the person you want to contact and you are connected. The Facebook apps just need to talk to facebook.com, so the user does not need to know which service they are using in order to configure the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12633&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bendevane.com/RDC2012/ians/2012/10/09/campsiteofthefutur/&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12633&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-300x170.png&#34; alt=&#34;email as federated service&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;170&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-12633&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-300x170.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-100x56.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-150x85.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-200x113.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-450x255.png 450w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-600x341.png 600w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582-900x511.png 900w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Federated-01-1024x582.png 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12633&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    email as federated service
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email is a great example of a federated system. Each email provider acts like a central server, but then each of those central servers can easily talk to each other and exchange data. So fastmail.fm and gmail.com are both centralized services, but users do not need to know any extra information in order to exchange emails between the two services, or any other of the millions of email servers out there. A federated system provides a lot of the benefits of a centralized server with more flexibility. The downside is that federated services generally require more configuration to use them (though webmail makes that much less of an issue).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12632&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/300px-Unstructured_peer-to-peer_network_diagram.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12632&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/300px-Unstructured_peer-to-peer_network_diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;a peer-to-peer network&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-12632&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/300px-Unstructured_peer-to-peer_network_diagram.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/300px-Unstructured_peer-to-peer_network_diagram-100x81.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/300px-Unstructured_peer-to-peer_network_diagram-150x122.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/300px-Unstructured_peer-to-peer_network_diagram-200x163.png 200w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12632&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    a peer-to-peer network
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems can provide unique benefits of bandwidth efficiency as well as working around blockages in the internet. Sharing large files with thousands of people is quite expensive when using a central server, but with bittorrent, anyone can share large files to many many people using only a basic broadband connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year and a half of our Bazaar project, we have been thinking a lot about how to distribute apps to people who face a number of challenges. Each of these systems offers distinct advantages and disadvantages, so it is quite difficult to choose only one. Instead, we thought why not try to make a system that combines all three? Android’s APK app package format is a good format to work in this model because they are self-contained and containing a form of embedded identity in the app signature. So if you already have an Android app installed, then Android will enforce that only APKs signed by the same key as the installed app can be installed over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means in theory, it does not matter where the APK came from as long as it has a valid signature. There are some details where it does matter, mostly related to exploits like “Master Key” that can inject code into an existing APK. The FDroid app repository signature has a similar property: once you trust the repository signing key, it does not matter how you got the repository files as long as the signature validates. This is a model proven by GNU/Linux distros like Debian. The repository metadata also provides a way to validate APKs have not been modified since they were added to the signed repository. Since both of these do not rely on the method of transport to prove their authenticity, this combination provides a great testbed for this idea of combining a central service, with decentralized servers and peer-to-peer distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was all incorporated in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FDroid&lt;/a&gt; app store for Android. The central f-droid.org app repository means that FDroid can deliver well over one thousand apps without any configuration on the part of the user. The “fdroidserver” developer tools means that anyone can set up their own repository of apps, and users can easily add that repository to FDroid. It is not quite zero configuration, but the process is not too difficult, and there is more we are planning to do to smooth out that process even more. This also provides a channel for users to get apps via “collateral freedom” techniques like using Amazon S3, Akamai, etc. to distribute files where many such services are filtered or blocked. Lastly, we made it possible to have the FDroid app itself act as an app repository, and other devices can connect to that repository using local WiFi, mesh, Bluetooth, and removable media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stuff is all implemented and included in the FDroid app and fdroidserver developer tools. The big remaining challenge is combining them all into a usable experience for people who do not know the technical details. This has been tested, discussed, sketched out, and there is a prototype implementation in the works. So I can end with a quick overview of some positive and negative observations about the various peer-to-peer connections that we experimented with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; Bluetooth is ubiquitous
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; very slow data rate
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; pairing is difficult
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; WiFi is very widespread
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; local connections are very fast
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; access points and proxies can block host-to-host connections
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; running access points on a device is not common nor easy
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; NFC makes Bluetooth very easy to use
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; NFC is not commonly used or available
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; NFC is far to slow and fiddly to be used as the data transmission medium
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; SD cards can move lots of data securely
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; not all devices have removable SD cards
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; swapping SD cards can be a fiddly process
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; swapping SD cards can not be automatic
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; USB thumb drives can move lots of data securely
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; they can be easily swapped between devices
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; swapping SD cards can not be automatic
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; not all devices support USB-OTG i.e. attached devices
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; USB-OTG is not widely used
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys, signatures, certificates, verifications, etc. What are all these for?</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/12/12/keys-signatures-certificates-verifications-etc.-what-are-all-these-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 13:20:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/12/12/keys-signatures-certificates-verifications-etc.-what-are-all-these-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/key.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/key-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;portable shared security token&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-12129&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;For the past two years, we have been thinking about how to make it easier for anyone to achieve private communications. One particular focus has been on the “security tokens” that are required to make private communications systems work. This research area is called internally &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/psst/wiki/PSST&#34; title=&#34;PSST Wiki&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Portable Shared Security Tokens aka PSST&lt;/a&gt;. All of the privacy tools that we are working on require “keys” and “signatures”, to use the language of cryptography, and these are the core of what “security tokens” are. One thing we learned a lot about is how to portray and discuss tools for private or anonymous communications to people who just want to communicate and are not interested in technical discussion. This is becoming a central issue among a lot of people working to make usable privacy tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The widely established way of talking about privacy tools comes from the lingo of the underlying methods: cryptography, networking, etc. We talk about public and private keys, signing, validation, verification, key exchange, certificates, and fingerprints. In order for cryptography to work, keys need to be marked whether they are verified or not. &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/public_key_cryptography_sm.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/public_key_cryptography_sm-300x190.png&#34; alt=&#34;hide the guts of what is happening&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;190&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-12135&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/public_key_cryptography_sm-300x190.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/public_key_cryptography_sm.png 500w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Few computers users understand what these terms are referring to, even highly technical people who regularly use encryption do not know the meaning of all these things, nor should they. This is a low level detail that is not important to how the vast majority of users understand privacy in computers. Keys and verification are far too abstract to be generally understandable, and what other kind of key has a fingerprint? Even more so, few people can tell you the difference between validation and verification when it comes to keys, signatures and certificates. The software should not be exposing all this, but instead should be minimizing the complexity as much as possible, and providing as simple a user experience as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defining the Concepts that Define the Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key part of defining that simple user experience is defining the core concepts that the software is organized around. In our discussions, we mostly talked about the ideas of identity and trust, while some discussion of verifying identity seemed unavoidable. Talking about identity and trust is a lot more relevant in day-to-day life, i.e. knowing that the message came from the person you think it did, and trusting that it was private. It is most direct to talk about establishing a trusted connection to another person, but that’s not something that crypto can ever promise because there is still the analog gap between the person and the device. These core ideas must represent what is technically possible, so we searched for widely understood concepts that map well to the technical limitations: “a private conversation”, “a trusted app”, “verifiable video”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12128&#34; style=&#34;width: 160px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/ecc.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12128&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/ecc-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;create metaphors based on what users know&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;size-thumbnail wp-image-12128&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/ecc-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/ecc-300x300.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/ecc.jpg 350w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12128&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    create metaphors based on what users know
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;Diving in deeper, we concluded that the balance point between technical accuracy and widely understandable lingo was to talk about trusting the device, not the person. The technology can provide trusted connections between devices, and it is pretty close to how people experience digital communications. There is the laptop, the mobile phone, the net cafe, the friend’s computer, computer at work, etc. etc. When I look at my phone to see a message from a friend, it is easy to picture that friend typing that message out on that device, though it does take some conscious effort. The hard part here is that as we communicate more and more with our devices, there is less and less separation in our minds about whether we were talking in person, via voice, or by sending text. This is a point to focus on when thinking about designing the experience of private, secure communications software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let the Software Handle It!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a forming consensus in the world of usable security to focus on figuring out how to automate as much as possible then figure out how best tailor the experience of the essential parts that cannot be automated. The hard part will remain explaining the limitations of a given privacy tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Guardian Project, we work a lot on incremental progress, so many of our projects are focused on specific, narrow improvements. With &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/chatsecure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ChatSecure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/keysync/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keysync&lt;/a&gt; , we were able to automate one small part of the whole process, cryptography identity portability, which provides the foundation to provide private communications and verifiable media. Allowing users to sync their trust profiles between desktop and mobile makes it much more likely that users will have fully verified OTR conversations when chatting on their devices and laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/code/gnupg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard for Android (GPGA)&lt;/a&gt;, we have made it easy to import keys via QRCode as well as &lt;code&gt;openpgp4fpr:&lt;/code&gt; URLs (a standard defined in conjuction with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.monkeysphere.info/&#34; title=&#34;Monkeysphere Home Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Monkeysphere&lt;/a&gt; project. We are also working on a common method of using NFC for OpenPGP key signing in conjuction with &lt;a href=&#34;http://sufficientlysecure.org/index.php/openpgp-keychain/&#34; title=&#34;OpenPGP Keychain home page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpenPGP Keychain&lt;/a&gt;. Even little things like optimizing support for standard file extensions can go a long way to make things easier, so GPGA automatically sets itself up to receive files with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2015&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;standard OpenPGP MIME types&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;code&gt;application/pgp-keys&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;application/pgp-encrypted&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;application/pgp-signature&lt;/code&gt;) as well as the corresponding file extensions (&lt;code&gt;.pkr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.skr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.key&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.sig&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.asc&lt;/code&gt;, etc.). That makes it so a user can just click on one of these files, and GPGA will walk them through the whole process, doing as much as possible automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting idea that is a big step in this direction is “secure introductions”. The idea is to automatically share trusted identity information when securely communicating with multiple people. For example, whenever you send a signed, encrypted email to multiple people, the email program should include the key fingerprints of each recipient in that email. Then the email program of the people receiving that email should automatically mark those keys as verified if the sender’s key is trusted and the signature is valid. There is not a meaningful amount of detail leaked in this interaction, since the existence of all the people’s keys and email address is already present in a secure email. The tricky part is figuring out how to make it harder for someone to use this maliciously to spread false identity information while keeping things as automatic as possible. This is very much a long term research idea: there are no widespread implementations of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
