<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Software Tooling for Android Feature Extraction</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/05/06/free-software-tooling-for-android-feature-extraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/05/06/free-software-tooling-for-android-feature-extraction/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As part of the Tracking the Trackers project, we are inspecting
thousands of Android apps to see what kinds of tracking we can find.
We are looking at both the binary APK files as well as the source
code.  Source code is of course easy to inspect, since it is already a
form that is meant to be read and reviewed by people.  Android APK
binaries are a very different story.  They are first and foremost a
machine-executable format.  On top of that, many developers
deliberately obfuscate as much as possible in the APK to resist
inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means inspection requires using tools to look into the binary APK
format.  There is actually a massive amount of work that goes into
inspecting APKs because this is required in order to do useful malware
analysis.  For the most part, these inspection techniques are the
malware companies&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;special sauce&amp;rdquo;, so they are proprietary and
generally kept secret.  On top of that, malware companies keep secret
a lot of the conclusions they about what is useful data to collect,
and what should be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key piece of the Tracking the Trackers project is to make all of
research, tooling, and conclusions free, open, and publicly available.
First and foremost, that means the tools must be free software.  They
should also be easily installable so the barrier to entry for new
inspectors is as low as possible.  We focus on getting software as
part of Debian, since once there, so many people have access to those
packages since Ubuntu, Kali, and so many other GNU/Linux distros are
based on Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-available-in-debian-already&#34;&gt;What is available in Debian already&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2015/04/30/getting-android-tools-into-debian/&#34;&gt;Our
work&lt;/a&gt;
with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/AndroidTools&#34;&gt;Debian Android Tools
Team&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://java.debian.net/&#34;&gt;Debian Java
Team&lt;/a&gt; over the years means many key tools
are already included in Debian and its derivatives, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;key Android SDK components like &lt;em&gt;apksigner&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;dx&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;android.jar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;apktool&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;dexdump/dexlist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;enjarify&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LibScout&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;libsmali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;procyon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-we-are-using&#34;&gt;Tools we are using&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key aspect of our research is that working with terabytes of APKs,
this is necessary to be able to spot and map out as many trackers as
possible.  Since feature extraction can be a slow and resource
intensive process, we needed to use some tools that emphasize speed
over flexibility.  Even with fast extraction tools, we still have to
build up tailored processes to speed things up.  Some of these
straightforward feature extraction processes would take months to run
on ~3TB of APKs on a 32-thread machine with 144GB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/reddr/LibScout&#34;&gt;LibScout&lt;/a&gt; - detect SDKs/libraries with their version in binary APKs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/avast/apkparser&#34;&gt;https://github.com/avast/apkparser&lt;/a&gt; - faster manifest/resources parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/avast/apkverifier&#34;&gt;https://github.com/avast/apkverifier&lt;/a&gt; - faster APK signature verifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jedisct1/ipgrep&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jedisct1/ipgrep&lt;/a&gt; - ipgrep extracts possibly obfuscated host names and IP addresses from text, resolves host names, and prints them, sorted by ASN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stricaud/faup&#34;&gt;https://github.com/stricaud/faup&lt;/a&gt; - Fast URL decoder library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cryptax/droidlysis&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cryptax/droidlysis&lt;/a&gt; - Quickly analyze APKs for the most essential features: permissions, &lt;code&gt;Activity&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/code&gt; names, and key method calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;apkverifier&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;apkparser&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;droidlysis&lt;/em&gt; are generally useful, but
not yet in Debian.  So we packaged them to make them easily available.
They are currently in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ftp-master.debian.org/new.html&#34;&gt;Debian
NEW&lt;/a&gt; queue, awaiting final
review before inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools have been assembled into scripts to run the actual feature
extract processes, they are maintained in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/extracted-features&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/extracted-features&lt;/a&gt; repo.  When
the actual data generated is small enough and there are not copyright
conflicts, the data is also included there.  Mostly, the data sets are
too large and sometimes touch on copyright restrictions, so they are
unfortunately not publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of other tasks, including managing large APK
collections, gathering data to generate statistics about the features,
and downloading publicly available tracker SDK.  Those scripts are
maintained in &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/scripts&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/scripts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gradle-plugins&#34;&gt;Gradle Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with source code, then it is possible to do other kinds
of analysis.  Most Android apps are built with the Gradle tool.  So we
reviewed a wide range of Gradle plugins, and found these three useful
in our investigations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/autonomousapps/dependency-analysis-android-gradle-plugin&#34;&gt;dependency-analysis-android-gradle-plugin&lt;/a&gt; - Produce a report of unused direct dependencies and used transitive dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeremylong/DependencyCheck&#34;&gt;OWASP Dependency-Check&lt;/a&gt; - utility that detects publicly disclosed vulnerabilities in application dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vanniktech/gradle-dependency-graph-generator-plugin/&#34;&gt;gradle-dependency-graph-generator-plugin&lt;/a&gt; - Gradle plugin that lets you visualize your Java library dependencies in a graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-we-reviewed&#34;&gt;Tools we reviewed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked at quite a few existing tools, and found many interesting
and useful ones.  While they all produced useful output, many of these
were not useful to this project because they were tailored around the
use case of a person inspecting a small set of apps, so for example,
they were too slow or did not produce machine readable output suitable
for working with large APK collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/U039b/android_permissions_harvester&#34;&gt;android_permissions_harvester&lt;/a&gt; - for finding which permissions are used based on method calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cryptax/droidlysis&#34;&gt;droidlysis&lt;/a&gt; - cryptax&amp;rsquo;s (aXelle&amp;rsquo;s) tool: &amp;ldquo;DroidLysis is a property extractor for Android apps&amp;rdquo;. See also her &lt;a href=&#34;https://cfp.hack.lu/hacklu19/talk/ZZKNSM/&#34;&gt;talk at hacklu 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rednaga/APKiD&#34;&gt;APKiD&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;In addition to detecting packers, obfuscators, and other weird stuff, it can also identify if an app was compiled by the standard Android compilers or dexlib&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rednaga.io/2016/07/31/detecting_pirated_and_malicious_android_apps_with_apkid/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/redex&#34;&gt;redex&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;taking advantage of Redex allows us to normalise the applications prior to analysis&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.quarkslab.com/android-application-diffing-analysis-of-modded-version.html&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaitai-io/kaitai_struct_formats/blob/master/executable/dex.ksy&#34;&gt;kaitai_struct_formats&lt;/a&gt; - generic binary struct parser tool, useful for directly parsing Android &lt;em&gt;classes.dex&lt;/em&gt; files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/armijnhemel/binaryanalysis-ng&#34;&gt;binaryanalysis-ng&lt;/a&gt; - a framework for unpacking files recursively and running checks on the unpacked files.  Great for someone who needs to inspect small sets of a wide variety of file types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/plum-umd/redexer&#34;&gt;redexer&lt;/a&gt; - infer with which parameters the app uses certain permissions (we name this feature RefineDroid)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ytliu/apk-static-xref&#34;&gt;apk-static-xref&lt;/a&gt; - staticallly generate a cross-reference-graph (XRG) of a component (e.g., Service) of Android APK file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dorneanu/smalisca&#34;&gt;smalisca&lt;/a&gt; - Static Code analysis tool that generates call graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/thema/NGIZeroPET.html&#34;&gt;NGI Zero PET&lt;/a&gt; fund.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Features&#34; for Finding Trackers</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/28/features-for-finding-trackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/04/28/features-for-finding-trackers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One key component of the Tracking the Trackers project is building a
machine learning (ML) tool to aide humans to find tracking in Android
apps. One of the most important pieces of developing a machine
learning tool is figuring out which &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo; should be fed to the
machine learning algorithms. In this context, features are
constrained data sets derived from the whole data set. In our case,
the whole data set is terabytes of APKs. This post is an outline of
the features that we are focusing on in this current project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;confirmed-features&#34;&gt;Confirmed Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are features that we will definitely used, and already have good
tooling to do the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_extraction&#34;&gt;feature
extraction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;permissions&#34;&gt;Permissions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android apps must request
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/permissions/overview&#34;&gt;permissions&lt;/a&gt;
from the Android OS to access sensitive user data as well as certain
system features. This can naturally give big hints towards tracking
attempts. Basically an app which does not request any permissions will
have a much harder time of tracking its users, while an app aimed
towards tracking will require a myriad of permissions depending on the
properties it desires to track (e.g. location, contacts, phone IDs,
Bluetooth IDs, WiFi IDs, camera/microphone-access, call-logs and many
more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracking-libraries-and-sdks&#34;&gt;Tracking Libraries and SDKs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code re-use plays a big role in any software project, why write your
own tracking functionality when someone else has already implemented a
whole library geared towards tracking users. This functionality is
provided by different SDKs, which are pre-configured bundles of
functionality which in turn (for this use case) are provided by
tracking companies. The app developer often has to choose the desired
functionality. While importing a tracking library is no guarantee for
tracking activities it is certainly a red flag. We compare the
libraries imported by the app with a list of known tracking libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;domain-names&#34;&gt;Domain Names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers leave URLs in form of strings in the code to allow exchange
of information with the world outside of the app. This can be used to
transfer information about the user which in turn can be used for
tracking. The domains often contain a hint about the purpose behind
the data transfer (e.g. &lt;code&gt;https://www.google-analytics.com&lt;/code&gt;). Domain names
are data sinks for collecting data, which gives us a clear point to
focus on analyzing since collecting tracking data does not matter if
it never leaves the local device, while domain names are the point in
the code where data leaves the device and is sent to be collected and
analyzed on a remote server. Combined with other features like
permissions and seeing tracking libraries being imported a human
reviewer could get a pretty good idea of what type of information
could be sent. This human &amp;ldquo;gut feeling&amp;rdquo; of recognizing fishy
combinations of features is something a neural network can often learn
to approximate by being trained on a sufficient amount of training
data. Domain names known to be relevant to tracking are collected and
maintaned by &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/en/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;new-experimental-features&#34;&gt;New Experimental Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are features that show a lot of promise, but there is not
existing tooling to easily work with them.  We are working to make it
easier, and will cover that work in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-key-id&#34;&gt;API Key ID&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exodus-Privacy/etip/issues/62&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;API Key ID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
is a string that identifies bit of authentication data for enabling
access to an online service. Many online services require an &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt;
even if a library or SDK is not required to access it. Even when the
SDK is detected, the presence of an &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt; shows that the tracking
function is actually enabled. For example, the Google Firebase SDK
includes lots of functionality, not only tracking, each of which must
be enabled with an &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt;. So the presence of Firebase is not
enough to confirm tracking. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.epicenter.works/content/analysis-of-the-stopp-corona-app-improvements-through-expert-report&#34;&gt;current
example&lt;/a&gt;
of exactly this is the Austrian Red Cross&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Stopp Corona&lt;/em&gt; app to track
the spread of covid-19 in Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-language-processing-nlp&#34;&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned under the section on domain names, domain names can
already give a clear hint at intent. However since this property is
well known, URLs might be obfuscated to hide this information. This
domain name obfuscation is a well known technique in the world of
malware, there is some evidence of use by tracking companies. In this
case, a language model might learn that any URL that looks like random
letters and numbers might be a sign to consider increasing the
probability of classifying this app as tracking slightly, depending on
other features like requested permissions, and imported tracking
libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadcast-receivers&#34;&gt;Broadcast Receivers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android provides a system for data to be broadcast to all apps on a
device, this is known as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/broadcasts&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Broadcast
Receiver&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
A wide range of data is available via this mechanism, both from the
Android system as well as apps.  The Android OS broadcasts detailed
information about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/monitoring-device-state/battery-monitoring&#34;&gt;battery level, health, and charging
status&lt;/a&gt;,
including details of &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/os/BatteryManager#BATTERY_PLUGGED_AC&#34;&gt;how its
charging&lt;/a&gt;.
Many music apps will broadcast detailed information about the song
being played, while also &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/trackingthetrackers/wiki/-/issues/5&#34;&gt;collecting those
events&lt;/a&gt; from
the system and other apps.  The full extent of this activity is not
well described, both what data is broadcasted, what apps are doing
with it, and which apps are collecting.  As a feature, &lt;em&gt;Broadcast
Receivers&lt;/em&gt; have a lot of promise since they fit the patterns of useful
features for machine learning: small, globally unique, and easy to
extract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;feature-extraction-process&#34;&gt;Feature Extraction Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are using tabular data to feed to the machine learning processes,
so the process of extracting and pre-processing different features for
classification includes similar steps for every feature. The number of
features that can reasonably be processed this way is limited to
probably tens of thousands of features, or perhaps even hundreds of
thousands. Therefore we have collections of the top-&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; features where
&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; is in the range of thousands: For example, the top thousand
tracking libraries, or all built-in permissions. This way we extract
the features out of the binary APK file, and source code when
available, and loop over our collections of known features. If the
feature was found in the APK/source the tabular data will be a 1, else
a 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;This work was supported by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/thema/NGIZeroPET.html&#34;&gt;NGI Zero PET&lt;/a&gt; fund.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Trackers: using machine learning to aid ethical decisions</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/01/16/tracking-the-trackers-using-machine-learning-to-aid-ethical-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2020/01/16/tracking-the-trackers-using-machine-learning-to-aid-ethical-decisions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid is a free software community app store that has been working since 2010 to make all forms of tracking and advertising visible to users. It has become the trusted name for privacy in Android, and app developers who sell based on privacy make the extra effort to get their apps included in the F-Droid.org collection. These include &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/com.nextcloud.client&#34;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;, Tor Browser, &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/de.thecode.android.tazreader&#34;&gt;TAZ.de&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/de.tutao.tutanota&#34;&gt;Tutanota&lt;/a&gt;.  Auditing apps for tracking is labor intensive and error prone, yet ever more in demand. F-Droid already has tools to aide contributors in this process, visible in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/fdroiddata/merge_requests&#34;&gt;app submission&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/rfp/issues&#34;&gt;Request For Packaging (RFP)&lt;/a&gt; issue trackers.  We also have functional prototypes of using machine learning to drastically speed up this process by augmenting humans, rather than replacing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the prime motivation of the F-Droid community is ethical software distribution, algorithms will never replace humans in making ethical decisions. We have also explored using machine learning to detect tracking in a more generic way, without manually compiled lists of tracking libraries. With this funding, we will improve the F-Droid tools, and make them generally available for any use case needing to reliably detect trackers in Android apps. This builds upon our &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/2017/12/14/new-collaborations-on-exposing-tracking.html&#34;&gt;collaboration&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://exodus-privacy.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Exodus Privacy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/reddr/LibScout&#34;&gt;LibScout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project comes out of some proof of concept work that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lo-res.org/~aaron/&#34;&gt;Aaron Kaplan&lt;/a&gt; and Hans-Christoph Steiner did, working with students in the Vienna Economics University&amp;rsquo;s (WU) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wu.ac.at/en/infobiz/teaching/sbwl-data-science&#34;&gt;Data Science Lab&lt;/a&gt;.  We focused on using machine learning with Android apps, first to detect malware, then second to detect tracking libraries.  It is of course ultimately an outgrowth of the F-Droid community&amp;rsquo;s efforts, and Guardian Project&amp;rsquo;s funded efforts for building systems without any tracking at all.  And special thanks to F-Droid founder &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ciaran_Gultnieks&#34;&gt;Ciaran Gultnieks&lt;/a&gt; for setting the ethical tone that inspired us all, back in &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/2010/09/30/no-free-beer.html&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This current 44,500€ project is funded by NLnet&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlnet.nl/PET/&#34;&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Trust Enhancing Technologies (PET) Fund&lt;/a&gt;.  F-Droid has received large, dedicated, computing resources from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cfarm.tetaneutral.net/machines/list/&#34;&gt;GCC Compile Farm&lt;/a&gt;, as well as some shared resources from Aaron Kaplan.  The budget will be used entirely to pay for people&amp;rsquo;s time for the research, development, and integration work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software development to get the existing LibScout and Exodus Privacy tools to be fully integrated into the F-Droid stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning research and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community management, to coordinate with F-Droid contributors, app developers, tool developers, academic researchers, etc. as well to promote these tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalize and package up all the useful parts of this project, which also means getting them included in Debian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-efforts&#34;&gt;Related Efforts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general approach that we are taking here has been proven in the context of web pages. The Brave Browser includes &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1805.09155&#34;&gt;machine learning techniques&lt;/a&gt; for blocking ads and trackers in webpages.  It is a very similar idea to what we propose, but that example is embedded into a browser and only applies to web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exodus Privacy has manually compiled an extensive list of tracking libraries and domains for receiving user data.  It then uses this to scan app from Google Play.  Those results are then reported on their website.  Exodus Privacy would directly benefit from this work, since they could use the tools we will create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghostery uses AI techniques to dynamically block ads in web pages. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/ghostery-deploys-ai-in-fight-against-ad-trackers/&#34;&gt;https://www.wired.com/story/ghostery-deploys-ai-in-fight-against-ad-trackers/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid has its own &lt;code&gt;fdroid scanner&lt;/code&gt; for doing checks based on manually prepared regular expressions.  This was combined with Exodus Privacy into F-Droid&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/fdroid/rfp/issues&#34;&gt;issuebot&lt;/a&gt; which automatically scans apps that users request to be added to F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibScout uses machine learning to detect which versions of which libraries are included in an Android app (APK).  Using the list of libraries from Exodus Privacy, we worked with the LibScout author to create a functional prototype of a tracking library detector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sec.cs.tu-bs.de/pubs/2014-ndss.pdf&#34;&gt;Drebin&lt;/a&gt; clearly demonstrated that machine learning can be used to automatically classify Android apps based on certain aspects of their behavior. Their aim was to find malware.  Working with CERT.at and the WU Data Science Lab, we reproduced the results of the Drebin paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenges&#34;&gt;The challenges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest promise of this project is also the biggest technical challenge: finding a way to take datasets about what includes tracking libraries (e.g. F-Droid manual review, LibScout, Exodus Privacy), and turning that into a more general machine learning approach.  We will have to explore a wide range of possible features to include in the machine learning that are distinct from the tracking libraries themselves.  This general approach will provide tracking detection with more automation and less maintenance work of rerunning the machine learning on updated datasets as new tracking libraries are put into use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical methods for determining whether an app includes trackers are well known and described.  They currently require knowledge of Android development.  Machine learning has been proven to be able to reliably spot trackers in apps, this project will turn working prototypes into production software, integrate it into F-Droid community-driven processes, and make these new tools easily available for anyone else to apply to their specific use cases. Given an Android apps downloaded from anywhere, these new tools will be able to mark which ones have any kind of tracking in them, with a very high degree of certainty.  With the portion of the project that involves applying LibScout, at this point, the idea has been proven with prototypes.  Applying it is a straightforward matter of bringing a proven prototype to production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations relying on proprietary apps that must follow strict data protection requirements, like banks under the GDPR, can use these tools to ensure that apps they rely on do not contain illegal tracking, and to ensure that such tracking is not added in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These techniques are also applicable to other platforms, like Progressive Web Apps and Apple iOS.  Bootstrapping another platform would require a marked training set of apps to feed to the machine learning.  F-Droid already provides this set, and Android is the most popular OS in the world, making Android the ideal platform to start this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;humans-at-the-core&#34;&gt;Humans at the core&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid is a community run free software project very much in the same spirit as Debian.  The community has always aimed to provide 100% verified free software, built from source.  From the beginning, there was also an interest in other ethical considerations as well, these are expressed via F-Droid&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Anti-Features&amp;rdquo;.  These are things tagged with Tracking (contains tracking), Ads (includes advertising), and NonFreeNet (requires a non-free network service).  The process of ensuring that the apps are 100% free software as well as tagging apps with the required Anti-Features is a manual process that many people contribute to, that is aided by quite a bit of automation.  This project fits directly into this existing ecosystem.  It will both quickly provide improvements in contributors&amp;rsquo; workflow based on the existing prototype, as well as experiments towards drastically improving the whole workflow of anyone working to track trackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid fits into the whole Android app ecosytem in a very specific role.   It is the one source that only distributes free software, and has built a well deserved reputation for not compromising on the ethics that guide the community.  This has led it to become the standard &amp;ldquo;clean set&amp;rdquo; in all manner of research into Android malware and tracking.  Many academic papers covering Android malware cite f-droid.org as the source of ground truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, it is important to highlight that it is essential to keep humans always at the center of of these tools.  We are building tooling to augment humans, not replace them. Since the prime motivation of the F-Droid community is to build ethical software distribution, algorithms will never replace humans in making decisions based on ethics.  The tools can automate the technical details, so that contributors do not need to understand them in order to meaningfully help with the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
