<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 05:43:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Signing Server</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/12/18/building-a-signing-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 05:43:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/12/18/building-a-signing-server/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Android APK signing model sets the expectation that the signing key will be the same for the entire lifetime of the app. That can be seen in the recommended lifetype of an Android signing key: &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/publish/app-signing.html#considerations&#34;&gt;20+ years&lt;/a&gt;. On top of that, it is difficult to &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2015/12/29/how-to-migrate-your-android-apps-signing-key/&#34;&gt;migrate an app to a new key&lt;/a&gt;. Since the signing key is an essential part to preventing APKs from impersonating another, Android signing keys must be kept safe for the entire life of the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The F-Droid repo signing keys follow a very similar model: the signing key is the essential way to safely identify an F-Droid repo. So the same considerations apply to F-Droid repo signing keys as to APK signing keys. This also provides some really useful benefits. Since the integrity of the repo index file and the APKs are guaranteed by the repo signature, the files can be delivered via whatever method is most convenient, and their integrity will be automatically verified by the F-Droid client app, the &lt;em&gt;f-droid.org&lt;/em&gt; deploy process, and Repomaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means the security burden is shifted from the online, public webserver to a private signing machine. Just keeping that machine out of the public eye goes a long way towards improving security. There are a number of additional measures that can be taken to further improve the security of the signing process. Here are some approaches, starting with the easiest and least security, and going on to more secure setups that require more work to setup and run. Signing is not an resource intensive process, so any machine will work, even a 10 year old, basic laptop. We recommend using a minimal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; install, and rebuilding the machine from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;automated-signing-server-with-with-hsm&#34;&gt;Automated Signing Server with with HSM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a fully automated signing setup, the machine running the signing needs to be online and running. Ideally this machine would have no remote access, at the very least remote access should be very carefully controlled and monitored. A laptop makes it easy to work with even when remote access is disabled, since it provides a built-in keyboard and monitor. If remote access is required, then any basic PC will work fine. Using a Hardware Security Module (HSM) to store the keys prevents them from being stolen if the server is broken into. An attacker could only run the signing process on that server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, this machine would only be accessible via Tor. That hides the physical location of the server, and hides the traffic from network. This makes it much harder attackers to find the actual machine to attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the HSM, we recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nitrokey.com/&#34;&gt;Nitrokey&lt;/a&gt; hardware, since they are free software/hardware, and provide a wide range of options. Use a separate machine to put the signing keys on HSM. A good HSM will keep an audit trail of how many signatures have been made, so that information could be used to create an automatic auditing process to raise alarms if too many signatures have been made. That could mean that this server was breached and used to sign unauthorized packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other possibility it to use a setup like &lt;a href=&#34;https://pagure.io/sigul&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;‘s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devops-blog.net/koji/gpg-signing-rpms-with-sigul-signing-server-koji-integration&#34;&gt;Sigul&lt;/a&gt; that involves three machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-laptop-dedicated-to-signing&#34;&gt;Basic laptop dedicated to signing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with a laptop that can be wiped clean and rebuilt from scratch. What is most important is that only the essential software is installed on it, and nothing else. Do not include any browser at all, for example, since that is the most common vector of attack. No remote access setup (e.g. SSH or VNC) should be installed or configured. To sign apps and repos, someone would take out this laptop, connect it to the network, and run the signing process. The signed results can then be published via the network connection. When the signing is complete, the machine can be turned off and disconnected and kept in a safe place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be made quite automatic with some custom scripts. The person running the process would only need to take out the machine, connect it, turn it on, wait until the process completes, then put it all away again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fully-offline-signing-laptop-with-usb-thumb-drives&#34;&gt;Fully offline signing laptop with USB thumb drives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt;: apt-offline has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/871656&#34;&gt;security bug&lt;/a&gt; so it was removed from Debian/buster. It is no longer recommended! Instead, use the Debian &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/doc/manuals/apt-offline&#34;&gt;apt offline&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; setup._&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is based on the same basic, stripped down laptop as the previous example. But this time, the networking should be entirely disabled before the install process. For example, it is easy in many laptops to physically remove the WiFi card. Therefore, it makes sense to use a laptop that does not include an ethernet jack, which are usually not possible to remove. Otherwise, blacklisting all kernel modules related to neworking can suffice. Since this machine is fully offline, the extra work of using an HSM is not as important, but it can’t hurt to include it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the full &amp;ldquo;CD&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;DVD&amp;rdquo; image of Debian to run the install. Be sure to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/CD/verify&#34;&gt;verify&lt;/a&gt; the GPG signatures and the SHA-256 hashes. One essential utility is &lt;em&gt;apt-offline&lt;/em&gt;, which automates the process of downloading Debian packages, verifying their signatures, and copying them over to an offline machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be extra careful, all of the software used should be verified. Chromebooks are nice, cheap laptops that run Linux natively. They also use Coreboot for the BIOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;buy-a-computer-off-the-shelf-with-cash-avoid-having-it-shipped-especially-across-borders&#34;&gt;
  Buy a computer off the shelf with cash, avoid having it shipped, especially across borders
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;buy-a-debian-supported-chromebook-with-removeable-wifi-hardware-and-needs-no-binary-blobs&#34;&gt;
  Buy a Debian-supported &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/chromium-os/developer-information-for-chrome-os-devices/acer-c720-chromebook&#34;&gt;Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; with removeable WiFi hardware, and needs no binary blobs
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;install-a-reproducibly-built-coreboot-binary&#34;&gt;
  Install a reproducibly built coreboot binary
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;install-from-a-reproducibly-built-debian-image-wiping-out-chrome-os-entirely&#34;&gt;
  Install from a reproducibly built Debian image, wiping out Chrome OS entirely
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-physical-environment&#34;&gt;The Physical Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing to consider is the physical location where signatures happen, and where essential equipment is stored. The signing environment must be physically secure. Otherwise, there is no way to prevent laptops or HSMs from being lost or used to sign inappropriate content. For the offline machines, keeping them in a locked room is a good start. For an online machine, forcing all network traffic and remote access over Tor hides the physical location of the machine from network observers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For high risk signing keys, using multiple layers of defense is important:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restricted physical access to HSMs or smart cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security cameras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onsite security guards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visitor logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tools-resistant server safe for online code-signing servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The signing server should be physically separate from the rest of the infrastructure. And the logs, machine, and network should be periodically audited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;difficult-decisions&#34;&gt;Difficult decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally all of these practices would be put into place, but each of these security measures comes at a cost of difficulty, expense, and complexity. They can also delay the process of getting regular updates out. So there are risks of implementing too strict security policies, much like the risks of not implementing enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Android apps with Debian: apt install android-sdk</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/03/13/build-android-apps-with-debian-apt-install-android-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 10:03:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2017/03/13/build-android-apps-with-debian-apt-install-android-sdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-12920&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian-300x300.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian-270x270.jpg 270w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian-230x230.jpg 230w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/debian.jpg 600w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In Debian stretch, the upcoming new release, it is now possible to build Android apps using only packages from Debian. This will provide all of the tools needed to build an Android app targeting the “platform” &lt;tt&gt;android-23&lt;/tt&gt; using the SDK &lt;tt&gt;build-tools&lt;/tt&gt; 24.0.0. Those two are the only versions of “platform” and “build-tools” currently in Debian, but it is possible to use the Google binaries by installing them into &lt;tt&gt;/usr/lib/android-sdk&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t cover yet all of the libraries that are used in the app, like the Android Support libraries, or all of the other myriad libraries that are usually fetched from jCenter or Maven Central. One big question for us is whether and how libraries should be included in Debian. All the Java libraries in Debian can be used in an Android app, but including something like Android Support in Debian would be strange since they are only useful in an Android app, never for a Debian app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building apps with these packages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps for building Android apps using Debian’s Android SDK on Stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install android-sdk android-sdk-platform-23&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;export ANDROID_HOME=/usr/lib/android-sdk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;em&gt;build.gradle&lt;/em&gt;, set &lt;em&gt;compileSdkVersion&lt;/em&gt; to 23 and &lt;em&gt;buildToolsVersion&lt;/em&gt; to 24.0.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;gradle assembleDebug&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gradle Android Plugin is also packaged. Using the Debian package instead of the one from online Maven repositories requires a little configuration before running Gradle. In the &lt;em&gt;buildscript&lt;/em&gt; block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add &lt;tt&gt;maven { url &amp;lsquo;file:///usr/share/maven-repo&amp;rsquo; }&lt;/tt&gt; to repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use &lt;tt&gt;compile &amp;lsquo;com.android.tools.build:gradle:debian&amp;rsquo;&lt;/tt&gt; to load the plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently there is only the target platform of API Level 23 packaged, so only apps targeted at &lt;em&gt;android-23&lt;/em&gt; can be built with only Debian packages. We will add more API platform packages via backports. Only &lt;em&gt;build-tools&lt;/em&gt; 24.0.0 is available, so in order to use the SDK, build scripts need to be modified. Beware that the Lint in this version of Gradle Android Plugin is still problematic, so running the :lint tasks might not work. They can be turned off with &lt;tt&gt;lintOptions.abortOnError&lt;/tt&gt; in &lt;em&gt;build.gradle&lt;/em&gt;. Google binaries can be combined with the Debian packages, for example to use a different version of the platform or build-tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why include the Android SDK in Debian?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Android developers could develop and ship apps right now using these Debian packages, this is not very flexible since only &lt;tt&gt;build-tools-24.0.0&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;android-23&lt;/tt&gt; platform are available. Currently, we are not aiming to cover the most common use cases. Those are pretty well covered by Google’s binaries (except for the proprietary license on the Google binaries), and are probably the most work for the Debian Android Tools Team to cover. We are first working on use cases that are poorly covered by the Google binaries, for example, like where only specific parts of the whole SDK are used. Here are some we have in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tools for security researchers, forensics, reverse engineering, etc. which can then be included in live CDs and distros like Kali Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a hardened APK signing server using &lt;em&gt;apksigner&lt;/em&gt; that uses a standard, audited, public configuration of all reproducibly built packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replicant is a 100% free software Android distribution, so of course &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.replicant.us/2017/02/replicant-6-0-development-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;they want to have a 100% free software SDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high security apps need a build environment that matches their level of security, the Debian Android Tools packages are &lt;a href=&#34;https://reproducible-builds.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reproducibly built&lt;/a&gt; only from publicly available sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dead simple install with strong trust path with mirrors all over the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long run, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/AndroidTools&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debian Android Tools Team&lt;/a&gt; aims to cover more use cases well, and also building the Android NDK. This all will happen more quickly if we have more contributors! Android is the most popular mobile OS, and can be 100% free software like Debian. Debian and its derivatives are one of the most popular platforms for Android development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we want feedback on how this should all work. For example, we need ideas for how to nicely integrate Debian’s Java libraries into the Android &lt;em&gt;gradle&lt;/em&gt; workflow. And ideally, the Android Support libraries would also be reproducibly built and packaged somewhere that enforces only free software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone interested in tools for working with Android apps and APKs, including for reverse engineering, inspection, auditing, etc. there are quite a few tools included now in Debian:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt install android-sdk androguard apktool diffoscope dummydroid enjarify gplaycli libsmali-java libscout repo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOWTO: get all your Debian packages via Tor Onion Services</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/07/31/howto-get-all-your-debian-packages-via-tor-onion-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 17:28:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2016/07/31/howto-get-all-your-debian-packages-via-tor-onion-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png&#34; alt=&#34;leakage&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-12699&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-100x66.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-150x99.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-200x132.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png 410w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Following up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some privacy leaks that we looked into a while back&lt;/a&gt;, there are now official Debian &lt;a href=&#34;https://onion.debian.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt; for getting software packages and security updates, thanks to the Debian Sys Admin team. This is important for high risk use cases like TAILS covers, but also it is useful to make it more difficult to do some kinds of targeted attacks against high-security servers. The default Debian and Ubuntu package servers use plain HTTP with unencrypted connections. That means anyone with access to the network streams could both monitor and fingerprint traffic. When an request for a security update is spotted, an attacker knows that machine is vulnerable to an exploit, and could reliably exploit it before the security update is applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.riseup.net/code/issues/8143&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HTTPS to get security updates&lt;/a&gt; improves this situation a lot, but by measuring the size of data transfers, it is still possible to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/G.Danezis/papers/TLSanon.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;track which files are being downloaded&lt;/a&gt;. A Tor Onion Service provides end-to-end encryption like the HTTPS connection. It also mixes up the traffic with lots of other traffic, so its not easy to see what traffic goes together. That makes it a lot harder for a network observer to tell when a security update is being downloaded. Additionally, using a Tor Onion Service forces the traffic over Tor, so that the Debian mirror server cannot see which server is requesting the updates. That helps prevent targeted attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other benefits as well, besides just for the person running the high security server in this example, especially if all of the traffic is coming over Tor. When updates are delivered over Tor, then that means the Debian mirror operators have less to worry about because they are handling less metadata that might have privacy concerns. It means that when law enforcement requests logs from the mirror operators, the mirror operators can more easily hand over anything they have since the mirror operator knows that there is not private information in the logs. Reducing the legal risks and privacy concerns makes it easier to run mirrors, and that helps internet services work better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One disadvantage of this approach as it now stands is that your server will get updates from the same mirror every time. There is only a single Tor Onion Service for the main archive. An alternate approach using the combination of Tor and &lt;a href=&#34;http://httpredir.debian.org/&#34;&gt;http://httpredir.debian.org/&lt;/a&gt; as the package source means that your server will get updates from a different mirror each time Tor changes its exit node (I believe that’s every 10 minutes or so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you set up your Debian machine to get updates over Tor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11-300x173.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;debian and tor&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;173&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-13395&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11-300x173.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11-768x444.jpg 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/tor-logo-2011_11.jpg 800w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Right now, the best way to set up a Debian machine to force traffic over Tor is to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TransparentProxy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;transparent proxying&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;em&gt;iptables&lt;/em&gt; rules. If you have that setup, then you can add the onion addresses as Debian apt sources as if they are any other HTTP Debian mirror. Another option is to install &lt;em&gt;apt-transport-tor&lt;/em&gt; like TAILS does, then you can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.skolelinux.org/pere/blog/Always_download_Debian_packages_using_Tor___the_simple_recipe.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;special syntax to add the Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt;. And another way is to install an HTTP proxy like &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; and enable apt HTTP proxy support as &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I described before&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;apt-transport-tor&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; approaches both have the downside of having to trust an added piece of software, whereas the transparent proxy technique uses what is already present in the Linux kernel. I’ve been using the &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; method since that is what I got working in 2014 and it has been working reliably on multiple servers since then. Also, I need &lt;em&gt;privoxy&lt;/em&gt; installed for another application anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to set up the apt sources to get packages and updates via Tor Onion Services without delaying security updates. First, remove &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/*.list&lt;/em&gt; to start with a clean slate. Next add &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/00.vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion.list&lt;/em&gt; to get the main Debian repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie main
deb-src http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie main

# aka volatile
deb http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie-updates main
deb-src http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie-updates main

deb http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian jessie-backports main
deb-src http://vwakviie2ienjx6t.onion/debian/ jessie-backports main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next add the new Tor Onion Service for the security update repository at &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/00.sgvtcaew4bxjd7ln.onion.list&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://sgvtcaew4bxjd7ln.onion/ jessie/updates main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then last, include the normal HTTP security.debian.org archive to ensure that your server gets the latest security updates, even if the &lt;a href=&#34;https://onion.debian.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Onion Service mirror&lt;/a&gt; is behind or there is some other issue related to Tor. This goes in &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/99.security.debian.org.list&lt;/em&gt; to ensure that it is always the last repository that is tried, and apt loads files from /etc/apt/source.list.d/ in alphabetical order, so it’ll always try to get the security updates from the Onion Service before falling back to the HTTP source as a last resort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://security.debian.org/ jessie/updates main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also run an unofficial mirror of the security updates on &lt;a href=&#34;http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian&#34;&gt;http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian&lt;/a&gt; if you want to add another backup, i.e. &lt;em&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list.d/00.dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion.list&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian-security/ jessie/updates main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Migrate Your Android App’s Signing Key</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2015/12/29/how-to-migrate-your-android-apps-signing-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2015/12/29/how-to-migrate-your-android-apps-signing-key/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is time to update to a stronger signing key for your Android app! The old default RSA 1024-bit key is weak and officially deprecated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Android OS requires that every application installed be signed by a digital key. The purpose behind this signature is to identify the author of the application, allow this author and this author alone to make updates to the app, as well as provide a mechanism to establish inter-application trust. The Android security model defines an app by two things: the package name (aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context.html#getPackageName%28%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;packageName&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/a/android.com/tools/tech-docs/new-build-system/applicationid-vs-packagename&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ApplicationID&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/manifest/manifest-element.html#package&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;package&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and the signing key. If either of those are different, then Android considers it a different app. When the package name and signing key of one APK match an installed app, then the APK is considered an update and Android will replace the installed app with the APK. If the APK is signed by a different key, then Android will prevent installing and updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing is to see what the current signing key is. Check any app’s signing key using our free utility app &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.checkey&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Checkey&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_13170&#34; style=&#34;width: 790px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1.png&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-13170&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-13170&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1-1024x576.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lookout needs to generate a new key!&#34; width=&#34;780&#34; height=&#34;439&#34; class=&#34;size-large wp-image-13170&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1-300x169.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1-768x432.png 768w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1-350x197.png 350w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1-860x484.png 860w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/checkey-1.png 1280w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-13170&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Lookout needs to generate a new key!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official Android docs have tons of useful information about what the signing keys are good for, how to generate them, and how to use them. Unfortunately, it doesn’t provide any instructions for migrating, and for many years, 1024-bit RSA was the default. But first, why would you want or need to migrate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on when you created your signing key, you might have a particularly weak key. The primary danger of a weak key is that an adversary could break your key in order to generate fake APK signatures. Then those malicious APKs can be installed as updates to your app. There are other nefarious purposes depending on how you use the signing key in your apps. Or if you are unfortunate enough to have suffered a loss of your private key material, then it is definitely time for a new signing key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to our friends at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://androidobservatory.org/stats&#34; title=&#34;Android Observatory&#34;&gt;Android Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, over 64% of Android apps in their data store use 1024-bit signing keys (RSA or DSA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;visualization&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; height: 400px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several good reasons to migrate off of 1024-bit RSA keys, even though there is no &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; proof of a 1024 prime factorization required to generate any 1024-bit key at will. The evidence has been mounting for a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIST’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-57/sp800-57_part1_rev3_general.pdf&#34;&gt;official guidelines&lt;/a&gt; (PDF, page 64 and 67) deprecated 1024-bit RSA keys at the end of 2013. This deprecation by NIST isn’t an indication that 1024-bit RSA is compromised, instead it is a preemptive move to stay ahead of attacks. Confidence in NIST might be shaken in light of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2013/09/on-nsa.html&#34;&gt;recent revelations&lt;/a&gt;, but in this case increasing the RSA key size is unlikely to trigger any secret NSA backdoors. If anything, the deprecation year could have been extended slightly to allow the NSA a window where they had the capacity to factor 1024-bit keys and everyone was still using them. So, it’s time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an example, a decade ago the cost of building special purpose hardware capable of breaking a single 1024-bit RSA key in one year was estimated at $10 million (&lt;a href=&#34;http://tau.ac.il/~tromer/papers/cbtwirl.pdf&#34;&gt;Adi Shamir, Eran Tromer, On the cost of factoring RSA-1024&lt;/a&gt;, 2003). Presumably the techniques have improved by orders of magnatude, and the hardware value depreciated. It is conceivable the cost has fallen enough to be affordable not only by nation-state actors, but by large criminal enterprises too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a comprehensive talk on the state of the art (as of December 2012) when it comes to breaking 1024-bit RSA, check out the 29C3 talk &lt;a href=&#34;http://events.ccc.de/congress/2012/Fahrplan/events/5275.en.html&#34; title=&#34;FactHacks: RSA factorization in the real world&#34;&gt;FactHacks: RSA factorization in the real world&lt;/a&gt; with the cryptographers Daniel J. Bernstein, Nadia Heninger, and Tanja Lange (&lt;a href=&#34;http://events.ccc.de/congress/2012/wiki/Documentation#Recordings&#34; title=&#34;29C3 Recordings&#34;&gt;watch recording&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migrating to a strong key for an Android app is, unfortunately, not so simple. If you are publishing a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; app to the app store, then simply generate a new strong signing key and you’re done. Congratulations! However, there exists no easy way to update your signing key for an existing application, because an installed application can only take updates from an APK signed with &lt;em&gt;the same&lt;/em&gt; key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we outline a basic method with which you can use to fake an update to your signing key. This is not as user friendly as we would like. Some of the hard facts of performing this process is that for most app stores including Google Play, you will lose ratings and reviews since the app will show up with a new package name, and the app store will treat it like an entirely new app. Also, the user will have to manually uninstall the original app once they finish the procedure. Here is a rough outline of the process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate the new signing key, &lt;em&gt;RSA 4096&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the first app, &lt;em&gt;App1&lt;/em&gt;, with a mechanism for exporting private data, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/TrustedIntents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TrustedIntents&lt;/a&gt; with a signature pin of the new key, &lt;em&gt;RSA 4096&lt;/em&gt;, which &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2014/07/30/introducing-trustedintents-for-android/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Checkey will generate for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new version of the app with a different package name, &lt;em&gt;App2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sign &lt;em&gt;App2&lt;/em&gt; with new key, &lt;em&gt;RSA 4096&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add method to &lt;em&gt;App2&lt;/em&gt; for receiving user data from &lt;em&gt;App1&lt;/em&gt;, including a signature pin of the old signing key, &lt;em&gt;RSA 1024&lt;/em&gt;, for use with TrustedIntents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish &lt;em&gt;App2&lt;/em&gt; to the app stores&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From &lt;em&gt;App1&lt;/em&gt;, prompt user to install &lt;em&gt;App2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;runs and imports data from &lt;em&gt;App1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;App2&lt;/em&gt; prompts user to uninstall &lt;em&gt;App1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;, there will be some easier tools for handling this. The F-Droid system is already used to multiple signing keys per app since F-Droid uses its own signing key for many of the apps it releases, and that F-Droid signing key is different from the signing key that the original developer used in their Google Play uploads. F-Droid will likely be able to support APKs with the same package name but with multiple signing keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-note-on-compatibility&#34;&gt;A Note on Compatibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is security vs compatibility trade off a few might be interested in. Pre-4.3, Android did not support any signature algorithms except SHA1. With Android &amp;gt;= 4.3, SHA256 support was fixed, and SHA384, SHA512, and ECDSA were added (&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=38321&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). There are still android 2.3.3 (&lt;code&gt;android-10&lt;/code&gt;) devices being sold, so anyone interested in backwards compatibility will have to heed this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the larger the keysize and hashsize used, the longer it takes to install and update the application. So extremely large values might be unsuitable for slower hardware. The following probably doesn’t buy you a tremendous amount of additional security but cranks the paranoia to 11. It does so at the cost of compatibility and performance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Gen with:&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
  keytool -genkey -v -keystore test.keystore -alias testkey -keyalg RSA -keysize 4096 -sigalg SHA512withRSA -dname &amp;quot;cn=Test,ou=Test,c=CA&amp;quot; -validity 10000&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sign with:&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
  jarsigner -verbose -sigalg SHA512withRSA -digestalg SHA512 -keystore test.keystore test.apk testkey&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have some scripts that we use to generate keys in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/smartcard-apk-signing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;smartcard-apk-signing&lt;/a&gt; repo. It is also possible to generate an Android signing key using openssl or other libraries. It is often wise to use different software than standard for doing things like generating keys. Since the Java &lt;code&gt;keytool&lt;/code&gt; approach that is the standard, recommended method for Android, that makes it a target for adversaries that are interested in breaking keys. If a key was generated using &lt;code&gt;openssl&lt;/code&gt; or GNU TLS instead, for example, then that key would not be affected if &lt;code&gt;keytool&lt;/code&gt; had &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/kroll/software-transparency-debian-openssl-bug/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a bug like Debian’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://security-tracker.debian.org/tracker/CVE-2008-0166&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CVE-2008-0166&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing metadata leakage from software updates</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 12:48:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/10/16/reducing-metadata-leakage-from-software-updates/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: now you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2016/07/31/howto-get-all-your-debian-packages-via-tor-onion-services/&#34;&gt;do this with Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png&#34; alt=&#34;leakage&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-12699&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-300x199.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-100x66.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-150x99.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-200x132.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage.png 410w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Many software update systems use code signing to ensure that only the correct software is downloaded and installed, and to prevent the code from being altered. This is an effective way to prevent the code from being modified, and because of that, software update systems often use plain, unencrypted HTTP connections for downloading code updates. That means that the metadata of what packages a machine has installed is available in plain text for any network observer, from someone sitting on the same public WiFi as you, to state actors with full network observation capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that potentially private information is leaking. That private information could be which packages you have installed and which versions. That information can help an attacker figure out the best way to break into the target machine. Also, a unique fingerprint can be generated based on which packages a machine has installed, and that could help de-anonymize traffic that goes over Tor or other anonymity tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who use &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; in Debian, Ubuntu or any related GNU/Linux distro, there is a lot of metadata leaked to the internet when &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; contacts Debian repositories using a standard configuration. Mostly, that is because by default, the connections are unencrypted (http, ftp, rsync). The integrity of the package itself is not reason enough to use HTTPS since the GPG signing is much more reliable for that task. Here is how I break it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package authenticity&lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;software can be modified while being downloaded&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repo availability&lt;br /&gt;
( &lt;em&gt;whole sites or specific URL paths can be selectively blocked by governments and companies&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package availability&lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;software security updates can be individually blocked&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who’s downloading what package (&lt;em&gt;currently visible to anyone who can see the&lt;br /&gt;
network traffic, including open wifi, etc.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current apt model covers #1 well, but only covers #2 and #3 with a two week window (the expiration date on the repo metadata). And it does not cover #4 at all. Using HTTPS for apt repos is a simple way to improve the security of all 4. It adds a weak backup security layer for #1, it makes it much more difficult for a portion of a large internet mirror to be seletively blocked (e.g. #2 and #3). For example, if you use HTTPS to mirrors.kernel.org, everything has to be blocked to block Debian repos or packages. And pipelining downloads through a reused HTTPS connection makes it very difficult for the network observer to track metadata about packages, #4).&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-150x150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leakage control&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-12701&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-100x100.jpg 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control-200x200.jpg 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/leakage-control.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are some relatively easy steps that greatly reduce the amount of metadata that is leaked: using HTTPS connections to the mirrors and running those connections through Tor. Setting &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; to pipeline as many transactions into a given HTTPS session is also useful, but currently only supported for HTTP and not HTTPS. Even though HTTPS/TLS has security weaknesses, it is a lot better than nothing, and can help provide real world protection. The downside is that it is not common for Debian machines to connect to apt mirrors using HTTPS, so that potentially marks the install as a machine worth targeting. There are more and more HTTPS mirrors, and more interest in using them, so I think in time, that will only lessen as a concern. Here are the HTTPS mirrors that I have had good luck with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mirrors.ece.ubc.ca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mirrors.kernel.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mirror.cse.unsw.edu.au&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spout.ussg.indiana.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, here is the config that I have been using on a number of Debian-deriv machines, and it has been working well. It requires &lt;code&gt;apt-transport-https&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntuguide.org/wiki/Tor#Privoxy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;privoxy&lt;/code&gt; setup as an HTTP proxy for Tor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;$ cat /etc/apt/apt.conf.d/99force-tor
# force everything through privoxy HTTP proxy to tor
Acquire::ftp::Proxy &#34;http://127.0.0.1:8118&#34;;
Acquire::http::Proxy &#34;http://127.0.0.1:8118&#34;;
Acquire::https::Proxy &#34;http://127.0.0.1:8118&#34;;

# don&#39;t use SSL, its insecure, only use TLS
Acquire::https::SslForceVersion &#34;TLSv1&#34;;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found about 10 official Debian mirrors that have reliable HTTPS. Then I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/eighthave/7285154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;script that finds all of them&lt;/a&gt;, but many have self-signed certs and other issues. A number of the HTTPS mirrors also mirror the “security” archive, but I recommend that the &lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; URL to the official &lt;code&gt;security.debian.org&lt;/code&gt; repo is still included to make sure that security updates are promptly available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a test security repo running that is only available via an .onion address. I hope to encourage people to run official mirrors on a Tor Hidden Service, then HTTPS is not needed. Note that &lt;code&gt;apt-transport-tor&lt;/code&gt; is not required if a tor proxy is setup. To try mine, add it to your &lt;code&gt;sources.list&lt;/code&gt; (and make sure &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; is somehow using Tor). The order is important, that determines the priority of where &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; will get the package from is all other variables are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;deb http://dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion/debian-security/ wheezy/updates main
deb http://security.debian.org/ wheezy/updates main
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Use the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://onion.debian.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debian Tor Onion Services&lt;/a&gt; now, &lt;tt&gt;dju2peblv7upfz3q.onion&lt;/tt&gt; is deprecated and will be shut down!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-specific-example-tails&#34;&gt;A specific example: TAILS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tails&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-12711&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-100x100.png 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails-200x200.png 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Tails.png 256w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TAILS&lt;/a&gt; is an operating system that aims to be as private and anonymous as possible to enable, and has allowed &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.press/blog/2014/04/help-support-little-known-privacy-tool-has-been-critical-journalists-reporting-nsa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2014/10/laura-poitras-crypto-tools-made-snowden-film-possible/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laura Poitras&lt;/a&gt; to work without leaking information despite being targeted by some very skilled and highly resourced organizations. TAILS mostly works as a “live CD”, meaning the whole operating system is downloaded as a single “image” file, then either burned to a CD/DVD, or to a USB thumb drive. Updates work the same way. But TAILS has an optional feature to use the Debian package system to install and persist packages that are not included by default. TAILS does not use the default set of mirrors that a standard Debian install uses, it is set up by default with a range of possible Debian package sources, including the current stable version (called wheezy), the versions in testing, and packages backported to the stable version. That means that when this feature is used, TAILS fetches the metadata for all of those sections of Debian (stable/wheezy, testing, wheezy-backports, unstable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given all of the proven fingerprinting approaches, like using the font list from the browser, I think its a safe assumption that the apt-get metadata will also provide similar fingerprinting opportunities. For basic TAILS use, this is all avoided since updates are done via ISO images. But once a user installs packages via &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt;, that changes since TAILS then goes out onto the internet to fetch all of the repo metadata. That goes over Tor since TAILS forces all network traffic over Tor, so that helps break the link between the machine downloading the updates and those that can see that machines internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems quite likely that the set of mirrors and the order in which they are run will provide a way to identify the system as TAILS. As for identifying individual machines, &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; sends a lot of metadata, like language that the system is using, which packages need updates, etc. On top of the set of mirrors used, there is potentially enough metadata there to fingerprint the individual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One open question is how the &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; downloads map to different Tor circuits. If all of the traffic from a given &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; session goes over a single Tor circuit, then the exit node, the mirror server, and any network observer that can see the traffic between those two can use that as the fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To expand on this, if TAILS fetched all of its apt sources (wheezy, backports, testing, etc) via HTTPS from the same mirror (e.g. mirrors.kernel.org), then the exit node and network observer could not really distinguish the distro the machine making the connection was running since mirrors.kernel.org hosts many distro mirrors. There are two key parts here: using HTTPS to encrypt the data, and using HTTP pipelining so that network connections are reused for multiple downloads, rather than the default behavior of making a new HTTPS for each individual download. This setup would also prevent the custom pattern of apt sources from being distinguished since it would just show as downloading some series of files, and those files could be packages, package metadata, perl modules, source tarballs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security in a thumb drive: the promise and pain of hardware security modules, take one!</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/03/28/security-in-a-thumb-drive-the-promise-and-pain-of-hardware-security-modules-take-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 16:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/03/28/security-in-a-thumb-drive-the-promise-and-pain-of-hardware-security-modules-take-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cryptostick-usb-flash-drive-security-software.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cryptostick-usb-flash-drive-security-software.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;security in a thumb drive&#34; width=&#34;219&#34; height=&#34;119&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-12311&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cryptostick-usb-flash-drive-security-software.jpg 219w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cryptostick-usb-flash-drive-security-software-100x54.jpg 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cryptostick-usb-flash-drive-security-software-150x81.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cryptostick-usb-flash-drive-security-software-200x108.jpg 200w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 219px) 100vw, 219px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hardware Security Modules (aka Smartcards, chipcards, etc) provide a secure way to store and use cryptographic keys, while actually making the whole process a bit easier. In theory, one USB thumb drive like thing could manage all of the crypto keys you use in a way that makes them much harder to steal. That is the promise. The reality is that the world of Hardware Security Modules (HSMs) is a massive, scary minefield of endless technical gotchas, byzantine standards (PKCS#11!), technobabble, and incompatibilities. Before I dive too much into ranting about the days of my life wasted trying to find a clear path through this minefield, I’m going to tell you about one path I did find through to solve a key piece of the puzzle: Android and Java package signing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ACS ACR38-T-IBS&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;248&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-12313&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs.jpg 320w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs-300x232.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs-100x77.jpg 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs-150x116.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/moreinfo_acr38t_ibs-200x155.jpg 200w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;For this round, I am covering the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aventra.fi/English/products_MyEID_E.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aventra MyEID PKI Card&lt;/a&gt;. I bought a SIM-sized version to fit into an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smartcardfocus.com/ilp/id~99/ACR38T_IBS/p/readers.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ACS ACR38T-IBS-R&lt;/a&gt; smartcard reader (it is apparently no longer made, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://acs.com.hk/en/products/1/acr38t-d1-plug-in-sim-sized-card-reader/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ACT38T-D1&lt;/a&gt; is meant to replace it). Why such specificity you may ask? Because you have to be sure that your smartcard will work with your reader, and that your reader will have a working driver for you system, and that your smartcard will have a working PKCS#11 driver so that software can talk to the smartcard. Thankfully there is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenSC/OpenSC/wiki&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpenSC&lt;/a&gt; project to cover the PKCS#11 part, it implements the PKCS#11 communications standard for many smartcards. On my Ubuntu/precise system, I had to install an extra driver, &lt;code&gt;libacr38u&lt;/code&gt;, to get the ACR38T reader to show up on my system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s start there and get this thing to show up! First we need some packages. The OpenSC packages are out-of-date in a lot of releases, you need version 0.13.0-4 or newer, so you have to add our PPA (Personal Package Archive) to get current versions, which include a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=742089&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;specific fix for the Aventra MyEID&lt;/a&gt;: (fingerprint: &lt;code&gt;F50E ADDD 2234 F563&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:guardianproject/ppa
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install opensc libacr38u libacsccid1 pcsc-tools usbutils
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing, I use &lt;code&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal to see what USB devices the Linux kernel sees, and thankfully it sees my reader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;$ lsusb
Bus 005 Device 013: ID 072f:9000 Advanced Card Systems, Ltd ACR38 AC1038-based Smart Card Reader
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, its time to try &lt;code&gt;pcsc_scan&lt;/code&gt; to see if the system can see the smartcard installed in the reader. If everything is installed and in order, then &lt;code&gt;pcsc_scan&lt;/code&gt; will report this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;$ pcsc_scan 
PC/SC device scanner
V 1.4.18 (c) 2001-2011, Ludovic Rousseau &amp;lt;&amp;amp;#x6c;u&amp;amp;#x64;ov&amp;amp;#x69;c.&amp;amp;#x72;o&amp;amp;#x75;&amp;amp;#x73;s&amp;amp;#x65;au&amp;amp;#x40;f&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x65;e&amp;amp;#x2e;fr&amp;gt;
Compiled with PC/SC lite version: 1.7.4
Using reader plug&#39;n play mechanism
Scanning present readers...
0: ACS ACR38U 00 00

Thu Mar 27 14:38:36 2014
Reader 0: ACS ACR38U 00 00
  Card state: Card inserted, 
  ATR: 3B F5 18 00 00 81 31 FE 45 4D 79 45 49 44 9A
[snip]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;pcsc_scan&lt;/code&gt; cannot see the card, then things will not work. Try re-seating the smardcard in the reader, make sure you have all the right packages installed, and if you can see the reader in &lt;code&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt;. If your smartcard or reader cannot be read, then &lt;code&gt;pcsc_scan&lt;/code&gt; will report something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;$ pcsc_scan 
PC/SC device scanner
V 1.4.18 (c) 2001-2011, Ludovic Rousseau &amp;lt;&amp;amp;#x6c;&amp;amp;#x75;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x6f;&amp;amp;#x76;&amp;amp;#x69;c.rousse&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x75;&amp;amp;#x40;&amp;amp;#x66;&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x65;e.fr&amp;gt;
Compiled with PC/SC lite version: 1.7.4
Using reader plug&#39;n play mechanism
Scanning present readers...
Waiting for the first reader...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving right along… now &lt;code&gt;pcscd&lt;/code&gt; can see the smartcard, so we can start playing with using the OpenSC tools. These are needed to setup the card, put PINs on it for access control, and upload keys and certificates to it. The last annoying little preparation tasks are finding where &lt;code&gt;opensc-pkcs11.so&lt;/code&gt; is installed and the “slot” for the signing key in the card. These will go into a config file which &lt;code&gt;keytool&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;jarsigner&lt;/code&gt; need. To get this info on Debian/Ubuntu/etc, run these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;$ dpkg -S opensc-pkcs11.so
opensc: /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/opensc-pkcs11.so
$ pkcs11-tool --module /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/opensc-pkcs11.so \
&amp;gt;     --list-slots
Available slots:
Slot 0 (0xffffffffffffffff): Virtual hotplug slot
  (empty)
Slot 1 (0x1): ACS ACR38U 00 00
  token label        : MyEID (signing)
  token manufacturer : Aventra Ltd.
  token model        : PKCS#15
  token flags        : rng, login required, PIN initialized, token initialized
  hardware version   : 0.0
  firmware version   : 0.0
  serial num         : 0106004065952228
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the info needed to put into a &lt;code&gt;opensc-java.cfg&lt;/code&gt;, which &lt;code&gt;keytool&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;jarsigner&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/technotes/guides/security/p11guide.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;need in order to talk&lt;/a&gt; to the Aventra HSM. The name, library, and slot fields are essential, and the description is helpful. Here is how the &lt;code&gt;opensc-java.cfg&lt;/code&gt; using the above information looks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;name = OpenSC
description = SunPKCS11 w/ OpenSC Smart card Framework
library = /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/opensc-pkcs11.so
slot = 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now everything should be ready for initializing the HSM, generating a new key, and uploading that key to the HSM. This process generates the key and certificate, puts them into files, then uploads them to the HSM. That means you should only run this process on a trusted machine, certainly with some kind of disk encryption, and preferably on a machine that is not connected to a network, running an OS that has never been connected to the internet. A live CD is one good example, I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/download/index.en.html#index4h1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tails on a USB thumb drive&lt;/a&gt; running with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/doc/first_steps/persistence/index.en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;secure persistent store&lt;/a&gt; on it (we have been working here and there on making a TAILS-based distro specifically for managing keys, we call it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info/projects/psst/wiki/CleanRoom&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CleanRoom&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12321&#34; style=&#34;width: 560px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12321&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-1024x805.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HSM plugged into a laptop&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;432&#34; class=&#34;size-large wp-image-12321&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-1024x805.jpg 1024w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-300x235.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-100x78.jpg 100w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-150x117.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-200x157.jpg 200w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-450x353.jpg 450w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-600x471.jpg 600w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2-900x707.jpg 900w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cstick2.jpg 1600w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12321&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    HSM plugged into a laptop
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, the HSM needs to be initialized, then set up with a signing PIN and a “Security Officer” PIN (which means basically an “admin” or “root” PIN). The signing PIN is the one you will use for signing APKs, the “Security Officer PIN” (SO-PIN) is used for modifying the HSM setup, like uploading new keys, etc. Because there are so many steps in the process, I’ve written up scripts to run thru all of the steps. If you want to see the details, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/smartcard-apk-signing/blob/master/Aventra_MyEID_Setup/setup.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/smartcard-apk-signing/blob/master/openssl-gen/gen.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/guardianproject/smartcard-apk-signing/blob/master/Aventra_MyEID_Setup/finalize.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scripts&lt;/a&gt;. The next step is to generate the key using &lt;code&gt;openssl&lt;/code&gt; and upload it to the HSM. Then the HSM needs to be “finalized”, which means the PINs are activated, and keys cannot be uploaded. Don’t worry, as long as you have the SO-PIN, you can erase the HSM and re-initialize it. But be careful! Many HSMs will permanently self-destruct if you enter in the wrong PIN too many times, some will do that after only three wrong PINs! As long as you have not finalized the HSM, any PIN will work, so play around a lot with it before finalizing it. Run the init and key upload procedure a few times, try signing an APK, etc. Take note: the script will generate a random password for the secret files, then echo that password when it completes, so make sure no one can see your screen when you generate the real key. Alright, here goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;code $ git clone https://github.com/guardianproject/smartcard-apk-signing
code $ cd smartcard-apk-signing/Aventra_MyEID_Setup
Aventra_MyEID_Setup $ ./setup.sh 
Edit pkcs15-init-options-file-pins to put in the PINs you want to set:
Aventra_MyEID_Setup $ emacs pkcs15-init-options-file-pins
Aventra_MyEID_Setup $ ./setup.sh 
Using reader with a card: ACS ACR38U 00 00
Connecting to card in reader ACS ACR38U 00 00...
Using card driver MyEID cards with PKCS#15 applet.
About to erase card.
PIN [Security Officer PIN] required.
Please enter PIN [Security Officer PIN]: 
Using reader with a card: ACS ACR38U 00 00
Connecting to card in reader ACS ACR38U 00 00...
Using card driver MyEID cards with PKCS#15 applet.
About to create PKCS #15 meta structure.
Using reader with a card: ACS ACR38U 00 00
Connecting to card in reader ACS ACR38U 00 00...
Using card driver MyEID cards with PKCS#15 applet.
Found MyEID
About to generate key.
Using reader with a card: ACS ACR38U 00 00
Connecting to card in reader ACS ACR38U 00 00...
Using card driver MyEID cards with PKCS#15 applet.
Found MyEID
About to generate key.
next generate a key with ./gen.sh then ./finalize.sh
Aventra_MyEID_Setup $ cd ../openssl-gen/
openssl-gen $ ./gen.sh 
Usage: ./gen.sh &amp;quot;CertDName&amp;quot; [4096]
  for example:
  &amp;quot;/C=US/ST=New York/O=Guardian Project &amp;amp;#x54;e&amp;amp;#x73;&amp;amp;#x74;/&amp;amp;#x43;N=&amp;amp;#x74;es&amp;amp;#x74;.&amp;amp;#x67;&amp;amp;#x75;a&amp;amp;#x72;di&amp;amp;#x61;np&amp;amp;#x72;o&amp;amp;#x6a;&amp;amp;#x65;c&amp;amp;#x74;&amp;amp;#x2e;i&amp;amp;#x6e;fo&amp;amp;#x2f;em&amp;amp;#x61;i&amp;amp;#x6c;&amp;amp;#x41;d&amp;amp;#x64;re&amp;amp;#x73;s=&amp;amp;#x74;e&amp;amp;#x73;&amp;amp;#x74;@&amp;amp;#x67;&amp;amp;#x75;a&amp;amp;#x72;di&amp;amp;#x61;np&amp;amp;#x72;o&amp;amp;#x6a;&amp;amp;#x65;c&amp;amp;#x74;.i&amp;amp;#x6e;fo&amp;quot;
openssl-gen $ ./gen.sh &amp;quot;/C=US/ST=New York/O=Guardian Project Te&amp;amp;#x73;t&amp;amp;#x2f;C&amp;amp;#x4e;=&amp;amp;#x74;e&amp;amp;#x73;t&amp;amp;#x2e;g&amp;amp;#x75;ardi&amp;amp;#x61;n&amp;amp;#x70;r&amp;amp;#x6f;j&amp;amp;#x65;c&amp;amp;#x74;.&amp;amp;#x69;n&amp;amp;#x66;o/em&amp;amp;#x61;i&amp;amp;#x6c;A&amp;amp;#x64;d&amp;amp;#x72;e&amp;amp;#x73;s&amp;amp;#x3d;t&amp;amp;#x65;st&amp;amp;#x40;g&amp;amp;#x75;a&amp;amp;#x72;d&amp;amp;#x69;a&amp;amp;#x6e;p&amp;amp;#x72;o&amp;amp;#x6a;e&amp;amp;#x63;t.&amp;amp;#x69;n&amp;amp;#x66;o&amp;quot;
Generating key, be patient...
2048 semi-random bytes loaded
Generating RSA private key, 2048 bit long modulus
.......................................+++
..................................................+++
e is 65537 (0x10001)
Signature ok
subject=/C=US/ST=New York/O=Guardian Project Test/&amp;amp;#x43;&amp;amp;#x4e;&amp;amp;#x3d;&amp;amp;#x74;&amp;amp;#x65;st.gu&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x69;&amp;amp;#x61;nproj&amp;amp;#x65;&amp;amp;#x63;&amp;amp;#x74;&amp;amp;#x2e;&amp;amp;#x69;nfo/e&amp;amp;#x6d;&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x69;&amp;amp;#x6c;&amp;amp;#x41;ddres&amp;amp;#x73;&amp;amp;#x3d;&amp;amp;#x74;&amp;amp;#x65;&amp;amp;#x73;t@gua&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x69;&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x6e;proje&amp;amp;#x63;&amp;amp;#x74;&amp;amp;#x2e;&amp;amp;#x69;&amp;amp;#x6e;fo
Getting Private key
writing RSA key
Your HSM will prompt you for &#39;Security Officer&#39; aka admin PIN, wait for it!
Enter destination keystore password:  
Entry for alias 1 successfully imported.
Import command completed:  1 entries successfully imported, 0 entries failed or cancelled
[Storing keystore]
Key fingerprints for reference:
MD5 Fingerprint=90:24:68:F3:F3:22:7D:13:8C:81:11:C3:A4:B6:9A:2F
SHA1 Fingerprint=3D:9D:01:C9:28:BD:1F:F4:10:80:FC:02:95:51:39:F4:7D:E7:A9:B1
SHA256 Fingerprint=C6:3A:ED:1A:C7:9D:37:C7:B0:47:44:72:AC:6E:FA:6C:3A:B2:B1:1A:76:7A:4F:42:CF:36:0F:A5:49:6E:3C:50
The public files are: certificate.pem publickey.pem request.pem
The secret files are: secretkey.pem certificate.p12 certificate.jkr
The passphrase for the secret files is: fTQ*he-[:y+69RS+W&amp;amp;+!*0O5i%n
openssl-gen $ cd ../Aventra_MyEID_Setup/
Aventra_MyEID_Setup $ ./finalize.sh 
Using reader with a card: ACS ACR38U 00 00
Connecting to card in reader ACS ACR38U 00 00...
Using card driver MyEID cards with PKCS#15 applet.
Found MyEID
About to delete object(s).
Your HSM is ready for use! Put the secret key files someplace encrypted and safe!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now your HSM should be ready for use for signing. You can try it out with &lt;code&gt;keytool&lt;/code&gt; to see what is on it, using the signing PIN not the Security Officer PIN:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;smartcard-apk-signing $ /usr/bin/keytool -v \
&amp;gt;     -providerClass sun.security.pkcs11.SunPKCS11 \
&amp;gt;     -providerArg opensc-java.cfg \
&amp;gt;     -providerName SunPKCS11-OpenSC -keystore NONE -storetype PKCS11 \
&amp;gt;     -list
Enter keystore password:  

Keystore type: PKCS11
Keystore provider: SunPKCS11-OpenSC

Your keystore contains 1 entry

Alias name: 1
Entry type: PrivateKeyEntry
Certificate chain length: 1
Certificate[1]:
Owner: &amp;amp;#x45;&amp;amp;#x4d;&amp;amp;#x41;&amp;amp;#x49;&amp;amp;#x4c;&amp;amp;#x41;&amp;amp;#x44;&amp;amp;#x44;RESS=test@g&amp;amp;#x75;&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x72;&amp;amp;#x64;&amp;amp;#x69;&amp;amp;#x61;&amp;amp;#x6e;&amp;amp;#x70;&amp;amp;#x72;oject.info, CN=test.guardianproject.info, O=Guardian Project Test, ST=New York, C=US
Issuer: E&amp;amp;#x4d;A&amp;amp;#x49;LA&amp;amp;#x44;D&amp;amp;#x52;ES&amp;amp;#x53;=&amp;amp;#x74;e&amp;amp;#x73;&amp;amp;#x74;@&amp;amp;#x67;u&amp;amp;#x61;rd&amp;amp;#x69;a&amp;amp;#x6e;pr&amp;amp;#x6f;j&amp;amp;#x65;ct&amp;amp;#x2e;i&amp;amp;#x6e;f&amp;amp;#x6f;, CN=test.guardianproject.info, O=Guardian Project Test, ST=New York, C=US
Serial number: aa6887be1ec84bde
Valid from: Fri Mar 28 16:41:26 EDT 2014 until: Mon Aug 12 16:41:26 EDT 2041
Certificate fingerprints:
	 MD5:  90:24:68:F3:F3:22:7D:13:8C:81:11:C3:A4:B6:9A:2F
	 SHA1: 3D:9D:01:C9:28:BD:1F:F4:10:80:FC:02:95:51:39:F4:7D:E7:A9:B1
	 SHA256: C6:3A:ED:1A:C7:9D:37:C7:B0:47:44:72:AC:6E:FA:6C:3A:B2:B1:1A:76:7A:4F:42:CF:36:0F:A5:49:6E:3C:50
	 Signature algorithm name: SHA1withRSA
	 Version: 1


*******************************************
*******************************************
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let’s try signing an actual APK using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/tools/publishing/app-signing.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;arguments that Google recommends&lt;/a&gt;, again, using the signing PIN:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;smartcard-apk-signing $ /usr/bin/jarsigner -verbose \
&amp;gt;     -providerClass sun.security.pkcs11.SunPKCS11 \
&amp;gt;     -providerArg opensc-java.cfg -providerName SunPKCS11-OpenSC \
&amp;gt;     -keystore NONE -storetype PKCS11 \
&amp;gt;     -sigalg SHA1withRSA -digestalg SHA1 \
&amp;gt;     bin/LilDebi-release-unsigned.apk 1
Enter Passphrase for keystore: 
   adding: META-INF/1.SF
   adding: META-INF/1.RSA
  signing: assets/busybox
  signing: assets/complete-debian-setup.sh
  signing: assets/configure-downloaded-image.sh
  signing: assets/create-debian-setup.sh
  signing: assets/debian-archive-keyring.gpg
  signing: assets/debootstrap.tar.bz2
  signing: assets/e2fsck.static
  signing: assets/gpgv
  signing: assets/lildebi-common
[snip]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a working, but elaborate, process for setting up a Hardware Security Module for signing APKs. Once the HSM is setup, using it should be quite straightforward. Next steps are to work out as many kinks in this process as possible so this will be the default way to sign APKs. That means things like figuring out how &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=742831&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Java can be pre-configured to use OpenSC in the Debian package&lt;/a&gt;, as well as including all &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=742089&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;relevant fixes&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;pcscd&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;opensc&lt;/code&gt; packages. Then the ultimate is to add support for using HSMs in Android’s generated build files like the &lt;code&gt;build.xml&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;ant&lt;/code&gt; that is generated by &lt;code&gt;android update project&lt;/code&gt;. Then people could just plug in the HSM and run &lt;code&gt;ant release&lt;/code&gt; and have a signed APK!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking HTTPS for Better Security</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/02/12/tweaking-https-for-better-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 19:14:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2014/02/12/tweaking-https-for-better-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The HTTPS protocol is based on TLS and SSL, which are standard ways to negotiate encrypted connections. There is a lot of complexity in the protocols and lots of config options, but luckily most of the config options can be ignored since the defaults are fine. But there are some things worth tweaking to ensure that as many connections as possible are using reliable encryption ciphers while providing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forward_secrecy&#34;&gt;forward secrecy&lt;/a&gt;. A connection with forward secrecy provides protection to past transactions even if the server’s HTTPS private key/certificate is stolen or compromised. This protects your users from large scale network observers that can store all traffic for later decryption, like governments, ISPs, telecoms, etc. From the server operator’s point of view, it means less risk of leaking users’ data, since even if the server is compromised, past network traffic will probably not be able to be encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my situation, I was using our development site, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.guardianproject.info&#34;&gt;https://dev.guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as my test bed, it is Apache 2.2 and openssl 1.0.1 running on Ubuntu/precise 12.04 Long-Term Support, so that means that some of the options are more limited since this is an older release. On Debian, Ubuntu and other Debian-derivatives, you’ll only need to edit &lt;code&gt;/etc/apache2/mods-available/ssl.conf&lt;/code&gt;. There are more paranoid resources &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2013/08/05/configuring-apache-nginx-and-openssl-for-forward-secrecy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;for perfectly configuring your TLS&lt;/a&gt;, but we’re not ready to drop support for old browsers that only support SSLv3, and not TLS at all. So I went with this line to enable SSLv3 and TLSv1.0 and newer:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
SSLProtocol all -SSLv2&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With TLS connections, the client and the server each present a list of encryption ciphers that represent the ciphers they each support in order of preference. This enables the client and server to choose a cipher that both support. Normally, the client’s list takes precedence over the server’s, but with many browsers that can be changed. Unfortunately it seems that Microsoft Internet Explorer (IE) ignores this and always uses the client’s preference first. Here’s how to make Apache request that the server preferences are preferred:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
SSLHonorCipherOrder on&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is tweaking the server’s preference list to put ciphers that enable forward secrecy first (don’t worry if you don’t understand the next stuff about my rationale, my aim is to walk thru the process). This is done in most web servers using openssl-style cipher lists. I started out with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Security/Server_Side_TLS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;what Mozilla recommends&lt;/a&gt;, then pared down the list to remove AES-256 ciphers, since AES-128 is widely regarded to be faster, quite strong, and perhaps &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Security/Server_Side_TLS#Prioritization_logic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more resistant to timing attacks than AES-256&lt;/a&gt;. I also chose to remove RC4-based ciphers, since &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Security/Server_Side_TLS#RC4_weaknesses&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RC4 might already be broken&lt;/a&gt;, and will only get worse with time. RC4 has historically been used to mitigate the “BEAST” attack, but that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2013/09/10/is-beast-still-a-threat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mostly happening in the clients now&lt;/a&gt;. So with that I ended up with this cipher list (should be all one line in your config file):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
SSLCipherSuite &amp;quot;ECDHE-RSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:DHE-RSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-SHA256:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-SHA:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-SHA:DHE-RSA-AES128-SHA256:DHE-RSA-AES128-SHA:DHE-RSA-CAMELLIA128-SHA:AES128-GCM-SHA256:AES128-SHA256:AES128-SHA:CAMELLIA128-SHA:DES-CBC3-SHA&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to make sure is that all of these ciphers are supported on your system. You can get the list of supported ciphers from &lt;code&gt;openssl ciphers&lt;/code&gt;. I used this command line to get them in a nice, alphabetized list:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
openssl ciphers | sed &#39;s,:,\n,g&#39; | sort&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we want to set the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HSTS&lt;/a&gt; header to tell the browser to always use HTTPS. To enforce this, a header is added to the collection of HTTP headers delivered when connecting to the HTTPS site. This header tells the client browser to always connect to the current domain using HTTPS. It includes an expiration date (aka &lt;code&gt;max-age&lt;/code&gt;) after which, the client browser will again allow HTTP connections to that domain. The server might then again redirect the HTTP connection to HTTPS, and again the client will get the HSTS header, and use only HTTPS until the expiration date comes again. To include this header in your Apache server, add this line:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Header add Strict-Transport-Security &amp;quot;max-age=15768000;includeSubDomains&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can check the results of your work with Qualys’ handy SSL Test. You can see the result of my efforts here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=dev.guardianproject.info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=dev.guardianproject.info&#34;&gt;https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=dev.guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;A-&lt;/strong&gt; is not bad. I tried for a good long while to get IE to use FS (Forward Secrecy) ciphers, but failed. IE does not respect the server-side cipher preferences. My guess is that the only way to get IE to use FS ciphers is to make a custom cipher list that does not include anything but FS ciphers and serve that only to IE. I know it is possible to do because &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=bitbucket.com&amp;s=131.103.20.172&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bitbucket.com got an &lt;strong&gt;A+&lt;/strong&gt; for doing it&lt;/a&gt;. For a quick way to check out the cipher lists and HSTS header, look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iSECPartners/sslyze&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iSEC Partner’s sslyze&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only a quick overview of the process to outline the general concepts. To find out more I recommend reading the source articles for this post, including specific directions for nginx and lighttpd:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Security/Server_Side_TLS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Server-side TLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qualys’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2013/08/05/configuring-apache-nginx-and-openssl-for-forward-secrecy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Configuring Apache, Nginx, and OpenSSL for Forward Secrecy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qualys’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2013/09/10/is-beast-still-a-threat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Is BEAST Still a Threat?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HTTP Strict Transport Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting keys into your keyring with Gnu Privacy Guard for Android</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/12/06/getting-keys-into-your-keyring-with-gnu-privacy-guard-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 15:11:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/12/06/getting-keys-into-your-keyring-with-gnu-privacy-guard-for-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you can have a full &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnupg.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GnuPG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on your Android device with &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.gpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for Android, the next step is getting keys you need onto your device and included in &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt;. We have tried to make it as easy as possible without compromising privacy, and have implemented a few approaches, while working on others. There are a few ways to get this done right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt; registered itself with Android as a handler of all the standard &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc3156.txt&#34; title=&#34;RFC3156: MIME Security with OpenPGP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpenPGP MIME types&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;code&gt;application/pgp-keys&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;application/pgp-encrypted&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;application/pgp-signature&lt;/code&gt;), as well as all of the OpenPGP and GnuPG file extensions (&lt;code&gt;.pkr&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;.skr&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;.key&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;.sig&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;.asc&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;.gpg&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;.bin&lt;/code&gt;). This means that users just have to share a file to &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt; using any of the standard Android methods, these files can be launched from an email attachment, opened from the SD card using a file browser, clicked in the Downloads view, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to quickly send your whole public keyring from your laptop to your mobile device, you can just grab the database file directly from &lt;em&gt;GnuPG&lt;/em&gt; and copy it to your SD card. Here is how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plug your device into your laptop via USB so you can copy files to the SD card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find your &lt;em&gt;GnuPG&lt;/em&gt; home folder (on GNU/Linux and Mac OS X, it will be in &lt;code&gt;~/.gnupg/pubring.gpg&lt;/code&gt;, on Windows it is &lt;code&gt;%APPDATA%\gnupg&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your &lt;em&gt;GnuPG&lt;/em&gt; home folder, copy &lt;strong&gt;pubring.gpg&lt;/strong&gt; to your device’s SD card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unmount and unplug your device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on your device, open your favorite file manager app (&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.openintents.filemanager&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OI File Manager&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Astro&lt;/em&gt;, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go to the SD card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;long-click on &lt;strong&gt;pubring.gpg&lt;/strong&gt; and share it to &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click OK on the Import Keys dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt; will do the rest. Give is some time to sync to the Contacts database, then you’ll see all of your keys from your desktop are now in your People app and are listed in &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt; itself. You can now encrypt files to any of those keys, or verify files signed by any of those keys. Here are a couple screenshots to illustrate key points in the process, using &lt;em&gt;OI File Manager&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12155&#34; style=&#34;width: 209px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-0.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12155&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-0-199x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;send your public keyring file&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-12155&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-0-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-0.png 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12155&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
      1. send your public keyring file
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12156&#34; style=&#34;width: 209px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12156&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-1-199x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;choose Gnu Privacy Guard to send the file to&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-12156&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-1-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-1.png 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12156&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    2. choose &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt; to send the file to
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12157&#34; style=&#34;width: 209px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12157&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-2-199x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;click OK to import the key file&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-12157&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-2-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-2.png 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12157&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    3. click OK to import the key file
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12158&#34; style=&#34;width: 209px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12158&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-3-199x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;now you can see the imported keys in Gnu Privacy Guard&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-12158&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-3-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-import-key-file-3.png 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12158&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    4. now you can see the imported keys in &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to get the keyring files like &lt;strong&gt;pubring.gpg&lt;/strong&gt; to your device: you can also share the keyring files via email, chat, or even services like &lt;em&gt;Dropbox&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Google Drive&lt;/em&gt;. Then once the files are on your device, you can import them using the same procedure as above. But keep in mind that you are sending your whole collection of secure contacts to that service, which will have full access to read it. If you have any worries about leaking your keyring to anyone, then a good method is to copy it directly to the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12192&#34; style=&#34;width: 209px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-search-keyserver.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12192&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-search-keyserver-199x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;search the keyserver for the author&#39;s key (I lost the key from 1998, so don&#39;t use that one...)&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-12192&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-search-keyserver-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/GPGA-search-keyserver.png 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12192&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    search the keyserver for the author’s key (the key from 1998 is lost, don’t use that one…)
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also search and download keys via the public pool of OpenPGP keyservers. If you already know someone’s keyid or fingerprint, you can search using that. Otherwise, you can search based on name or email address. But be careful! Downloading a key from a keyserver does not give you a key you can trust. Anyone can upload a key to the keyservers, and they can make that key have any name or email address. Downloading from the keyservers is a convenient way to download a key, but you must verify the key’s fingerprint with the person you are trying to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_12184&#34; style=&#34;width: 160px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/0x9F0FE587374BBE81-qr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-12184&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/0x9F0FE587374BBE81-qr-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;scan this QR Code to get the author&#39;s OpenPGP key&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;size-thumbnail wp-image-12184&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/0x9F0FE587374BBE81-qr-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/0x9F0FE587374BBE81-qr-300x300.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/0x9F0FE587374BBE81-qr.png 330w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-12184&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    scan this QR Code to get the author’s OpenPGP key
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;In conjunction with the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.monkeysphere.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Monkeysphere&lt;/a&gt; project, we developed a standard URI scheme for sending OpenPGP key fingerprints. For example, you can find my key ID here: &lt;a href=&#34;openpgp4fpr:9F0FE587374BBE81&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;openpgp4fpr:9F0FE587374BBE81&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This provides a clickable way to get an OpenPGP key. On an Android device with &lt;em&gt;Gnu Privacy Guard&lt;/em&gt; installed, you can click on this link to download my key from the keyservers. This URI scheme also works well in QR Codes. Scan this QR Code on your device with an app like &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.zxing.client.android&#34; title=&#34;Barcode Scanner in the Google Play Store&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barcode Scanner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and click &lt;strong&gt;Open Browser&lt;/strong&gt;, and Gnu Privacy Guard will download my key to your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other ideas out there that we also want to support. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sufficientlysecure.org/index.php/openpgp-keychain/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OpenPGP Keychain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes a way to transmit the whole public key via &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Near_field_communication&#34; title=&#34;Near Field Communication&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NFC&lt;/a&gt;. This allows people can swap keys directly from phone to phone without having internet access at all. But NFC is quite slow to transmit data so the devices need to be held together for a while until the whole key is received. NFC could be used to rapidly transmit an &lt;code&gt;openpgp4fpr:&lt;/code&gt; URI, and then the whole public key would be fetched from a keyserver, but that then requires internet access and also leaks a bit of metadata to the internet. A better technique would be to transmit the entire public key over Bluetooth, using NFC to setup the Bluetooth session. We’re also looking at ways to do this via WiFi and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonjour_(software)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bonjour (mDNS)&lt;/a&gt; local service advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up your own app store with F-Droid</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/11/05/setting-up-your-own-app-store-with-f-droid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 11:55:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/11/05/setting-up-your-own-app-store-with-f-droid/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;(_This blog post as now been cooked into an &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/wiki/page/Setup_an_FDroid_App_Repo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;updated HOWTO&lt;/a&gt;_)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Play Store for Android is not available in all parts of the world, US law restricts its use in certain countries like Iran, and many countries block access to the Play Store, like China. Also, the Google Play Store tracks all user actions, reporting back to Google what apps have been installed and also run on the phone. Because of the NSA leaks, we’re seeing that governments are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/oct/30/google-reports-nsa-secretly-intercepts-data-links&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;actively tapping&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/31/technology/nsa-is-mining-google-and-yahoo-abroad.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the raw data streams&lt;/a&gt; of Google, Yahoo, and others. So that means the information the Google Play Store sends back to Google is also intercepted by the NSA (and probably other country’s agencies), and that information is shared with other governments. In other words, your activity on the Google Play Store is far from private. Lastly, the Google Play Store is not free software, unlike the core of Android itself. It is proprietary software that Google entirely controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/your-own-app-store.png&#34; alt=&#34;your-own-app-store&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;203&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-11896&#34; /&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34; title=&#34;F-Droid Home Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful, free app store for Android. It is modeled after the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian.org&#34; title=&#34;Debian home page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt; distro. It has its own package repositories (repos) and build servers for all the apps that are part of the official OS. Like Debian and Ubuntu, you can also setup your own repos for anyone to use. Any free software can be added to the official F-Droid repos, where they are built and signed by the F-Droid server. This can be annoying because it means that your apps in F-Droid are signed by a different key than your apps in the Google Play Store. If you host your own F-Droid repo, then people can use F-Droid to install your own builds signed by your own signing key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a quick HOWTO for how to setup such a repository on a Debian or Ubuntu box. It is somewhat technical, you will use the terminal, but you don’t need to be a terminal expert to follow along. First you need a the &lt;code&gt;fdroidserver&lt;/code&gt; tools and a webserver. For the webserver, here we use &lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt; for the webserver since its lightweight, but any will do if you already have one running. The fdroidserver tools are not yet in the official Debian/Ubuntu/etc repos, so you have to add our PPA (Personal Package Archive) to get it (fingerprint: &lt;tt&gt;F50E ADDD 2234 F563&lt;/tt&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:guardianproject/ppa
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install fdroidserver nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of this HOWTO, we’re going to setup a “&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/manual/fdroid.html#Simple-Binary-Repository&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Simple Binary Repository&lt;/a&gt;” to host our official APKs. The repo will be set up in the recommended &lt;code&gt;fdroid/&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory. This gives the &lt;code&gt;fdroid&lt;/code&gt; tool its own directory to work in, and makes the repo URL clearly marked as an FDroid repo. Let’s give our normal user control over this subdirectory in the web root so that we don’t need to run the F-Droid tools as root (with &lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt;, the webroot is &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/nginx/www&lt;/code&gt;, it is different for other webservers):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir /usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid
sudo chown -R $USER /usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid
cd /usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid
fdroid init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now put your APK files into &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid/repo&lt;/code&gt; and you are ready to run the commands to build the repo (if &lt;code&gt;fdroid init&lt;/code&gt; cannot find your Android SDK in &lt;code&gt;/opt/android-sdk&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;$ANDROID_HOME&lt;/code&gt;, it will prompt you for the path):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid
cp /path/to/*.apk /usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid/repo/
fdroid update -c
fdroid update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/fdroidheader3-300x75.png&#34; alt=&#34;fdroidheader3&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;75&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-11906&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/fdroidheader3-300x75.png 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/fdroidheader3.png 720w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Voila! Now you have a working F-Droid Repo! Add it to an F-Droid client on your Android device to test it out. That is done in the &lt;strong&gt;Manage Repos&lt;/strong&gt; screen available from the menu. Your repo URL will be the hostname or IP address of your machine with &lt;code&gt;/fdroid/repo/&lt;/code&gt; added to the end of it, i.e. &lt;code&gt;https://mysecureserver.com/fdroid/repo/&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;http://192.168.2.53/fdroid/repo/&lt;/code&gt;. You can temporarily uncheck the official repos to easily see what F-Droid found in your new repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;customization&#34;&gt;Customization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also customize your repo by editing the config file. Be sure to use a programming text editor, like &lt;code&gt;editor /usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid/config.py&lt;/code&gt;. In the config file, you can set the name of the repo, the description, the icon, paths to specific versions of the build tools, links to a related wiki, and whether to keep stats. Here’s the basic repo description block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;repo_url = &amp;quot;https://guardianproject.info/fdroid/repo&amp;quot;
repo_name = &amp;quot;My Local Repo&amp;quot;
repo_icon = &amp;quot;GP_Logo_hires.png&amp;quot;
repo_description = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
This is a local test repository of Hans-Christoph Steiner &amp;lt;&amp;amp;#x68;a&amp;amp;#x6e;s@&amp;amp;#x67;ua&amp;amp;#x72;d&amp;amp;#x69;&amp;amp;#x61;n&amp;amp;#x70;ro&amp;amp;#x6a;e&amp;amp;#x63;&amp;amp;#x74;.&amp;amp;#x69;nf&amp;amp;#x6f;&amp;gt;.  It is a repository of Guardian Project apps.
&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put your icon into your repo, choose a PNG image to put in your repo. The PNG goes in &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid/&lt;/code&gt;, the file can be named whatever you want (by default its &lt;code&gt;fdroid-icon.png&lt;/code&gt;). If you change the name from the default, be sure to update &lt;code&gt;repo_icon&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;archive_icon&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid/config.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-security&#34;&gt;More Security&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/apg.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/apg-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;apg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-1029&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/apg-150x150.png 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/apg.png 256w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Now that you have a working repo, its time to improve the security. Generating a repo in place is very easy, that is why this HOWTO started there, but it is not as secure as it should be if your repo is going to be your main distribution point. When generating the repo in place, make sure that &lt;code&gt;config.py&lt;/code&gt; is not accessible via the web, since it contains passwords. If the file permissions are correct (e.g. &lt;code&gt;chmod 0600 config.py&lt;/code&gt;), then &lt;code&gt;config.py&lt;/code&gt; will not be readable by the webserver. But the signing keys will still be that public server. To improve this situation, generate the repo on a non-public machine like your laptop, keeping &lt;code&gt;config.py&lt;/code&gt; and the keystore only on that machine, then use &lt;code&gt;fdroid server update&lt;/code&gt; to publish the changes to your repo on a separate server. You just need to set &lt;code&gt;serverwebroot&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.py&lt;/code&gt; properly, then &lt;code&gt;fdroid server update&lt;/code&gt; will do the publishing via rsync over ssh. So both computers will have to have ssh and rsync installed and setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use your own existing signing key rather than the one generated by &lt;code&gt;fdroid init&lt;/code&gt;, just edit &lt;code&gt;repo_keyalias&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;keystore&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;keystorepass&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;keypass&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;keydname&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/nginx/www/fdroid/config.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we like Tor and its Hidden Services for providing privacy, we also want to setup an F-Droid repository that is accessible over a Tor Hidden Service aka onion address. This will be covered in a future HOWTO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Way to Visit Strongbox on a Phone</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/05/16/the-only-way-to-visit-strongbox-on-a-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 17:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/05/16/the-only-way-to-visit-strongbox-on-a-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; magazine just launched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/closeread/2013/05/introducing-strongbox-anonymous-document-sharing-tool.html&#34;&gt;Strongbox&lt;/a&gt;, a whistleblower submission system that’s hosted on a hidden website. There’s only one way to access the hidden site on a phone or tablet, and that’s with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.browser&amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Orweb app&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s a simple breakdown of how to do securely and anonymously blow the whistle, explained in an interactive tutorial:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3719  aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy19&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19-199x300.png&#34; width=&#34;199&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19-199x300.png 199w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/galaxy19.png 400w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Visit &lt;a title=&#34;strongbox tutorial&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guardianproject.info/howto/strongbox&lt;/a&gt; for an interactive tutorial on using Strongbox on your phone.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The website exists as a hidden site on what is widely known as the darknet, since you are going there hidden or “in the dark.” Instead of a .com, .org, or .info address (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;) the sites like Strongbox show up with a .onion. And like you need a web browser to go to a .com web address, you need a darknet browser to go to a .onion darknet address. On a mobile, we make the most secure and anonymous darknet &amp; web browser, Orweb. And if you want to get to strongbox on your phone, we’re the only way to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  To browse, you’ll need our &lt;a title=&#34;orweb&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orweb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orweb&lt;/a&gt; app. It’s currently only available for Android and you can &lt;a title=&#34;Orweb anonymous browser&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.browser &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;get it here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have another type of phone or tablet, unfortunately you’ll have to use a computer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  For Orweb to be anonymous and give you access to the darknet .onion addresses, you’ll need to enable onion routing with our &lt;a title=&#34;orbot&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/apps/orbot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; plugin. This plugin gives Orweb and other compatible apps (like our &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.otr.app.im&#34;&gt;Gibberbot secure chat&lt;/a&gt;  for Facebook, Google, &amp; Jabber) the ability to send web traffic through the darknet, thus avoiding tracking as well as blocking. You can &lt;a title=&#34;Orbot on Android&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.android  &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;download Orbot here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the official app of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://TorProject.org&#34;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt;, which develops the onion routing protocol, on Android.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Once both are installed, you just need to go to this hidden site: &lt;a title=&#34;Strongbox Onion Site&#34; href=&#34;http://tnysbtbxsf356hiy.onion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://tnysbtbxsf356hiy.onion&lt;/a&gt; . Make sure that you’re using the Orweb browser and that Orbot is running. From there, you can easily submit messages to The New Yorker. Unfortunately you can’t yet submit files to them through the phone just yet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Overall, this is an exciting step in the right direction. With an increase in tracking and crackdown on political dissidents and whistleblowers around the world, there need to be safe and trusted ways of sharing information that has the potential of saving lives and making the world a better place. &lt;a title=&#34;the new yorker magazine&#34; href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most trusted journalistic outfits in the world and it will be interesting to follow how they understand and vet information that comes in from anonymous sources. It will be a lesson for the entire privacy community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/PihUXCmJzW/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-3730 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;On the Internet, algorithms can infer you&#39;re a dog.&#34; alt=&#34;Dog Algorithm&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-300x300.jpg 300w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm-150x150.jpg 150w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Dog-Algorithm.jpg 612w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  At the same time, it’s not yet a trusted technology. While the code is accessible and &lt;a href=&#34;http://deaddrop.github.io/&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; it is unclear whether it’s a full version of the DeadDrop code that it came from or a fork of it. It also hasn’t been audited yet. Already, we’re seeing issues popping up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deaddrop/deaddrop/issues&#34;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully it will be fully vetted as a solution and stand up to the ambitious and crucial claims that it is able “to provide you with a greater degree of anonymity and security than afforded by conventional e-mail.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  In the months before January, I worked a few seats down from Aaron Swartz in the ThoughtWorks offices. Since those shocking days, it’s been inspiring to continue to see his legacy. I spoke with him a bunch of times about using technology to introduce truly disruptive techniques for empowering people whose rights were otherwise being trampled. At the time, we were working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbelinsky.com/crowdring/&#34;&gt;Crowdring&lt;/a&gt;, an intiative from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.therules.org/&#34;&gt;/The Rules&lt;/a&gt;. And we spoke about the power of leveraging telephony to give voice so widely, and the trade off of handing over personally identifiable information. He recognized the need for constantly evolving and shifting tactics and was expert at integrating that into both strategy and code. It’s an honor to continue to work with him now, and with the rest of the open source community as we all contribute code and ideas to make the world better.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Having just won the Knight News Challenge for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/2013/01/27/informacam-wins-knight-news-challenge/&#34;&gt;Informacam project&lt;/a&gt;, we’re excited at the growing interest from the world of journalism in making sure that sources are kept truly secure and anonymous in the digital age. We’re working to build our whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=6502754515281796553&#34;&gt;suite of tools&lt;/a&gt; to make it easier and better to do so. If you want to reach out to us, anonymously or otherwise, to &lt;a title=&#34;Guardian Contact&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/ &#34;&gt;let us know how we can help&lt;/a&gt;, you can use Orbot and Tor to do so over any of these methods. We look forward to it!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Awareness Party</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/04/26/security-awareness-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 09:05:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2013/04/26/security-awareness-party/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the security world, there’s a pesky belief that a tool can either be secure or easy to use, but not both. Some experts also argue that training people to be safe online is too hard and doesn’t accomplish much (see Bruce Schneier’s recent post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/03/security_awaren_1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security Awareness Training&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Without a thoughtful approach, that’s usually how it plays out. But it doesn’t have to be that way! We’re committed to making online security fun to learn and fun to use, and we’re launching a new series of interactive tutorials to make it happen. Consider this post an invitation to our festive Security Awareness Party. &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/home/how-you-can-work-with-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beer is encouraged&lt;/a&gt;, especially if it comes from &lt;a title=&#34;Android-powered beer kegerator&#34; href=&#34;https://kegbot.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an Android-powered kegbot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Guardian, security is always our #1 priority. We owe that to our users who rely on us to keep them safe in places like Syria or Iran. But the time we spend on encryption is wasted if users don’t like using our tools, or can’t figure out how they work. We want to make security apps that are enjoyable and easy to use everyday, and don’t take a PHD to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activists in Iran and Syria know firsthand how important technologies like Tor and VPNs are for staying safe online. Our friends and neighbors might not be living under a repressive dictatorship, but that doesn’t mean they couldn’t use a little digital security in their lives. Maybe your nephew wants to get past the block on Facebook at school, or your co-worker wants to watch March Madness at work (make sure she gets that decoy spreadsheet ready). Maybe your friend just wants to send his wife a few…private messages, and he’d rather not have them stored by Google or Verizon. These people might not be pros, but they’re curious and happy to poke around their technology. With a little fun and interactive guidance, they can be well on their way to becoming a power user. Everyone starts somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make life safer and easier for at-risk activists and everyday people alike. That’s why we make accessible and straightforward guides to help you quickly and easily get past censors, internet police, or the office IT department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gibberbot-tutorial&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gibberbot Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newest tutorial is for our secure chat app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=info.guardianproject.otr.app.im&amp;feature=search_result&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibberbot&lt;/a&gt;. With your Android phone in one hand and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/chatsecurely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibberbot Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; in the other, you can be chatting securely on Google or Facebook chat in minutes! But Google and Facebook can’t even tell what you’re talking about. It’s also more convenient to have all of your chat apps rolled into one so that it doesn’t matter where your friends message you, it still goes to the same place. Gibberbot works even if someone is trying to monitor or block your phone’s communications. If you know another language and would like to contribute, &lt;a title=&#34;Gibberbot Tutorial Transifex Translations&#34; href=&#34;https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/gibberbot-tutorial/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;we’d love your help translating the tutorial (we’ve got English and Tibetan covered)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3291&#34; style=&#34;width: 251px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/chatsecurely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3291&#34; class=&#34; wp-image-3291&#34; alt=&#34;galaxy5&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/galaxy5.png&#34; width=&#34;241&#34; height=&#34;361&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p id=&#34;caption-attachment-3291&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    So you want to chat securely?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
     
  &lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Orbot Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    With our Android app Orbot, browsing the web securely and safely through Tor has been a piece of cake for a while now. But we just created &lt;a title=&#34;How to Orbot Tutorial&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/browsefreely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an interactive tutorial to get you started&lt;/a&gt; and show how easy it is circumvent censorship, even if the Google Play Store is blocking direct access to our app.
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    The tools themselves are getting smarter too. A new tool from &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project&#34; href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;, called &lt;a title=&#34;Tor Project Obfsproxy&#34; href=&#34;http://www.torproject.org/projects/obfsproxy.html.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pluggable Transports&lt;/a&gt;, hides your Tor traffic to look like regular Internet traffic, making it even easier for Tor users to stay ahead of surveillance and censorship. To use this new tool with Orbot, just follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/How-to-browse-freely-on-your-phone-if-your-internet-is-blocked.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our new one-page guide&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a title=&#34;How to browse freely on your phone if your internet is blocked - Farsi&#34; href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/How-to-browse-freely-on-your-phone-if-your-internet-is-blocked-Farsi.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in Farsi&lt;/a&gt;) and you’re all set! For a more in-depth guide to using Orbot, watch our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dcf5sh99ze0&#34;&gt;video tutorial&lt;/a&gt; (now in English and Arabic).
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_3585&#34; style=&#34;width: 250px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/howto/browsefreely&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3585&#34; class=&#34; wp-image-3585&#34; alt=&#34;orbot galaxy s3&#34; src=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15.png&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;361&#34; srcset=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15.png 400w, https://guardianproject.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/galaxy15-199x300.png 199w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p id=&amp;quot;caption-attachment-3585&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;wp-caption-text&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  So you want to escape censorship?
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      As we continue to grow our team and create new tools, we need your feedback!  Please tell us what we can do to go from security awareness training to a full-on security awareness party. Feel free to leave a comment on this post or tell us how we can make things easier through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.info/contact/&#34;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt;. You can also let us know about any upcoming parties that we should be attending.
    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;This post is partially a response to Bruce Schneier’s recent piece: &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Schneier Security Awareness Training&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/03/security_awaren_1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Security Awareness Training&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
