<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobifree on Guardian Project</title>
    <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/mobifree/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobifree on Guardian Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://guardianproject.github.io/info/tags/mobifree/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Ruby/Jekyll contractors to start ASAP</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/12/06/seeking-ruby/jekyll-contractors-to-start-asap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/12/06/seeking-ruby/jekyll-contractors-to-start-asap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardian Project is seeking Ruby/Jekyll contractors for mobile/free software and privacy work!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for self-motivated, free software hackers to work with Guardian Project on privacy and internet freedom for mobile devices. Our work is 100% free software and we have a steady stream of projects that tie into F-Droid, Debian, Android, Fastlane, Mobifree and other exciting projects. We work to support people and communities around the world. This is a flexible, remote position but we also like to work in person when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-you&#34;&gt;About you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have at least a few years of experience with Ruby/Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demonstrated the ability to work collaboratively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understand public, free software workflows&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are proactive and self-directed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fluent in Git.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-points-for&#34;&gt;Bonus points for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debian (and derivatives)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experience with GitLab CI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and bash skills&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding privacy implications of metadata&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life experiences that are underrepresented in tech work&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fluency in more than one language&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;User research and UX design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blogging and writing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for projects managed by Hans-Christoph Steiner. We are centered in Vienna, Austria so ideally you work in a similar time zone, but that is not a requirement. We work in English but our team members speak many languages. This work is tied to specific projects and will be contracted per project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please reply to jobs@guardianproject.info or find us in any of the regular channels!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking part-time Grant Administrator</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/08/05/seeking-part-time-grant-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/08/05/seeking-part-time-grant-administrator/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Location: Fully remote (African/European time zone) or Vienna, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type: Part-time contractor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guardian Project is a small organization working to make a big impact in data privacy and secure communications. From the average person looking to use the internet and their mobile device more securely, to journalists needing to safely communicate with sources, to activists looking for secure communication channels, Guardian Project creates solutions that focus on privacy so you have true freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we started this work back in 2008, our team has grown significantly and our impact reach has as well. To help us scale our project even further, we are looking for a dynamic and skilled Grand Administrator to join our team. This role is crucial for the smooth operation of our contractor administration and the effective management of our grants and funding opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team is rooted in Vienna, Austria with a number of contractors around the world. We work mainly in English, our team members speak many languages. Work is contract-based but with the possibility to shift into full-time employment in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-ll-do&#34;&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ll do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;support-our-contractors&#34;&gt;Support our Contractors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team consists primarily of independent contractors, passionate about creating meaningful change through technological solutions. Our freelancers need your support in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drafting and executing working contracts for new and existing team members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding new team members and making them feel welcome, introducing them to our internal communication platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up email accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting monthly check-ins with team members to confirm the contract status and update records as necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process contractor invoices and liaise with our tax accountant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event planning and organizing our annual team retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;grant-management&#34;&gt;Grant Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our organization&amp;rsquo;s funding is partially dependent on grants, we are looking for someone to support us in all things grant management, including the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research and identify new upcoming grant and private funding opportunities relevant for our organization´s mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inform and liaise with the team to assess suitability and requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare grant applications together with team support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build and sustain relationships with grant funders and partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage reporting requirements for various grants, ensuring all reporting is accurate and submitted on time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;networking-and-relationship-management&#34;&gt;Networking and Relationship Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay up to date on industry events and networking opportunities to enhance visibility and outreach opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend industry conventions and gatherings to represent Guardian Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage leads for private funding opportunities and maintain relationships with existing and potential grant partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liaise with other impactful technology and human rights organizations around the world and stakeholders at different levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enhance-our-outreach-and-engagement&#34;&gt;Enhance our Outreach and Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor our blog and social media accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curate relevant content on our online channels to engage our community and enhance our impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-you-are&#34;&gt;Who You Are&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong organizational skills with the ability to manage multiple tasks and deadlines effectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results oriented and willing to expand your current skill set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal, with a knack for relationship building and stakeholder management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comfortable working independently in a small team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficient in using office and financial software, including MS Office and cloud-based document management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detail-oriented with a high level of accuracy in handling administrative and financial duties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-s-a-bonus-if-you&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bonus if you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a Bachelor’s degree in Business Administration or Non-profit Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have experience in grant writing and administration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have experience working in an international, multicultural team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are based in Vienna, Austria and can speak German&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What We Offer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A supportive and dynamic work environment where your work directly contributes to Guardian Project´s mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible working hours and vacation time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully or mostly remote work environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great deal of autonomy and responsibility, with a huge impact on our organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A competitive hourly rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-person team retreats and meet-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunities for professional development and growth within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ready-to-apply&#34;&gt;Ready to Apply?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send your resume and a cover letter explaining why you are a good fit for this position to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jobs@guardianproject.info&#34;&gt;jobs@guardianproject.info&lt;/a&gt;.  We aim to fill this position in September 2024.
Join us in our mission to create a safer, more secure internet and mobile experience! We look forward to receiving your application!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Time Using CalyxOS Review</title>
      <link>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/04/03/first-time-using-calyxos-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guardianproject.github.io/info/2024/04/03/first-time-using-calyxos-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“But how are you planning on using the phone?” he asked me. I paused, a bit confused. “As a replacement for my iPhone. I want to do everything with this phone that I can do with my iPhone, and use it as I normally would.” He took a beat to respond, “Wow, alright. Well let&amp;rsquo;s give it a shot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would describe myself as tech-curious, but the reality is I am not your typical CalyxOS user. In fact, I didn´t know CalyxOS existed until recently. I am not a software developer, I can´t write code and until recently, I never worked in tech. But none-the-less I found myself needing a replacement for my iPhone and asked HC if they could help me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in no time my refurbished Google Pixel 4a phone had arrived, loaded and ready to go with CalyxOS. So here is my very unprofessional review of how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked into the Calyx setup process with no expectations. Well, actually I take that back. I expected it to be similar to my 20-something years of iOS experience that I was used to. I expected there to be some sort of introduction and for some sort of apps to be pre-loaded into the phone. I of course knew that the apps and home screen from my old iPhone wouldn´t magically appear on my Google Pixel, and that I would need to manually download them if I wanted to keep using them on my new device. So I was prepared for that, but otherwise, I walked in blind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First impressions&lt;/strong&gt;
The introduction and set up process went incredibly smoothly. It was a very similar experience to when I started up a new iPhone for the first time. I needed to select a language and location and then I needed to connect to wifi. So far so good, except that my wifi password is incredibly long and annoying. But that is on me, not Calyx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date and time set up no problem. It accurately identified my general location and the recommended time-zone was correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to location services there were two options, one was automatically enabled, the other I needed to make a choice. If my memory serves, I don´t think I had this choice when setting up my iPhones in the past. I choose to allow apps to use my location that have asked my permission and kept going. I set up my pin and two fingerprints. This was all very similar to my older iOS phones. Then I encountered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://microg.org/&#34;&gt;microG&lt;/a&gt; instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is MicroG?&lt;/strong&gt;
The microG explanation was helpful since I had no idea what microG does. For the uninitiated, it acts like an open source replacement for Google Play services and related software. But it only includes the “useful parts” and most interestingly, it does not have any advertising or location tracking, a bonus if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installing the Apps Bundle&lt;/strong&gt;
Then it was time to install the apps bundle.  This was new, since usually the apps come pre-installed on my iPhone. But I thought it was nice that I had a choice here. In any case I left all apps selected and downloaded all of them. I will be doing write-ups on my experiences with those separately in case you want to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they were downloading, there was a useful description about each app, which was a very nice touch for the uninitiated. Because I will be honest, I did not recognize the majority of these apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next was a prompt asking if I wanted to restore a backup. Which I didn´t have, so I kept going to navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation Options&lt;/strong&gt;
Here I had two options, gesture navigation and 3-button navigation. I was not sure what the term gesture navigation meant initially, so the little animation explaining the swiping actions made it very clear. I thought, “Let´s keep this simple” and I went with 3-buttons and off we went to my phone´s home screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My new home with CalyxOS&lt;/strong&gt;
My first thought was, “I downloaded a whole bunch of apps, but where are they?” As an iOS user, I was used to seeing all the pre-installed apps just appear, so this threw me off but only for a second or two. I started swiping around on the screen and found them in no time by swiping upwards. But then I quickly realized I did not know what the majority of the apps do, so I would need to familiarize myself with them in order to use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some apps were more self explanatory than others. For example, the usual basic phone apps, camera, clock, contacts, music, phone, calculator were all very obvious. Then there were some new apps that I didn´t quite know what they did, but the title made it very obvious. For example, K-9 Mail, Riseup VPN, Firewall, Calyx VPN and the Aurora Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A note about the Aurora Store. I saw the little Google Drive logo on the shopping bag, so I thought that might be a place where I can download my Google Play apps. But if I did not see that tiny logo, I might not have known to look there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Droid I knew as an app store from my previous work and I also recognized Tor Browser, Orbot and OnionShare. I kind of assumed those three were connected because all the logos were purple and there was an onion theme going on which I associated with Tor. So we can say in this case, the branding worked!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A wrinkle in the time-space continuum&lt;/strong&gt;
My only issue with the entire experience was that my location was around 600 kilometers off from my actual real-time location. No matter what app I used, Organic Maps, Google Maps, or SatStat, all said I was in some industrial area in a city 600 kilometers away from my house. In fact, they were so consistent that I thought, maybe it is a wrinkle in the time-space continuum and I really am in two places at once! All jokes aside, I reached out to the very helpful Calyx development team and they are helping me solve the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/CalyxOS/calyxos/-/issues/2257&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows, at the end of the day it might be the hardware, since no one else has reported this bizarre issue and my phone was refurbished to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;
All in all my experience unboxing and setting up a Calyx phone went very smoothly. And as a tech-curious user, with very little experience in software engineering, I can say it was a very easy switch from iOS to CalyxOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CalyxOS gives you an alternative to big tech, without sacrificing usability. It gave me choices in terms of my data privacy that made me feel safe and more empowered. And it gave me a whole bundle of open source, privacy conscious apps to try out, so I can expand my horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I am curious to see more iOS and Android users migrate towards CalyxOS as a viable alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
